<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Secret Manager</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Secret Manager</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:secret-manager</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/secret-manager/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:secret-manager:2025-10-13:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Preview:</strong> Integrated secret synchronization feature is now available in preview. You can automatically synchronize secrets from Secret Manager into Kubernetes Secret objects within your Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE) clusters. This process allows applications to access secrets from Secret Manager using standard Kubernetes methods, such as environment variables or volume mounts. Applications that are already configured to read secrets from Kubernetes Secret object can now seamlessly read secrets in Secret Manager.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/secret-manager/docs/sync-k8-secrets">Synchronize secrets to Kubernetes Secrets</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Synchronize secrets from Secret Manager to GKE.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Secret Synchronization to GKE</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:secret-manager:2025-09-01:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Automatic secret rotation with the Secret Manager add-on for Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE)</strong>: You can configure the Secret Manager add-on to automatically rotate secrets so that secrets updated in Secret Manager after initial pod deployment are automatically and periodically pushed to the pod. This feature is now Generally available (GA).</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/secret-manager/docs/secret-manager-managed-csi-component#configure_automatic_rotation_of_secrets">Configure automatic rotation of secrets</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Secret Manager add-on for GKE now supports automatic secret rotation. This feature, now Generally Available (GA), allows secrets updated in Secret Manager to be automatically pushed to pods after initial deployment.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Automatic secret rotation for GKE</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:secret-manager:2025-07-09:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced tagging capabilities for Secret Manager</strong>: You can now add tags directly at the time of secret creation. This new feature lets you provide essential metadata for your resources and helps with better organization, cost tracking, and automated policy application from the time a secret is created. In addition to this, <em>tagging for regional secrets</em> is now fully supported, both during secret creation and for existing regional secrets. For more information, see the documentation on tags for <a href="https://cloud.google.com/secret-manager/docs/create-and-manage-tags">global secrets</a> and <a href="https://cloud.google.com/secret-manager/regional-secrets/create-manage-tags-regional-secrets">regional secrets</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Soft-enforced rate limits for modifying secrets and secret versions</strong>: We have introduced soft-enforced rate limits for the following operations in Secret Manager:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>AddSecretVersion</code></li>
<li><code>UpdateSecret</code></li>
<li><code>EnableSecretVersion</code></li>
<li><code>DisableSecretVersion</code></li>
<li><code>DestroySecretVersion</code></li>
</ul>
<p>Soft enforcement lets us continue serving requests beyond the defined quota as long as our backend systems can comfortably handle the increased load. For details, see the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/secret-manager/quotas">Quotas and limits</a> documentation.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Secret Manager now supports adding tags at creation for better organization and cost tracking, including full support for regional secrets. Additionally, soft-enforced rate limits have been introduced for several modification operations to ensure continued service availability.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New tagging and rate limit features in Secret Manager</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:secret-manager:2025-06-23:libraries:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A weekly digest of client library updates from across the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sdk">Cloud SDK</a>.</p>
<h3>Go</h3>
<h3>Changes for <a href="https://github.com/googleapis/google-cloud-go/tree/main/secretmanager/apiv1">secretmanager/apiv1</a></h3>
<h4><a href="https://github.com/googleapis/google-cloud-go/compare/secretmanager/v1.14.7...secretmanager/v1.15.0">1.15.0</a> (2025-06-17)</h4>
<h5>Features</h5>
<ul>
<li><strong>secretmanager:</strong> Update secret manager protos for tags (<a href="https://github.com/googleapis/google-cloud-go/issues/12406">#12406</a>) (<a href="https://github.com/googleapis/google-cloud-go/commit/feb078b04ab541dd3bdceb2ac1f24938bb0354a3">feb078b</a>)</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>This is a weekly digest of client library updates for Google Cloud.</summary>
    <title>Libraries: Client Library Updates</title>
  </entry>
</feed>