<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Organization Policy</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Organization Policy</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:organization-policy</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/organization-policy/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:organization-policy:2025-10-06:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can use custom constraints with Organization Policy to provide more granular control over specific fields for some Dataform resources. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/dataform/docs/create-custom-constraints">Create custom organization policy constraints</a>. This feature is <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">generally available</a> (GA).</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Organization Policy now supports custom constraints for granular control over Dataform resources. This generally available feature allows for more specific field management.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Custom Constraints for Dataform Resources</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:organization-policy:2025-10-03:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Select Workload Identity Federation resources let you use custom constraints to define your own restrictions on Google Cloud services. To learn which Workload Identity Federation resources support custom constraints and to view sample use cases, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/iam/docs/workload-identity-federation-custom-constraints">Use custom organization policies for Workload Identity Federation</a>.</p>
<p>This feature is available in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">General Availability</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now use custom constraints to define restrictions on Google Cloud services for Workload Identity Federation resources. This feature is in General Availability.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Workload Identity Federation Custom Constraints</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:organization-policy:2025-09-18:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Select Cloud Load Balancing resources let you use custom constraints to define your own restrictions on Google Cloud services. To learn which load balancing resources support custom constraints and to view sample use cases, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/load-balancing/docs/custom-constraints">Manage Cloud Load Balancing resources using custom constraints</a>.</p>
<p>This feature is available in <strong>General Availability</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now use custom constraints to define your own restrictions on Google Cloud services for select Cloud Load Balancing resources. This feature is in General Availability.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Custom constraints for Cloud Load Balancing</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:organization-policy:2025-09-11:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can use custom constraints with Organization Policy to provide more granular control over specific fields for some Live Stream API resources. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/livestream/docs/custom-constraints">Use custom custom constraints</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now use custom constraints with Organization Policy for more granular control over Live Stream API resources.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Organization Policy Custom Constraints</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:organization-policy:2025-09-09:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Preview:</strong> Eight new organization policy constraints are available to help you
enforce security best practices for Compute Engine virtual machine (VM)
instances.</p>
<p>These <a href="https://cloud.google.com/resource-manager/docs/organization-policy/using-constraints#managed-constraints">managed constraints</a>
simplify governance for common security scenarios and integrate with safe
rollout tools like
<a href="https://cloud.google.com/resource-manager/docs/organization-policy/dry-run-policy">dry-run</a>
and
<a href="https://cloud.google.com/policy-intelligence/docs/test-organization-policies">simulation</a>,
letting you test their impact before enforcement.</p>
<p>The new constraints are as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>compute.managed.disableNestedVirtualization</code></li>
<li><code>compute.managed.disableSerialPortAccess</code></li>
<li><code>compute.managed.disableSerialPortLogging</code></li>
<li><code>compute.managed.disallowGlobalDns</code></li>
<li><code>compute.managed.requireOsConfig</code></li>
<li><code>compute.managed.requireOsLogin</code></li>
<li><code>compute.managed.vmCanIpForward</code></li>
<li><code>compute.managed.vmExternalIpAccess</code></li>
</ul>
<p>These constraints can evaluate metadata values at the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/metadata/overview#metadata-directories">VM instance, project, or
zonal level</a>. For more information about these managed constraints, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/resource-manager/docs/organization-policy/org-policy-constraints#managed-constraints">Managed
Constraints</a> in the Resource Manager documentation.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Preview: Eight new organization policy constraints are available to help you enforce security best practices for Compute Engine virtual machine (VM) instances. These managed constraints simplify governance for common security scenarios and integrate with safe rollout tools like dry-run and simulation, letting you test their impact before enforcement.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Organization Policy Constraints for Compute Engine</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:organization-policy:2025-09-08:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can use custom constraints with Organization Policy to provide more granular control over specific fields for some Cloud Deploy resources. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/deploy/docs/custom-org-policy">Use custom organization policies</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Organization Policy now supports custom constraints for finer control over Cloud Deploy resources.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Custom Constraints in Cloud Deploy</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:organization-policy:2025-08-28:fixed:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Certain Organization Policy <a href="https://cloud.google.com/resource-manager/docs/organization-policy/overview#managed-constraints">managed constraints</a> that were released on August 21, 2025 were not functioning as intended. The Organization Policy Service evaluated these constraints as if the <code>effectiveInstanceMetadata</code> field of the resources that they were enforced on was empty, causing them to always evaluate to either allow or deny access to the resource.</p>
<p>The following managed constraints were evaluated to always allow creation of resources where they were enforced:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>constraints/compute.managed.disableGuestAttributesAccess</code></li>
<li><code>constraints/compute.managed.disableSerialPortAccess</code></li>
<li><code>constraints/compute.managed.disableSerialPortLogging</code></li>
</ul>
<p>The following managed constraints were evaluated to always block creation of resources where they were enforced:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>constraints/compute.managed.disallowGlobalDns</code></li>
<li><code>constraints/compute.managed.requireOsConfig</code></li>
<li><code>constraints/compute.managed.requireOsLogin</code></li>
</ul>
<p>This issue has been corrected, and these constraints now properly evaluate the <code>effectiveInstanceMetadata</code> field to determine whether resource creation should be allowed or blocked.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A bug affecting certain organization policies has been fixed. Previously, some managed constraints were not evaluated correctly, leading to unintended access allowances or blocks. This has been resolved and policies are now functioning as expected.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Organization policy issue fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:organization-policy:2025-08-18:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can use custom constraints with Organization Policy to provide more granular control over specific fields for some Backup for GKE resources. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine/docs/add-on/backup-for-gke/how-to/create-custom-constraints">Manage Backup for GKE resources using custom constraints</a>. This feature is <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">generally available</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>New custom constraints for Backup for GKE.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New custom constraints for Backup for GKE</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:organization-policy:2025-08-18:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now use organization policy conditions to match a tag key. This lets you enable or
disable enforcement against all resources with that tag key, regardless of what
tag value is attached. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/resource-manager/docs/organization-policy/tags-organization-policy">Setting an organization policy with tags</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now use organization policy conditions to match a tag key.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New feature: Match tag key in organization policy</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:organization-policy:2025-07-25:issue:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Organization policies in dry-run mode are reporting inconsistent results for the following <a href="https://cloud.google.com/resource-manager/docs/organization-policy/overview#managed_constraints">managed constraints</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>constraints/compute.managed.restrictProtocolForwardingCreationForTypes</code></li>
<li><code>constraints/iam.managed.allowedPolicyMembers</code></li>
<li><code>constraints/essentialcontacts.managed.allowedContactDomains</code></li>
<li><code>constraints/compute.managed.blockPreviewFeatures</code></li>
</ul>
<p>If a resource inherited an organization policy in dry-run mode that uses any of these managed constraints, that dry-run policy was evaluated without using the parameters specified in the live policy. Normally, an organization policy in dry-run mode that's inherited on a resource is overridden by the live organization policy set directly on that same resource. Not evaluating the live organization policy parameters in the inherited organization policy in dry-run mode led to inconsistent results.</p>
<p>Our engineering team is working to resolve this issue.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Inconsistent results for managed constraints in dry-run mode.</summary>
    <title>Issue: Issue with dry-run organization policies</title>
  </entry>
</feed>