<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Cloud Location Finder</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Cloud Location Finder</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-location-finder</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/cloud-location-finder/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-location-finder:2025-06-11:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud Location Finder public preview release.</p>
<p>Cloud Location Finder lets you identify and filter cloud locations in regions and zones across Google Cloud, Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services, and Oracle Cloud Infrastructure based on proximity, geographic location, and carbon energy usage.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>We are excited to announce the public preview of Cloud Location Finder. This tool allows you to find and filter cloud locations across major providers like Google Cloud, Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services, and Oracle Cloud Infrastructure. You can filter based on proximity, geographic location, and even carbon energy usage.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Cloud Location Finder Now in Public Preview</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-location-finder:2025-06-11:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google Cloud CLI commands for Cloud Location Finder are available. For more information, see the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sdk/gcloud/reference/alpha/cloudlocationfinder">gcloud cloudlocationfinder</a> help text.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now use Google Cloud CLI commands with Cloud Location Finder. For more details, check the gcloud cloudlocationfinder help text.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud Location Finder CLI commands available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-location-finder:2025-06-11:feature:2</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A REST API for Cloud Location Finder is available. For more information, see the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/location-finder/docs/reference/rest">API Reference</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new REST API is now available for Cloud Location Finder, providing programmatic access to location data. More details can be found in the API documentation.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud Location Finder REST API Now Available</title>
  </entry>
</feed>