<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Dataform</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Dataform</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:dataform</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/dataform/" />
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:dataform:2025-07-14:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="text/markdown">Updates to the automatic cataloging of Dataform metadata in Dataplex improve the near real-time [management](https://cloud.google.com/dataplex/docs/catalog-overview) and [search](https://cloud.google.com/dataplex/docs/search-assets) capabilities for repository metadata. These features are [generally available](https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages) (GA).</content>
    <summary>Dataplex now offers improved near real-time management and search for Dataform repository metadata, with features now generally available. This update enhances how users interact with and find information within their data catalogs.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Dataform Metadata Management in Dataplex Updated</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:dataform:2025-06-12:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="text/markdown">Dark theme is now available for BigQuery and Dataform. To turn on the dark theme, go to the Console, open the **Settings and utilities** menu next to your avatar, and select **Preferences**. On the **User preferences** page, select **Appearance** in the navigation, select your color theme, and save your selection.</content>
    <summary>You can now enable dark theme for BigQuery and Dataform. Access this feature through the User Preferences page under Appearance settings in the Console.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Dark Theme Now Available for BigQuery and Dataform</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:dataform:2025-05-29:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="text/markdown">You can now use your Google Account user credentials to authorize the creation, scheduling, and running of pipelines, the scheduling of notebooks and data preparations, and the creation of workflow configurations. For more information, see [Schedule runs](https://cloud.google.com/dataform/docs/schedule-runs). This feature is in [preview](https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages).</content>
    <summary>You can now use your Google Account credentials to authorize pipeline creation, scheduling, and execution, as well as notebook scheduling and data preparation. Workflow configurations can also be created using these credentials. This feature is currently in preview.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Use Google Account Credentials for Authorization</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:dataform:2025-05-28:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="text/markdown">You can now use strict act-as mode to enable an additional security check for certain user actions in Dataform. For more information, see [Use strict act-as mode](https://cloud.google.com/dataform/docs/strict-act-as-mode). This feature is in [preview](https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages).</content>
    <summary>Dataform now supports strict act-as mode, an enhanced security feature for user actions. This preview feature adds an extra layer of verification for specific operations.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New security feature in Dataform</title>
  </entry>
</feed>