<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Media CDN</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Media CDN</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:media-cdn</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/media-cdn/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:media-cdn:2025-10-10:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Media CDN supports multipart range requests, which enable users to request
multiple non-contiguous segments of a file in a single HTTP request.
This feature is in <strong>Preview</strong>.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/media-cdn/docs/caching#multipart-range-requests">Multipart range requests</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Media CDN now supports multipart range requests, allowing users to fetch multiple file segments in one go. This feature is currently in Preview.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Multipart range requests now in Preview</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:media-cdn:2025-09-24:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can use Autonomous System Numbers (ASN) based rules from Cloud Armor for Media CDN. ASN-based rules allow you to create security policies that specifically permit or deny traffic based on the ASN of the client requesting your content. This feature is <strong>Generally Available</strong>.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/media-cdn/docs/overview#armor-support">Google Cloud Armor support</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now use ASN-based rules for Media CDN. This feature allows you to create security policies that permit or deny traffic based on the client's ASN. It is now Generally Available.</summary>
    <title>Feature: ASN-based rules for Media CDN</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:media-cdn:2025-09-24:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can use Network Threat Intelligence (NTI) from Cloud Armor in Edge Security Policies for Media CDN edge cache services for Enterprise users. NTI helps identify and block requests originating from known malicious IP addresses and networks. This feature is <strong>Generally Available</strong>.</p>
<p>For an example, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/media-cdn/docs/security-policies#example-block-malicious-using-NTI">Example: Block traffic from known malicious IPs</a>.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/media-cdn/docs/overview#armor-support">Google Cloud Armor support</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Enterprise users can now leverage Network Threat Intelligence (NTI) from Cloud Armor in Edge Security Policies for Media CDN edge cache services. This feature, now Generally Available, helps identify and block requests from known malicious IP addresses and networks.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Network Threat Intelligence Now Available for Media CDN</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:media-cdn:2025-08-08:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can use Autonomous System Numbers (ASN) based rules from Cloud Armor for Media CDN. ASN-based rules allow you to create security policies that specifically permit or deny traffic based on the ASN of the client requesting your content. This feature is in <strong>Preview</strong>.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/media-cdn/docs/overview#armor-support">Google Cloud Armor support</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Media CDN now supports ASN-based rules for Cloud Armor.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New ASN-based rules for Media CDN</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:media-cdn:2025-06-30:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Media CDN supports a dedicated range of IPs for requests to external origin servers. <a href="https://cloud.google.com/media-cdn/docs/origins#allow-ip">IP allowlisting</a> at the origin helps you restrict access to your content by only allowing traffic from Media CDN's IP addresses. This capability is <strong>Generally Available</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Media CDN now supports a dedicated range of IPs for requests to external origin servers. This feature is Generally Available.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: IP Allowlisting for External Origins</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:media-cdn:2025-06-25:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cloud.google.com/media-cdn/docs/origins#flex-shielding">Flexible shielding</a> helps you overcome some limitations of default origin shielding by letting you configure a single, specific geographic region for origin shielding,
typically selected to be near your centralized origin. This feature is in <strong>Preview</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Flexible shielding lets you select a specific geographic region for origin shielding, useful for origins centralized in one location. This feature is currently in Preview.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Flexible origin shielding is now available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:media-cdn:2025-06-18:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can use Network Threat Intelligence (NTI) from Cloud Armor in Edge Security Policies for Media CDN edge cache services for Enterprise users. NTI helps identify and block requests originating from known malicious IP addresses and networks. This feature is in <strong>Preview</strong>.</p>
<p>For an example, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/media-cdn/docs/security-policies#example-block-malicious-using-NTI">Example: Block traffic from known malicious IPs</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Network Threat Intelligence from Cloud Armor is now available in Edge Security Policies for Media CDN.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Network Threat Intelligence for Media CDN</title>
  </entry>
</feed>