<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Media CDN</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Media CDN</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:media-cdn</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/media-cdn/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:media-cdn:2025-06-30:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Media CDN supports a dedicated range of IPs for requests to external origin servers. <a href="https://cloud.google.com/media-cdn/docs/origins#allow-ip">IP allowlisting</a> at the origin helps you restrict access to your content by only allowing traffic from Media CDN's IP addresses. This feature is <strong>Generally Available</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Media CDN now supports a dedicated IP range for external origin requests, allowing for restricted access.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: IP Allowlisting for Media CDN Origins</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:media-cdn:2025-06-25:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cloud.google.com/media-cdn/docs/origins#flex-shielding">Flexible shielding</a> helps you overcome some limitations of default origin shielding by letting you configure a single, specific geographic region for origin shielding,
typically selected to be near your centralized origin. This feature is in <strong>Preview</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Flexible shielding lets you select a specific geographic region for origin shielding, useful for origins centralized in one location. This feature is currently in Preview.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Flexible origin shielding is now available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:media-cdn:2025-06-18:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can use Network Threat Intelligence (NTI) from Cloud Armor in Edge Security Policies for Media CDN edge cache services for Enterprise users. NTI helps identify and block requests originating from known malicious IP addresses and networks. This feature is in <strong>Preview</strong>.</p>
<p>For an example, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/media-cdn/docs/security-policies#example-block-malicious-using-NTI">Example: Block traffic from known malicious IPs</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Network Threat Intelligence from Cloud Armor is now available in Edge Security Policies for Media CDN.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Network Threat Intelligence for Media CDN</title>
  </entry>
</feed>