<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Google Cloud Armor</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Google Cloud Armor</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-armor</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/google-cloud-armor/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-armor:2025-10-15:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud Armor's <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/armor/docs/hierarchical-policies-overview">Hierarchical security policies</a> that facilitate centralized control, enhanced consistency, operational efficiency, and effective delegation of security policy management is Generally Available.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud Armor Hierarchical security policies are now Generally Available. This feature allows for centralized control, improved consistency, and efficient management of security policies.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Hierarchical security policies are now Generally Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-armor:2025-09-24:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud Armor's support for Network Threat Intelligence (NTI) in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/armor/docs/security-policy-overview#expandable-1">globally scoped edge security policies</a> for Media CDN edge cache services is Generally Available.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud Armor now supports Network Threat Intelligence (NTI) for Media CDN edge cache services. This feature, now Generally Available, enhances security for globally scoped edge security policies.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud Armor NTI Support for Media CDN Now Generally Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-armor:2025-09-24:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud Armor's support for Autonomous System Numbers (ASNs) in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/armor/docs/security-policy-overview#expandable-1">globally scoped edge security policies</a> for Media CDN edge cache services is Generally Available.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud Armor now supports Autonomous System Numbers (ASNs) in globally scoped edge security policies for Media CDN edge cache services. This feature is now Generally Available.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud Armor ASN Support for Media CDN Now GA</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-armor:2025-09-16:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud Armor support for <a href="https://cloud.google.com/armor/docs/address-groups-overview#organization-scoped-address-group">organization-scoped address groups</a> for security policies is Generally Available.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>We are excited to announce that organization-scoped address groups for Cloud Armor are now Generally Available. This feature allows you to manage IP address lists at the organization level, simplifying security policy creation and enforcement across your Google Cloud environment.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Organization-scoped address groups for Cloud Armor are now GA</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-armor:2025-08-08:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud Armor supports Autonomous System Numbers (ASNs) in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/armor/docs/security-policy-overview#expandable-1">globally scoped edge security policies</a> for Media CDN edge cache services in Preview.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud Armor now supports ASNs for Media CDN.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud Armor ASN Support</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-armor:2025-07-23:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud Armor supports internal service security policies for the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/armor/docs/integrating-cloud-armor#service-mesh">service mesh</a> to enforce global server-side rate limiting per client in Preview.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud Armor now supports internal service security policies for service mesh.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud Armor Feature Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-armor:2025-07-08:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud Armor <a href="https://cloud.google.com/armor/docs/waf-rules">preconfigured WAF rules</a> can now inspect up to the first 64kB (either 8kB, 16kB, 32kB, 48kB, or 64kB) of the POST or PATCH <a href="https://cloud.google.com/armor/docs/security-policy-overview#post-body">request body content</a> in Preview.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud Armor preconfigured WAF rules now support inspecting up to 64kB of POST/PATCH request body content in Preview. This enhancement allows for more comprehensive security analysis of incoming data.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Cloud Armor WAF Rules Now Inspect Larger Request Bodies</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-armor:2025-06-27:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud Armor's <a href="https://cloud.google.com/armor/docs/hierarchical-policies-overview">Hierarchical security policies</a> facilitate centralized control, enhanced consistency, operational efficiency, and effective delegation of security policy management in Preview.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>This feature allows for centralized control, consistent security policies, and efficient management, with support for policy delegation.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Hierarchical Security Policies Now in Preview</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-armor:2025-06-24:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud Armor supports <a href="https://cloud.google.com/armor/docs/address-groups-overview#organization-scoped-address-group">organization-scoped address groups</a> for security policies in Preview.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud Armor now supports organization-scoped address groups in preview, allowing for more centralized management of security policies across your organization.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud Armor supports organization-scoped address groups</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-armor:2025-06-18:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud Armor supports Network Threat Intelligence (NTI) in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/armor/docs/security-policy-overview#expandable-1">globally scoped edge security policies</a> for Media CDN edge cache services in Preview.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud Armor now supports Network Threat Intelligence for Media CDN edge cache services, enhancing security for globally scoped edge security policies.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud Armor NTI Support for Media CDN</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-armor:2025-06-09:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud Armor support for JA4 rate limiting key is Generally Available. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/armor/docs/configure-rate-limiting">Configure rate limiting</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>JA4 rate limiting key is now available in Cloud Armor. Learn more about configuring rate limiting. </summary>
    <title>Changed: Cloud Armor JA4 Rate Limiting Now Available</title>
  </entry>
</feed>