<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Retail API</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Retail API</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:retail-api</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/retail-api/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:retail-api:2025-09-05:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Vertex AI Search for commerce: Conversational product filtering</strong></p>
<p>As part of Search for commerce's Guided search package, <code>ConversationalSearchSpec</code> sits on top of the Vertex AI Search for commerce. When coverage parameters are met, Search for commerce users can enable this feature in the console or by setting the <code>followup_conversation_requested</code> flag to <code>true</code> in the search service interface. Conversational product filtering uses an LLM-generated question for each catalog attribute where <code>allowed_in_conversation</code> field is enabled.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/retail/docs/conversational-filtering">Conversational product filtering</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new feature for Search for commerce that allows for conversational product filtering.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Conversational Product Filtering</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:retail-api:2025-09-03:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Vertex AI Search for commerce: Conversational Commerce agent, GA</strong></p>
<p>The Conversational Commerce agent uses LLM and conversational product filtering to provide users with a real-time, ongoing conversational experience. The conversational product filtering feature functions as part of the Guided Search package, helping narrow down search queries sooner by presenting users with either relevant products, follow-up questions, or both.</p>
<p>The Conversational Commerce agent is generally available (GA). For information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/retail/docs/conversational-search">Conversational Commerce agent</a> and <a href="https://cloud.google.com/retail/docs/conversational-filtering">Conversational product filtering</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The new Conversational Commerce agent for Vertex AI Search is now generally available. This feature enhances the shopping experience by using LLMs and conversational product filtering to provide real-time, interactive product discovery.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Conversational Commerce Agent Now Generally Available</title>
  </entry>
</feed>