<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Cloud Healthcare API</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Cloud Healthcare API</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-healthcare-api</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/cloud-healthcare-api/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-healthcare-api:2025-10-09:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A new application has been added to the Cloud Console under "Healthcare",
  called "DICOM Studio"</li>
<li>This new application provides a web interface for exploring DICOM Stores
  in the Cloud Healthcare API similar to "FHIR Viewer".</li>
<li>Search and find studies, series, and instances in any DICOM Store using our DICOM Web API</li>
<li>View studies, series and instance metadata</li>
<li>Edit studies, series and instance metadata</li>
<li>Perform CRUD operations (Delete) on studies, series and instances</li>
<li>View studies, series and instance images via a transcoded image preview</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Explore and manage your DICOM data with ease using DICOM Studio, a new web interface in the Cloud Console's Healthcare section. Similar to FHIR Viewer, it allows you to search, view, edit, and delete studies, series, and instances, and even preview images.</summary>
    <title>Feature: DICOM Studio Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-healthcare-api:2025-09-12:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><code>Accept-Encoding</code> compression headers on DICOM frame requests that contain
  uncompressed pixel data (as defined by the DICOM transfer syntax) are now
  supported and can return compressed results</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Note</strong>: For very large downlinks and very large files where downlink vastly
outpaces compression speed, latency may slightly increase. Compression can be
disabled by not including the header in these cases.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>`Accept-Encoding` headers are now supported for DICOM frame requests with uncompressed pixel data, allowing for compressed results.</summary>
    <title>Feature: DICOM Compression Support</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-healthcare-api:2025-08-26:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Preview:</strong> Cloud Healthcare API has launched DICOM Updates and Patches. This
allows customers to update their DICOM data in-place. For more information, see
<a href="https://cloud.google.com/healthcare-api/docs/how-tos/dicom-update-patch">Update and patch DICOM studies, series, and instances</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Cloud Healthcare API now supports updating DICOM data in-place, simplifying data management.</summary>
    <title>Feature: DICOM Updates and Patches Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-healthcare-api:2025-05-27:deprecated:0</id>
    <published>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Healthcare Natural Language API is deprecated and will be shut down
on May 27, 2026. For more information, see
<a href="https://cloud.google.com/healthcare-api/docs/deprecations/">Deprecations</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Healthcare Natural Language API is being deprecated and will be shut down on May 27, 2026. For more information, please refer to the deprecations page.</summary>
    <title>Deprecated: Healthcare Natural Language API Deprecation</title>
  </entry>
</feed>