<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Application Integration</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Application Integration</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:application-integration</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/application-integration/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:application-integration:2025-09-10:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Connected app requires installation for OAuth 2.0 authentication in Salesforce trigger</strong></p>
<p>To configure a Salesforce trigger that uses OAuth 2.0 authentication, you must install the relevant <a href="https://help.salesforce.com/s/articleView?id=xcloud.connected_app_create.htm&amp;type=5">connected app</a> in your Salesforce account.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/application-integration/docs/configure-salesforce-trigger#post-setup">Install the OAuth connected app</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A connected app must be installed in Salesforce for OAuth 2.0 authentication in Salesforce triggers.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Salesforce Connected App Requirement</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:application-integration:2025-08-18:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Standard canvas view</strong></p>
<p>The integration editor now features a single, standard <a href="https://cloud.google.com/application-integration/docs/canvas-view">canvas view</a>. The legacy canvas is no longer available.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The legacy canvas is no longer available and the integration editor now features a single, standard canvas view.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Standard Canvas View</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:application-integration:2025-09-16:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Salesforce connected app requires installation for OAuth 2.0 authentication</strong></p>
<p>A new security requirement from Salesforce restricts the use of uninstalled connected apps. To ensure your Salesforce trigger remain functional, all users must install connected app in your Salesforce account.</p>
<p>When establishing a new Salesforce trigger using OAuth 2.0 authentication, you are now required to install the <a href="https://help.salesforce.com/s/articleView?language=en_US&amp;id=xcloud.connected_app_create.htm&amp;type=5">connected app</a> within your Salesforce account. This step is also necessary for existing triggers using OAuth 2.0 authentication if the connected app is not already installed, as failure to do so may cause them to stop working.</p>
<p>For more information, see Install the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/application-integration/docs/configure-salesforce-trigger#post-setup">OAuth connected app</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A Salesforce connected app must be installed for OAuth 2.0 authentication to ensure your Salesforce triggers continue to work. This applies to new and existing triggers if the app is not already installed.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Salesforce Connected App Update</title>
  </entry>
</feed>