<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Backup and DR</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Backup and DR</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:backup-and-dr</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/backup-and-dr/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:backup-and-dr:2025-10-14:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now set up backup vault specific workload quotas for critical resources like data sources, backups, backup plans, and backup plan associations. Until now these quotas were set up only at the project level, not at the workload level.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now set workload-specific quotas for critical resources within backup vaults, including data sources, backups, and backup plans. This provides more granular control than the previous project-level quotas.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Workload Quotas for Backup Vaults</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:backup-and-dr:2025-08-12:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Announcing the General Availability (GA) of Backup Vault support for independent Persistent Disks and Hyperdisks!</p>
<p>This new capability empowers you to protect application data, databases, and file shares stored on individual disks (where a full VM backup is not required) — all within a secure, immutable, logically air-gapped vault designed to withstand malicious deletion and advanced threats like ransomware.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Backup Vault support for independent Persistent Disks and Hyperdisks is now generally available.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: GA of Backup Vault for Independent Disks</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:backup-and-dr:2025-07-31:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Announcing the <strong>Public Preview launch of Cloud SQL enhanced backups</strong> with Backup and DR. This enables advanced data protection capabilities offered by Backup and DR including backup vault support, granular scheduling through backup plans, and centralized management.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL enhanced backups are now in public preview.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Cloud SQL Backups Now in Public Preview</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:backup-and-dr:2025-07-11:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We're excited to announce the launch of Editable Backup Plans, a new feature designed to give you more flexibility and control over your data protection strategy. You can now modify your existing backup plans directly, eliminating the need to create new plans and reassign them when your requirements change. This makes it easier than ever to adapt to evolving business needs, optimize for cost, and correct configuration errors on the fly.</p>
<p>What's new:</p>
<ul>
<li>Directly Edit Key Settings: You can now change the description, schedule, backup window, and retention periods of your existing backup plans. You can also add or remove backup rules as needed.</li>
<li>Automatic Updates: Once a plan is edited, the changes are automatically applied to all resources protected by that plan for all future backups. There's no need to manually detach and reattach the plan.</li>
<li>Backward Compatibility: This new capability is available for all backup plans, including those created before this update.</li>
</ul>
<p>Important Note: While most settings in a backup plan are now editable, the assigned backup vault cannot be changed. To store backups in a different vault, a new backup plan must be created.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now edit existing backup plans to change settings like schedule, retention, and backup rules, with changes automatically applying to all protected resources. The backup vault, however, remains unchangeable.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Editable Backup Plans Launched</title>
  </entry>
</feed>