<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Backup and DR</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Backup and DR</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:backup-and-dr</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/backup-and-dr/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:backup-and-dr:2025-11-19:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Added Change Block Tracking (CBT) support for RHEL 8.8 SAP kernels.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Change Block Tracking (CBT) is now supported for RHEL 8.8 SAP kernels.</summary>
    <title>Feature: CBT Support for RHEL 8.8 SAP Kernels</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:backup-and-dr:2025-11-19:fixed:1</id>
    <published>2025-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Resolved an issue with SAP HANA datafile validation on scale-out clusters.</li>
<li>Fixed a bug causing SAP HANA log backups to fail when the log mode is not 'normal'.</li>
<li>Addressed failures in Db2 dump full backups in some environments.</li>
<li>Corrected an issue where Db2 restore jobs with the roll-forward option were not applying logs completely.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Resolved issues with SAP HANA datafile validation and log backups, and fixed Db2 dump and restore failures.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: SAP HANA and Db2 Backup Fixes</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:backup-and-dr:2025-11-19:security:2</id>
    <published>2025-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Resolved a decryption failure that occurred when accessing KMS keys.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A decryption failure issue when accessing KMS keys has been resolved.</summary>
    <title>Security: Decryption Failure Resolved</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:backup-and-dr:2025-11-07:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Announcing the public preview launch of Database Center support for
resources protected with Backup and DR Service. Database Center is an
AI-assisted dashboard that highlights fleet-wide data points.The integration is
designed to provide Database Center users with a single, unified, and
accurate view of the data protection posture for all databases protected by
Backup and DR Service.This capability is available today, at no additional cost,
for all Cloud SQL customers who have protected their databases through
Backup and DR Service enhanced protection.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Database Center, an AI-assisted dashboard, now highlights fleet-wide data points for resources protected with Backup and DR Service. This integration offers a unified view of data protection for all Backup and DR Service-protected databases. The feature is available at no extra cost for Cloud SQL customers using enhanced protection.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Database Center now supports Backup and DR Service resources</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:backup-and-dr:2025-10-30:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new backup vault setting, <strong>Prevent deletion for duration specified in backup rule</strong>,
is now available. When enabled, this feature locks backups for the exact retention
period defined in the associated backup plan, overriding the vault's local minimum
retention and preventing manual deletion.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new backup vault setting, Prevent deletion for duration specified in backup rule, is now available. This feature locks backups for the exact retention period defined in the associated backup plan, overriding the vault's local minimum retention and preventing manual deletion.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New backup vault setting prevents deletion</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:backup-and-dr:2025-10-30:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Announcing the <strong>Public Preview</strong> launch of AlloyDB for PostgreSQL enhanced backups with Backup and DR Service. This enables advanced data protection capabilities offered by Backup and DR Service including backup vault support, granular scheduling through backup plans, and centralized management.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Backup and DR Service now supports AlloyDB for PostgreSQL in public preview, offering advanced data protection with features like backup vaults, flexible scheduling, and centralized management.</summary>
    <title>Feature: AlloyDB for PostgreSQL Backups Now in Public Preview</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:backup-and-dr:2025-10-21:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Change Block Tracking (CBT) support has been added for latest kernel versions in RHEL 8.10, 9.2, 9.4 and 9.6.</li>
<li>Improved alerting for long-running jobs by adding application type and name to the alerts.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Change Block Tracking (CBT) now supports the latest kernel versions in RHEL 8.10, 9.2, 9.4, and 9.6. Additionally, alerts for long-running jobs have been enhanced with application type and name.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Change Block Tracking Support Added</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:backup-and-dr:2025-10-21:security:1</id>
    <published>2025-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following CVEs have been addressed in this release: CVE-2022-1471, CVE-2025-31651, CVE-2025-31650, CVE-2022-42003, CVE-2025-25193, CVE-2024-6763, CVE-2025-52999, CVE-2025-24970, CVE-2025-49125, CVE-2025-48734, CVE-2024-52317, CVE-2025-48988, CVE-2025-46701</p>]]></content>
    <summary>This release addresses several CVEs to enhance security.</summary>
    <title>Security: Security Updates</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:backup-and-dr:2025-10-21:fixed:2</id>
    <published>2025-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Resolved a problem with timestamp conversions during recovery range calculations in SAP HANA</li>
<li>Fixed a bug that prevented the identification of persistent disk names in some SAP HANA environments</li>
<li>Fixed DB2 restore issue wrt pre-flight checks and instances with a large number of archive logs</li>
<li>Fixed a logging issue during Postgres upgrades where an incorrect version was displayed after a rollback</li>
<li>Resolved a restore failure when using a combination of full and incremental backups for SAP ASE</li>
<li>Fixed a connection leak and an issue with executor service shutdown in the VMware hypervisor integration, improving reliability.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Fixed timestamp conversions and persistent disk identification for SAP HANA.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: SAP HANA fixes</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:backup-and-dr:2025-10-15:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Backup and DR Service 11.0.16.253 is now available to update your backup/recovery appliances. Refer to these <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/backup-disaster-recovery/docs/configuration/update-appliance">instructions</a> to update your appliance.</p>
<ul>
<li>Guardrails have been defined for each backup/recovery appliance to specify the number of supported job slots, ensuring smooth parallel backup and mount jobs.</li>
</ul>
<p>Introducing notifications and alerts for the following critical events:</p>
<ul>
<li>Processes not running on a backup/recovery appliance</li>
<li>Expired certificates</li>
<li>No jobs running on a backup/recovery appliance</li>
<li>CPU and memory usage exceeding threshold values</li>
<li>Backup/recovery appliance appliance version out of support</li>
<li>Backup/recovery appliance updates available</li>
</ul>
<p>You can subscribe to these events and configure email alerts.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Backup and DR Service 11.0.16.253 is now available. This update includes new guardrails for backup/recovery appliances and introduces notifications and alerts for critical events such as processes not running, expired certificates, and resource usage exceeding thresholds. You can find update instructions [here](https://docs.cloud.google.com/backup-disaster-recovery/docs/configuration/update-appliance).</summary>
    <title>Announcement: New Version Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:backup-and-dr:2025-10-14:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now set up backup vault specific workload quotas for critical resources like data sources, backups, backup plans, and backup plan associations. Until now these quotas were set up only at the project level, not at the workload level.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now set workload-specific quotas for critical resources within backup vaults, including data sources, backups, and backup plans. This provides more granular control than the previous project-level quotas.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Workload Quotas for Backup Vaults</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:backup-and-dr:2025-08-12:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Announcing the General Availability (GA) of Backup Vault support for independent Persistent Disks and Hyperdisks!</p>
<p>This new capability empowers you to protect application data, databases, and file shares stored on individual disks (where a full VM backup is not required) — all within a secure, immutable, logically air-gapped vault designed to withstand malicious deletion and advanced threats like ransomware.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Backup Vault support for independent Persistent Disks and Hyperdisks is now generally available.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: GA of Backup Vault for Independent Disks</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:backup-and-dr:2025-07-31:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Announcing the <strong>Public Preview launch of Cloud SQL enhanced backups</strong> with Backup and DR. This enables advanced data protection capabilities offered by Backup and DR including backup vault support, granular scheduling through backup plans, and centralized management.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL enhanced backups are now in public preview.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Cloud SQL Backups Now in Public Preview</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:backup-and-dr:2025-07-11:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We're excited to announce the launch of Editable Backup Plans, a new feature designed to give you more flexibility and control over your data protection strategy. You can now modify your existing backup plans directly, eliminating the need to create new plans and reassign them when your requirements change. This makes it easier than ever to adapt to evolving business needs, optimize for cost, and correct configuration errors on the fly.</p>
<p>What's new:</p>
<ul>
<li>Directly Edit Key Settings: You can now change the description, schedule, backup window, and retention periods of your existing backup plans. You can also add or remove backup rules as needed.</li>
<li>Automatic Updates: Once a plan is edited, the changes are automatically applied to all resources protected by that plan for all future backups. There's no need to manually detach and reattach the plan.</li>
<li>Backward Compatibility: This new capability is available for all backup plans, including those created before this update.</li>
</ul>
<p>Important Note: While most settings in a backup plan are now editable, the assigned backup vault cannot be changed. To store backups in a different vault, a new backup plan must be created.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now edit existing backup plans to change settings like schedule, retention, and backup rules, with changes automatically applying to all protected resources. The backup vault, however, remains unchangeable.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Editable Backup Plans Launched</title>
  </entry>
</feed>