<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Capacity Planner</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Capacity Planner</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:capacity-planner</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/capacity-planner/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:capacity-planner:2025-12-09:change:0</id>
    <published>2025-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Google Cloud console has been changed as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>An <strong>Overview</strong> page for Capacity Planner has been added. You
  can use the <strong>Overview</strong> page to view data that summarizes the overall
  resource usage for a project, folder, or organization, including potential
  action items and the regional distribution of your resources.</li>
<li>The data for the region distribution of your resources has been relocated:
  the doughnut charts have been replaced with a bar chart on the
  <strong>Overview</strong> page for Capacity Planner.</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/capacity-planner/docs/view-data">View usage and forecast data</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Capacity Planner in the Google Cloud console has been updated with a new Overview page. This page provides a summary of resource usage and action items. The regional resource distribution is now displayed as a bar chart instead of doughnut charts.</summary>
    <title>Change: Capacity Planner UI Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:capacity-planner:2025-11-03:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can use client libraries to access the Capacity Planner API using C#, Go, Java, Node.js, PHP, Python, or Ruby. For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/capacity-planner/docs/reference/libraries">Capacity Planner client libraries</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Use client libraries in C#, Go, Java, Node.js, PHP, Python, or Ruby to access the Capacity Planner API.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Client libraries for Capacity Planner API</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:capacity-planner:2025-10-03:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Preview:</strong> Capacity Planner supports the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Usage and forecast data for Hyperdisk volumes</li>
<li>Usage and forecast data for Persistent Disk and Hyperdisk volume IOPS and throughput</li>
<li>Usage data for Spot VMs</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/capacity-planner/docs/view-data">View usage and forecast data</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Capacity Planner now includes usage and forecast data for Hyperdisk volumes, IOPS, and throughput for both Persistent Disk and Hyperdisk. Additionally, it now supports usage data for Spot VMs.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Capacity Planner now supports Hyperdisk, Persistent Disk, and Spot VM metrics</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:capacity-planner:2025-08-29:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cloud.google.com/capacity-planner/docs/overview">Capacity Planner</a> is available in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">Preview</a>!</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Capacity Planner is now available in Preview.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Capacity Planner now in Preview</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:capacity-planner:2025-08-29:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Reference documentation has been added for the REST Capacity Planner API. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/capacity-planner/docs/authentication">Authenticate to Capacity Planner</a> and the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/capacity-planner/docs/reference/rest">REST API reference overview</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Reference documentation for the Capacity Planner REST API is now available.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New REST API documentation</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:capacity-planner:2025-08-25:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Preview</strong>: You can use capacity requests to request a large number of resources for a future date and time, and across multiple regions or zones. When you use capacity requests, you get best-effort assurance for the capacity that Google Cloud provisions, and you only pay for resources when you use them. This approach helps ensure that your Google Cloud project has sufficient capacity to prevent resource availability errors during unexpected growth, without committing to pay for resources that you might not use.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/capacity-planner/docs/about-capacity-requests">About capacity requests</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Preview capacity requests to reserve resources for future use across multiple regions or zones. Get best-effort capacity assurance and only pay for what you use, preventing resource errors during growth without upfront commitment.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Capacity Requests: Plan for Future Needs</title>
  </entry>
</feed>