<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Guest Environment</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Guest Environment</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:guest-environment</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/guest-environment/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:guest-environment:2025-09-03:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Starting with version <code>20250901.00</code>, the guest agent is migrated to a new
plugin-based architecture to improve modularity. You can revert to the previous
version by setting the metadata attribute <code>enable-guest-agent-core-plugin</code> to
<code>FALSE</code>. For more information about the plugin-based architecture, see
<a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/images/guest-agent">Guest agent</a>.</p>
<p>This plugin-based guest agent is available for the following operating systems:</p>
<ul>
<li>Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) 9</li>
<li>Rocky Linux 9</li>
<li>CentOS Stream 9</li>
<li>Oracle Linux 9</li>
<li>AlmaLinux 9</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>The guest agent has been updated to a new plugin-based architecture starting with version 20250901.00. This change enhances modularity. You can revert to the previous version by setting the metadata attribute `enable-guest-agent-core-plugin` to `FALSE`.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: New Guest Agent Architecture</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:guest-environment:2025-09-03:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the introduction of the plugin-based architecture, the guest agent includes
the following updates:</p>
<ul>
<li>A new command-line tool, <code>ggactl_plugin</code>, is available to manage and restart
  the guest agent core plugin. To restart the agent, run:</li>
</ul>
<p>```
  ggactl_plugin coreplugin restart</p>
<p>```</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/images/manage-guest-agent#restart-guest-agent">Restarting the guest agent</a>.
* All guest agent components now use a new logging framework. This framework
  lets you set the logging level in the
  <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/images/manage-guest-agent#update-guest-agent-config">guest agent configuration file</a>.
  For more information about the logging options, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/images/manage-guest-agent#core">core settings</a>
  in the configuration options table.
* The workload refresh service <code>gce-workload-cert-refresher</code> is now part of the
  guest agent's core plugin. It is no longer a separate systemd service.
* The guest agent updates the metadata script runner and the Authorized Keys
  binary (Windows only) to use the new, configurable logging framework.
  Compatibility managers are included to facilitate the migration.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The guest agent now features a plugin-based architecture, including a new command-line tool `ggactl_plugin` for managing the core plugin. It also incorporates a new logging framework allowing configurable log levels and integrates the workload refresh service into the core plugin.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Plugin-Based Architecture for Guest Agent</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:guest-environment:2025-09-03:fixed:2</id>
    <published>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue is fixed where network routes were not consistently applied
(<a href="https://github.com/GoogleCloudPlatform/guest-agent/issues/516">GitHub Issue #516</a>).
The system now consistently applies network routes by monitoring the route table
and re-adding routes when they disappear.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>An issue is fixed where network routes were not consistently applied. The system now consistently applies network routes by monitoring the route table and re-adding routes when they disappear.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Network routes are now consistently applied</title>
  </entry>
</feed>