<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Apigee Integrated Portal</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Apigee Integrated Portal</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-integrated-portal</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/apigee-integrated-portal/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-integrated-portal:2025-07-24:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On July 24, 2025 we began redirecting the following Apigee Classic UI navigation items to Apigee UI in the Google Cloud console:</p>
<ul>
<li>Publish &gt; Portals</li>
</ul>
<p>See <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/api-platform/fundamentals/ui-overview#console-compare">Apigee UI in Cloud console navigation</a> for a mapping of each Classic Apigee UI feature page to its location in the Apigee UI in Cloud console.</p>
<p>See <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/deprecations/apigee-classic-ui">Apigee Classic UI shutdown</a> for details on shutdown dates.</p>
<p>If you require more time to transition to the Google Cloud console, submit the <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSedFe2Pj2f9B8YxD7cgWOyf8-IjRA8IhRZpZ2jXMZ9DU1uz1g/viewform">exception request form</a> by Aug 15, 2025.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Apigee Classic UI navigation items are being redirected to the Apigee UI in the Google Cloud console. The transition includes Publish &gt; Portals. See documentation for mapping and shutdown dates. Exception requests are due by Aug 15, 2025.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Apigee UI Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-integrated-portal:2025-06-23:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On June 23, 2025 we released a new version of the Apigee integrated portal.</p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> Rollouts of this release to production instances will begin within two business days and may take four or more business days to complete across all Google Cloud zones. Your instances may not have the feature available until the rollout is complete.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new version of the Apigee integrated portal has been released, with rollouts beginning within two business days and potentially taking up to four or more business days to complete across all Google Cloud zones.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: New Apigee Integrated Portal Version Released</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-integrated-portal:2025-06-23:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This release adds the <strong>Export</strong> feature to the Apigee UI in the Cloud console. You can now export publishing data for developers, apps, or API products as a comma-separated values (CSV) file or JSON file.</p>
<p><strong>Documentation:</strong> <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/api-platform/publish/adding-developers-your-api-product#export">Exporting publishing data</a></p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now export publishing data for developers, apps, or API products as a CSV or JSON file using the new Export feature in the Apigee UI.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Export Feature in Apigee UI</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-integrated-portal:2025-06-02:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On June 2, 2025 we released a new version of the Apigee integrated portal.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new version of the Apigee integrated portal was released on June 2, 2025.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: New Apigee portal version released</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-integrated-portal:2025-06-02:fixed:1</id>
    <published>2025-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>| Bug ID | Description |
| --- | --- |
| 404509044 | When <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/api-platform/publish/portal/configure-email#cloud-console-ui-preview">configuring an SMTP server,</a> and the portal is first provisioned, email notifications are sent to portal users from a generic sender address. This release updates that generic address to <code>noreply-apigee-portals@google.com</code>. |</p>
<p>This approach is suitable for evaluation, but you should configure your own SMTP server before launching your portal to users. When you configure the SMTP server, you can also configure the sender address, for example, <code>no-reply@mycompany.com</code>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The sender email address for email notifications from newly provisioned portals has been updated to no-reply-apigee-portals@google.com. This change ensures a more specific sender address for initial email communications. Remember to configure your own SMTP server and preferred sender address before launching your portal to avoid using the generic address.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Updated sender email for portal notifications</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-integrated-portal:2025-05-29:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On May 29, 2025 we released a new version of the Apigee integrated portal.</p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> Rollouts of this release to production instances will begin within two business days and may take four or more business days to complete across all Google Cloud zones. Your instances may not have the features and fixes available until the rollout is complete.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new version of the Apigee integrated portal has been released on May 29, 2025. The rollout to production instances will begin within two business days and may take longer to complete.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: New Apigee portal version released</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-integrated-portal:2025-05-29:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>GA: Apigee Integrated Developer Portal Admin UI in the Google Cloud console.</strong></p>
<p>This release adds the Apigee Integrated Developer Portal Admin UI from the Classic Apigee UI into the Google Cloud console.</p>
<p>Leveraging Google Cloud console components provides API providers and Portal Admins with a centralized platform to efficiently configure, publish, and manage your API consumer portals, eliminating the need to switch between different UIs.</p>
<p>No new APIs have been introduced in this release.</p>
<p>See <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/api-platform/publish/publishing-overview">Publishing overview</a> to get started.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Apigee Integrated Developer Portal Admin UI is now available in the Google Cloud console, offering a centralized platform for API providers and Portal Admins to manage API consumer portals without switching between different UIs.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Apigee Developer Portal Admin UI now in Google Cloud console</title>
  </entry>
</feed>