<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Compute Engine</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Compute Engine</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/compute-engine/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-09-17:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Compute Engine enforces limits to the total baseline performance that a project's Hyperdisk Balanced and Hyperdisk Balanced High Availability disks that are in the same zone can consume at the same time. The aggregate baseline performance limit is 50 GiB/s of throughput and 500,000 IOPS, and it only applies to baseline performance. For a detailed explanation, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/disks/hyperdisk-performance#baseline_consumption_limits">Concurrent consumption limits for baseline performance</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>New limits on concurrent throughput and IOPS for Hyperdisk Balanced and Hyperdisk Balanced High Availability disks are now in effect.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Hyperdisk Throughput and IOPS Limits</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-09-15:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Generally available</strong>: You can decrease a Compute Engine instance shutdown time by skipping the guest OS shutdown. This action speeds up an instance stop or deletion operation to release resources and quota faster. However, as abrupt guest OS shutdowns may cause data loss or corrupt file system data, we recommend that you skip a guest OS shutdown only when you delete instances, or when you stop instances which boot disks you don't plan to reuse. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/instances/decrease-shutdown-time">Decrease Compute Engine instances shutdown time</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now skip the guest OS shutdown to decrease Compute Engine instance shutdown time, which speeds up instance stop or deletion operations. Use this feature cautiously to avoid data loss.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Faster instance shutdown</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-09-12:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Preview</strong>: H4D VMs, designed for high performance computing (HPC) workloads, are now in preview. Based on 5th generation AMD EPYC Turin with Cloud RDMA 200 Gbps networking, H4D VMs offer 192 cores (SMT disabled), up to 1,488 GB of memory, and 3,750 GiB of Local SSD. H4D is optimized for tightly-coupled applications that scale across multiple nodes and offers RDMA-enabled 200 Gbps networking.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/compute-optimized-machines#h4d_series">H4D machine series</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>New H4D VMs are now available in preview, offering powerful AMD EPYC processors and high-speed networking for demanding HPC workloads.</summary>
    <title>Feature: H4D VMs in Preview</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-09-10:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Generally available</strong>: The <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/accelerator-optimized-machines#a4x-vms">accelerator-optimized A4X machine type</a>, the first GPU VM to run on Arm, is available on Compute Engine. The A4X machine series has the NVIDIA GB200 Grace Blackwell Superchips attached and runs on the NVIDIA GB200 NVL72 platform. Use this machine type to run your large artificial intelligence (AI) models, machine learning (ML), and high performance computing (HPC) workloads. The A4X machine type is currently available in the <code>us-central1-a</code> zone.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The new accelerator-optimized A4X machine type, the first GPU VM on Arm, is now generally available on Google Compute Engine. These VMs feature NVIDIA GB200 Grace Blackwell Superchips and are designed for large AI, ML, and HPC workloads. They are currently available in the `us-central1-a` zone.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Arm-based A4X VMs now on Compute Engine</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-09-09:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hyperdisk Balanced High Availability disks are available in all regions.
Hyperdisk Balanced High Availability disks synchronously replicate disk data from one zone to another. Cross-zonal replication provides data protection in the unlikely event of a zonal outage. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/disks/hd-types/hyperdisk-balanced-ha">About Hyperdisk Balanced High Availability</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Hyperdisk Balanced High Availability disks now offer cross-zonal data replication in all regions, ensuring data protection against zonal outages.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Hyperdisk Balanced Availability Now in All Regions</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-09-09:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Preview:</strong> Eight new organization policy constraints are available to help you
enforce security best practices for Compute Engine virtual machine (VM)
instances.</p>
<p>These <a href="https://cloud.google.com/resource-manager/docs/organization-policy/using-constraints#managed-constraints">managed constraints</a>
simplify governance for common security scenarios and integrate with safe
rollout tools like
<a href="https://cloud.google.com/resource-manager/docs/organization-policy/dry-run-policy">dry-run</a>
and
<a href="https://cloud.google.com/policy-intelligence/docs/test-organization-policies">simulation</a>,
letting you test their impact before enforcement.</p>
<p>The new constraints are as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>compute.managed.disableNestedVirtualization</code></li>
<li><code>compute.managed.disableSerialPortAccess</code></li>
<li><code>compute.managed.disableSerialPortLogging</code></li>
<li><code>compute.managed.disallowGlobalDns</code></li>
<li><code>compute.managed.requireOsConfig</code></li>
<li><code>compute.managed.requireOsLogin</code></li>
<li><code>compute.managed.vmCanIpForward</code></li>
<li><code>compute.managed.vmExternalIpAccess</code></li>
</ul>
<p>These constraints can evaluate metadata values at the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/metadata/overview#metadata-directories">VM instance, project, or
zonal level</a>. For more information about these managed constraints, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/resource-manager/docs/organization-policy/org-policy-constraints#managed-constraints">Managed
Constraints</a> in the Resource Manager documentation.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Eight new organization policy constraints are now available to help enforce security best practices for Compute Engine virtual machine (VM) instances. These managed constraints simplify governance for common security scenarios and integrate with safe rollout tools, allowing you to test their impact before enforcement.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Organization Policy Constraints for Compute Engine VMs</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-09-04:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hyperdisk Balanced High Availability (Hyperdisk Balanced HA) volumes attached to C3 instances have increased performance limits for several C3 machine types. The new limits for the updated machine types are as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>c3-*-8</code>: 50,000 IOPS and 800 MiB/s of throughput</li>
<li><code>c3-*-22</code>: 120,000 IOPS and 1,800 MiB/s of throughput</li>
<li><code>c3-*-44</code>: 160,000 IOPS and 2,400 MiB/s of throughput</li>
<li><code>c3-*-88</code>: 160,000 IOPS and 4,800 MiB/s of throughput</li>
<li><code>c3-*-176</code>: 160,000 IOPS and 10,000 MiB/s of throughput</li>
<li><code>c3-*-192</code>: 160,000 IOPS and 10,000 MiB/s of throughput</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/disks/hd-types/hyperdisk-balanced-ha#perf-limits">Performance limits when attached to an instance</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Performance limits for Hyperdisk Balanced HA volumes attached to C3 instances have been increased for several machine types, offering higher IOPS and throughput.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Hyperdisk Balanced HA performance increase for C3 instances</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-09-04:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Generally available</strong>: <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/images/os-details#network-features">Windows OS images</a> have been updated with a new version of the gVNIC driver. Third generation and later compute instances that use these updated Windows OS images support up to <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/network-bandwidth#summary-table">200 Gbps networking bandwidth</a> and <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/network-bandwidth#jumbo-mtu">Jumbo frames</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>New versions of the gVNIC driver are available for Windows OS images. This update enhances network performance for third-generation and later compute instances, supporting up to 200 Gbps bandwidth and Jumbo frames.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Updated Windows OS Images with gVNIC Driver</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-08-28:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Generally available:</strong> <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/memory-optimized-machines#m4_series">M4 memory-optimized hypermem VMs</a> are now generally available. These smaller machine types expand the memory-optimized family to allow for greater flexibility in matching your specific application needs. Hypermem VMs have a GB/vCPU ratio of 15.5:1 and are offered in the following sizes:</p>
<ul>
<li>m4-hypermem-16</li>
<li>m4-hypermem-32</li>
<li>m4-hypermem-64</li>
</ul>
<p>See the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/regions-zones">Regions and zones</a> page to learn where you can create M4 VMs.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Smaller memory-optimized VMs are now available, offering greater flexibility with a 15.5 GB/vCPU ratio.</summary>
    <title>Feature: M4 Hypermem VMs Now Generally Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-08-26:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Generally available</strong>: You can create instances that use only IPv6 IP addresses. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/instances/create-ipv6-instance#create-vm-ipv6-only">Create an IPv6-only instance</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now create instances that use only IPv6 addresses. This feature is generally available.</summary>
    <title>Feature: IPv6-only instances are now generally available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-08-20:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can use instant snapshots to back up Extreme Persistent Disk volumes. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/disks/instant-snapshots">About instant snapshots</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now use instant snapshots to back up Extreme Persistent Disk volumes.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Instant Snapshots for Extreme Persistent Disk</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-08-14:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Public Preview</strong>: You can now access the Compute Engine alpha API at the project level through a self-service process. By enabling the alpha API, you can use the Google Cloud console, gcloud CLI, API, and Terraform to view and manage Preview features. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/reference/rest/alpha">Use the Compute Engine alpha API</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Access the Compute Engine alpha API at the project level via self-service to manage preview features using the Google Cloud console, gcloud CLI, API, and Terraform.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Compute Engine Alpha API Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-08-13:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Generally available:</strong> License Manager is now generally available. License Manager lets you subscribe, manage, and track your third-party license usage on Google Cloud. As an administrator, you can use License Manager to offer per-user licensing products, like Microsoft Office, to your users with no long-term commitments and no overhead of managing compliance.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/instances/windows/license-manager">About License Manager</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Manage third-party licenses on Google Cloud.</summary>
    <title>Feature: License Manager Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-08-11:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Preview</strong>: The
<a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/accelerator-optimized-machines#g4-series">G4 accelerator-optimized machine series</a>
is designed for graphics-intensive workloads such as NVIDIA Omniverse
simulations, video transcoding, and virtual desktops. The G4 machine series also
provides a cost-effective solution for single-host inference and model tuning.</p>
<p>Powered by the 5th Generation AMD EPYC Turin CPU platform and featuring
<a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/data-center/rtx-pro-6000-blackwell-server-edition/">NVIDIA RTX PRO 6000 Blackwell Server Edition</a>
GPUs, the G4 machine series offer significant performance improvements over the
previous G2 machine series. For available G4
regions and zones, see
<a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/gpus/gpu-regions-zones#view-using-table">GPU regions and zones</a>.</p>
<p>To get started with G4 machine types, contact your Google account team.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The G4 machine series, powered by AMD EPYC and NVIDIA RTX GPUs, offers enhanced performance for graphics-intensive tasks like simulations and virtual desktops, serving as a cost-effective option for inference and model tuning.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New G4 Machine Series for Graphics Workloads</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-08-11:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can attach up to 128 instances to the same Hyperdisk ML volume whose size is between 2 TiB and 16 TiB. The previous limit was 30. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/disks/sharing-disks-between-vms">Share a disk between instances</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Attach up to 128 instances to the same Hyperdisk ML volume.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Increased instance limits for Hyperdisk ML volumes</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-08-05:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For Hyperdisk Throughput, the maximum IOPS for a single volume has increased from 600 MiB/s to 2,400 MiB/s. The maximum IOPS for a single volume has increased from 2,400 IOPS to 9,600 IOPS. Hyperdisk Throughput volumes are designed for cost-sensitive workloads, analytics workloads, and workloads that have sequential I/O and large block sizes. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/disks/hd-types/hyperdisk-throughput">About Hyperdisk Throughput</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>IOPS increase for Hyperdisk Throughput.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New IOPS increase for Hyperdisk Throughput</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-08-05:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Generally Available</strong>: The storage-optimized Z3 machine series offers a bare metal (<code>z3-highmem-192-highlssd-metal</code>) machine type with 192 vCPUs, 1,536 GB of memory, and 72 TiB of Local SSD storage.</p>
<p>Bare metal instances let you create an instance with direct access to the machine's CPU and memory, without a virtualization layer in the middle. Z3 uses <a href="https://cloud.google.com/titanium">Titanium</a> to deliver more compute and memory resources for your workloads by offloading network and I/O processing from the host hardware. To learn more, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/storage-optimized-machines#z3_series">Z3 machine series</a>. For information about bare metal instances, including regional availability, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/instances/bare-metal-instances">Bare metal instances on Compute Engine</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Introducing the Z3 machine series, offering storage-optimized instances with direct hardware access.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Z3 Machine Series Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-08-05:deprecated:2</id>
    <published>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Compute Engine feature that deploys containers on VMs during VM creation is deprecated. For more information about the alternative solutions for running containers on VMs and MIGs, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/deprecations/container-startup-agent-on-compute">Compute Engine container startup agent deprecation</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Container deployment on VM creation is deprecated.</summary>
    <title>Deprecated: Feature Deprecation</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-07-30:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Generally available</strong>: The general purpose C4 machine series now supports the following machine types on Intel's Xeon 6 processor (Granite Rapids):</p>
<ul>
<li>C4 VMs with Titanium Local SSD attached using new machine types:</li>
<li><code>c4-standard-*-lssd</code></li>
<li><code>c4-highmem-*-lssd</code></li>
<li>New bare metal machine types:</li>
<li><code>c4-standard-288-metal</code></li>
<li><code>c4-highmem-288-metal</code></li>
<li>C4 <code>standard</code>, <code>highmem</code>, and <code>highcpu</code> VMs with 144 and 288 vCPUs</li>
</ul>
<p>To learn more, see the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/general-purpose-machines#c4_series">C4 machine series</a>.</p>
<p>For more information, about the attached Local SSD disks, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/disks/local-ssd#lssd_disks_fixed">Machine types that automatically attach Local SSD disks</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>New C4 machine types now available for Intel's Xeon 6 processor, including options with Titanium Local SSD and bare metal configurations.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New C4 Machine Types Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-07-25:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hyperdisk Extreme is available in all regions and zones.
For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/disks/hd-types/hyperdisk-extreme">About Hyperdisk Extreme</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Hyperdisk Extreme is now available everywhere.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Hyperdisk Extreme Now Available Globally</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-07-25:changed:1</id>
    <published>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now resize Hyperdisk Balanced volumes twice within a 4-hour window. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/disks/modify-hyperdisks#capacity_changes">Capacity changes</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now resize Hyperdisk Balanced volumes twice within a 4-hour window.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Hyperdisk Balanced volume resize frequency increased</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-07-24:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Generally available</strong>: The general-purpose C4 machine series now supports Hyperdisk Balanced High Availability. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/general-purpose-machines#supported_disk_types_for_c4">Supported disk types for C4</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The C4 machine series now supports Hyperdisk Balanced High Availability.</summary>
    <title>Feature: C4 machine series now supports Hyperdisk Balanced High Availability</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-07-23:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When a regional Persistent Disk volume is fully replicated, Compute Engine now refreshes its replica recovery checkpoint every 15 minutes.</p>
<p>Learn more about <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/disks/about-regional-persistent-disk#repd-replica-recovery-checkpoint">Regional Persistent Disk replica recovery checkpoints</a> and <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/disks/repd-failover#recover-repd-using-checkpoint">how to use checkpoints to recover a degraded disk</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Persistent Disk replica recovery checkpoint refresh frequency increased to 15 minutes.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Persistent Disk Checkpoint Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-07-22:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Preview</strong>: Multi-writer support for Hyperdisk Extreme disks. You can give up to 16 instances simultaneous read-write access to the same disk. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/disks/sharing-disks-between-vms">Share disks between instances</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Multi-writer support for Hyperdisk Extreme disks.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New feature: Multi-writer support for Hyperdisk Extreme</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-07-21:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Generally available</strong>: The general-purpose C4D machine series offers the following bare metal machine types:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>c4d-standard-384-metal</code></li>
<li><code>c4d-highcpu-384-metal</code></li>
<li><code>c4d-highmem-384-metal</code></li>
</ul>
<p>This is the first machine series to offer AMD-based bare metal instances. Bare metal instances let you create an instance with direct access to the machine's CPU and memory, without a virtualization layer in the middle. C4D uses <a href="https://cloud.google.com/titanium">Titanium</a> to deliver more compute and memory resources for your workloads by offloading network and I/O processing from the host hardware. To learn more, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/general-purpose-machines#c4d_series">C4D machine series</a>. For information about bare metal instances, including regional availability, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/instances/bare-metal-instances#c4d-metal">Bare metal instances on Compute Engine</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The new C4D machine series, featuring AMD EPYC processors, is now generally available. These bare metal instances provide direct access to hardware resources, offering enhanced performance for demanding workloads. The series includes standard, high-CPU, and high-memory configurations.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New AMD-based bare metal instances now available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-07-18:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Generally available</strong>: You can create instant and standard snapshots from Hyperdisk volumes in multi-writer mode. You can also clone Hyperdisk volumes in multi-writer mode.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/disks/sharing-disks-between-vms">Share disks between instances</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Snapshots and cloning for multi-writer Hyperdisks are now generally available. This allows for greater flexibility in managing and sharing your storage.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Hyperdisk Snapshots and Cloning Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-07-15:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Compute flexible committed use discounts (CUDs) offer expanded coverage by
supporting the following resources and services:</p>
<ul>
<li>Memory-optimized M1, M2, M3, and M4 VMs</li>
<li>Compute-optimized H3 instances</li>
<li>Cloud Run services with request-based billing</li>
<li>Cloud Run Functions</li>
</ul>
<p>To receive the expanded coverage for flexible CUDs, you must opt in to the new
spend-based CUD model. Cloud Billing accounts that meet specific criteria are
automatically opted into the new model. On January 21, 2026, all remaining
accounts will automatically migrate to the new model. You can opt in before that
date to start receiving the expanded coverage. To learn more about the new model
and the opt-in details, see
<a href="https://cloud.google.com/docs/cuds-multiprice">Spend-based CUDs program improvements</a>.</p>
<p>To learn more about this change and how your flexible CUDs apply after you opt
in, see
<a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/instances/committed-use-discounts-overview#spend_based">Compute flexible CUDs</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Compute flexible committed use discounts now cover memory-optimized VMs (M1-M4), compute-optimized H3 instances, and Cloud Run services. To benefit from this expanded coverage, opt into the new spend-based CUD model before January 21, 2026, when all remaining accounts will be automatically migrated.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Expanded Coverage for Flexible Committed Use Discounts</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-07-02:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Preview</strong>: You can reserve GPU VMs that use A4 and A3 Ultra machine types by using future reservations in calendar mode. This feature lets you reserve up to 80 GPU VMs for up to 90 days to obtain capacity for the following workloads:</p>
<ul>
<li>Model pre-training jobs</li>
<li>Model fine-tuning jobs</li>
<li>High performance computing (HPC) simulation workloads</li>
<li>Short-term expected increases in inference workloads</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/instances/future-reservations-calendar-mode-overview">About future reservation requests in calendar mode</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now reserve A4 and A3 Ultra GPU VMs using future reservations in calendar mode. This allows for capacity booking of up to 80 GPU VMs for 90 days, suitable for model training, HPC, and inference workloads.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Reserve GPU VMs with Future Reservations</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-07-02:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Generally available</strong>: You can create Z3 VMs using smaller machine types, ranging in size from 14 to 88 vCPUs. Also, Z3 now offers <code>-standardlssd</code> and <code>-highlssd</code> predefined machine types. These new machine types have different amounts of Local SSD capacity per vCPU.</p>
<p>When you use Local SSD disks with Z3 VMs, you can receive committed use discounts (CUDs) without needing to <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/instances/reservations-with-commitments#committed_resources_that_require_attached_reservations">attach reservations to your commitments</a>.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/storage-optimized-machines">Storage-optimized machines</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Z3 VMs now support a wider range of machine types, from 14 to 88 vCPUs, including new predefined machine types with varying Local SSD capacities. Additionally, using Local SSDs with Z3 VMs now qualifies for committed use discounts without requiring reservation attachments.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Z3 VMs now more flexible with new machine types</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-07-02:feature:2</id>
    <published>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Preview</strong>: The general purpose C4 machine series now supports the following machine types on Intel's Xeon 6 processor (Granite Rapids):</p>
<ul>
<li>C4 VMs with Titanium Local SSD attached using two new machine types:</li>
<li><code>c4-standard-*-lssd</code></li>
<li><code>c4-highmem-*-lssd</code></li>
<li>Three new bare metal machine types:</li>
<li><code>c4-standard-288-metal</code></li>
<li><code>c4-highcpu-288-metal</code></li>
<li><code>c4-highmem-288-metal</code></li>
<li>C4 <code>standard</code>, <code>highmem</code>, and <code>highcpu</code> VMs with 144 and 288 vCPUs</li>
</ul>
<p>To learn more, see the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/general-purpose-machines#c4_series">C4 machine series</a>.</p>
<p>For more information, about the attached Local SSD disks, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/disks/local-ssd#lssd_disks_fixed">Machine types that automatically attach Local SSD disks</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The C4 machine series now supports new machine types on Intel's Xeon 6 processor (Granite Rapids), including VMs with Titanium Local SSD and bare metal options. This expansion provides more choices for various workloads.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New C4 machine types available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-06-30:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Generally available</strong>: You can now modify licenses attached to your disks. Previously, licenses on disk resources were immutable. You had to delete and recreate disks, or engage our support team to change licenses.</p>
<p>This feature provides greater flexibility for managing your disk licenses. You can now:</p>
<ul>
<li>Append, remove, replace, and view the history of license updates.</li>
<li>Perform in-place license upgrades, such as <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/images/premium/ubuntu-pro/upgrade-from-ubuntu">Ubuntu to Ubuntu Pro</a>, using the <code>gcloud</code> CLI and REST.</li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/licenses/switch-between-payg-and-byos">Switch from PAYG to BYOS billing</a> models.</li>
<li>Review <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/licenses/license-changes-and-restrictions">license changes and restrictions</a> and <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/images/premium/rhel/append-els-licenses">append a RHEL ELS</a> license to a newer version.</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information on how to manage licenses, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com//compute/docs/licenses/manage">Manage licenses</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now easily modify licenses attached to your disks, append, remove, replace, and view license history. This provides greater flexibility for managing disk licenses, including in-place upgrades and switching between billing models.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Modify disk licenses</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-06-27:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Generally available</strong>: You can specify a custom ephemeral external IPv6 address when creating an instance. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/instances/create-ipv6-instance">Create instances that use IPv6 addresses</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now specify a custom ephemeral external IPv6 address when creating an instance. This feature is now generally available.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Custom ephemeral IPv6 address for instances</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-06-13:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Generally available</strong>: General purpose <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/general-purpose-machines#c4d_series">C4D machine types</a>, powered by the fifth generation AMD EPYC processors (Turin) and Google Titanium, are generally available.</p>
<p>C4D is designed to run mission-critical workloads including web app and game servers, AI inference, web serving, video streaming, and data centric applications like analytics, relational, and in-memory databases.</p>
<p>C4D is available in <code>standard</code>, <code>highmem</code>, and <code>highcpu</code> machine types and supports only Google Cloud Hyperdisk storage and Titanium SSD. To learn more about C4D, refer to the <a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/compute/c4d-vms-unparalleled-performance-for-business-workloads">C4D release blog</a>. For details about where you can create C4D instances, see the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/regions-zones#available">Regions and zones</a> page.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The new C4D machine types, featuring AMD EPYC processors and Google Titanium, are now generally available. These general-purpose VMs are ideal for a wide range of mission-critical workloads, including web applications, game servers, AI inference, and data-centric applications like databases and analytics.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New C4D machine types now available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-06-13:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Preview</strong>: Dynamic NICs let you add or remove network interfaces to or from an instance without having to restart or recreate the instance.</p>
<p>You can also use Dynamic NICs when you need more network interfaces. The maximum number of vNICs for most machine types in Google Cloud is 10; however, you can configure up to 16 total interfaces by using Dynamic NICs.</p>
<p>For more information, see the following:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/multiple-interfaces-concepts">Multiple network interfaces overview</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/create-use-multiple-interfaces">Create VM instances with multiple network interfaces</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/add-dynamic-nics">Add Dynamic NICs to an instance</a></li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now add or remove network interfaces from your instances without needing to restart them. This feature allows for more network interfaces, with the possibility of configuring up to 16 total interfaces for most machine types.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Dynamic NICs: Add or remove network interfaces without restarting</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-06-11:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Preview</strong>: The storage-optimized Z3 machine series offers a bare metal (<code>-metal</code>) machine type with 192 vCPUs. Bare metal instances let you create an instance with direct access to the machine's CPU and memory, without a virtualization layer in the middle. To learn more, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/storage-optimized-machines#z3_series">Z3 machine series</a>. For information about bare metal instances, including regional availability, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/instances/bare-metal-instances">Bare metal instances on Compute Engine</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Introducing the storage-optimized Z3 machine series, now available with a bare metal option. This new machine type provides direct access to the machine's CPU and memory, bypassing the virtualization layer for enhanced performance.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Z3 Machine Series with Bare Metal Option</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-06-10:security:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A vulnerability (CVE-2025-2884) affecting Shielded VMs using virtual Trusted Platform Module (vTPM) was discovered and is being addressed. For more information, see the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/security-bulletins#gcp-2025-031">GCP-2025-031 security bulletin</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A vulnerability (CVE-2025-2884) affecting Shielded VMs with vTPM has been identified and is being resolved. Further details are available in the security bulletin GCP-205-031.</summary>
    <title>Security: Security vulnerability in Shielded VMs</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-06-06:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Generally available</strong>: The <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/monitor-security-risks-console">Security Risk Overview dashboard for Compute Engine</a> is generally available. In addition, it provides a <strong>Top CVE findings</strong> table that lists the most severe CVEs that affect your Compute Engine instances.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Security Risk Overview dashboard for Compute Engine is now generally available. This update includes a new table listing the most severe CVE findings affecting your Compute Engine instances.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Security Risk Overview dashboard for Compute Engine now available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-06-04:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Preview</strong>: OS Login now supports connections from SSH certificates in addition to SSH keys. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/oslogin/certificates">Set up OS Login to require SSH certificates for SSH connections</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>OS Login now supports connecting via SSH certificates, enhancing security and flexibility.</summary>
    <title>Feature: OS Login supports SSH certificates</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-06-03:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Preview</strong>: You can enable your project to send HTTP requests to a Compute Engine feature alpha URI. This action lets you test and develop with experimental features in the alpha stage using REST. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/reference/rest/alpha">Use the Compute Engine API in alpha</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now test and develop with experimental features in the alpha stage using REST by enabling your project to send HTTP requests to a Compute Engine alpha URI.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Test new Compute Engine features</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:compute-engine:2025-06-02:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Preview</strong>: The general-purpose C4D machine series offers bare metal (<code>-metal</code>) machine types with 384 vCPUs. Bare metal instances let you create an instance with direct access to the machine's CPU and memory, without a virtualization layer in the middle. To learn more, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/general-purpose-machines#c4d_series">C4D machine series</a>. For information about bare metal instances, including regional availability, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/instances/bare-metal-instances">Bare metal instances on Compute Engine</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The new C4D machine series now offers bare metal instances with 384 vCPUs, providing direct access to the machine's CPU and memory without a virtualization layer. This feature enhances performance for demanding workloads.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Introducing C4D bare metal instances</title>
  </entry>
</feed>