<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Manufacturing Data Engine</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Manufacturing Data Engine</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:manufacturing-data-engine</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/manufacturing-data-engine/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:manufacturing-data-engine:2025-12-10:release 1.5.2:0</id>
    <published>2025-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This release is a <strong>critical update</strong> if you have an existing deployment of
MDE version 1.5.0. This release introduces a new configuration package upload
option that allows users to automatically enable and activate all entities
created following the upload. It also includes other minor improvements and bug
fixes.</p>
<p>Follow the <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/manufacturing-data-engine/docs/deployment/upgrade-guide">Upgrade guide</a>
in the MDE documentation for detailed instructions. Note that instructions are
different depending on the MDE version you are upgrading from.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A critical update, MDE version 1.5.2, is now available. This release introduces a new configuration package upload option for automatic entity activation and includes general improvements and bug fixes. Refer to the upgrade guide for detailed instructions.</summary>
    <title>Release 1.5.2: MDE Release 1.5.2 Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:manufacturing-data-engine:2025-12-10:change:1</id>
    <published>2025-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><strong>Improvement (441727217)</strong>: Introduced an option to enable parsers after
  types activation when you upload a new configuration package.</li>
<li><strong>Improvement (333321871)</strong>: Refactored scripts to collect additional
  information for the MDE team when you open a support ticket to help
  faster troubleshooting.</li>
<li><strong>Improvement (441660844)</strong>: Added <code>typesMetadataBuckets</code> and
  <code>typesTransformations</code> JSON arrays as responses to the Tags API implementation.</li>
<li><strong>Improvement (435358499)</strong>: Enabled Streaming Engine for Dataflow in all
  MDE deployment sizes for optimized consumption, saving resources.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Upload new configurations with an option to enable parsers after type activation. We've also enhanced support ticket information collection and improved Dataflow performance with Streaming Engine.</summary>
    <title>Change: New configuration and improved diagnostics</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:manufacturing-data-engine:2025-12-10:security:2</id>
    <published>2025-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><strong>Improvement (448853115)</strong>: Added the ability to
  enable and configure VPC flow logging from Terraform. Collecting VPC flow logs
  is recommended to detect potential intrusions or anomalies.</li>
<li><strong>Improvement (450530585)</strong>: Updated container images
  and dependencies to address known security vulnerabilities.</li>
<li><strong>Improvement (448854007):</strong> Adjusted IAM roles used
  by some MDE service accounts following the least-privilege approach.</li>
<li><strong>Improvement (448148987)</strong>: Switched to DNS-based endpoint with AIM access
  control for GKE control plane, following security best practices.</li>
<li><strong>Improvement (448148673)</strong>: Enabled SSL required mode on the Cloud SQL
  instance for additional security enforcement.</li>
<li><strong>Improvement (448148275)</strong>: Enabled in-transit encryption and token
  authentication for Redis.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>This update introduces several security enhancements, including the ability to enable VPC flow logging via Terraform, updated container images to address vulnerabilities, adjusted IAM roles, and enforced SSL/encryption for services like GKE, Cloud SQL, and Redis.</summary>
    <title>Security: Enhanced Security Measures</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:manufacturing-data-engine:2025-12-10:libraries:3</id>
    <published>2025-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Release signature</strong></p>
<p><code>6e178bd
1.5.2
9ee64699a1bdf1cf690e7930d968f002</code></p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new version of the library has been released. Please update to version 1.5.2 to benefit from the latest improvements and fixes.</summary>
    <title>Libraries: New Library Version Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:manufacturing-data-engine:2025-12-10:fixed:4</id>
    <published>2025-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><strong>Fix (423567127):</strong> Fixed a bug that prevented numeric values to be
  correctly processed when using file ingestion.</li>
<li><strong>Fix (441294785):</strong> Fixed a bug that prevented the deletion of a message
  class if the related parser had been deleted beforehand.</li>
<li><strong>Fix (443710570)</strong>: Fixed a bug that could use an old version of a parser
  script when uploading a new configuration package that had the same parser name.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Several bugs have been fixed, including issues with numeric value processing during file ingestion, message class deletion, and parser script versioning.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Bug Fixes</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:manufacturing-data-engine:2025-08-29:release 1.5.1:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This release is a <strong>critical update</strong> if you have an existing deployment of MDE version 1.5.0. This release resolves a bug regarding materialization of metadata instances created prior to MDE 1.5.0. This release also includes other minor improvements and bug fixes.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Critical update for MDE 1.5.0 users. Addresses metadata materialization bug and includes minor improvements.</summary>
    <title>Release 1.5.1: Release 1.5.1</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:manufacturing-data-engine:2025-08-29:libraries:1</id>
    <published>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Release signature</strong></p>
<p>```
b0fc163
1.5.1
ffb87d39d343c20abebd2f52df74a2d3</p>
<p>```</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Release signature b0fc163 1.5.1 ffb87d39d343c20abebd2f52df74a2d3</summary>
    <title>Libraries: Libraries</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:manufacturing-data-engine:2025-08-29:fixed:2</id>
    <published>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><strong>Fix (417666631):</strong> Fixed an issue with metadata materialization for metadata instances that had been created prior to migrating to MDE 1.5.0.</li>
<li><strong>Fix (420921890):</strong> Fixed an error when attempting to update an instance tag metadata and saved it for instances that had been created prior to migrating to MDE 1.5.0.</li>
<li><strong>Fix (423535516)</strong>: Fixed inconsistent API response codes when trying to delete non-existing entities.</li>
<li><strong>Fix (383519276)</strong>: Fixed missing fields in MDE logging and added more details to make troubleshooting easier.</li>
<li><strong>Fix (424077359)</strong>: Fixed instance bucket creation through API. It now adds default <code>createdTime</code> as the time when the API call was received.</li>
<li><strong>Fix (422991109 and 424084607)</strong>: Fixed <code>ghost</code> deletion of Types and Metadata Buckets after removing a configuration package.</li>
<li><strong>Fix (423859259)</strong>: Fixed removal of BigQuery views when a Type is manually deleted.</li>
<li><strong>Fix (406803212)</strong>: Fixed wrong version materialization on MDE system tables.</li>
<li><strong>Fix (407015039)</strong>: Fixed <code>Delete</code> button in MDE UI when the system is in PROD mode (Production mode).</li>
<li><strong>Fix (435653743)</strong>: Fixed missing Grafana Terraform module.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Several issues have been resolved, including problems with metadata materialization, instance tag updates, API response codes, MDE logging, instance bucket creation, ghost deletion of Types and Metadata Buckets, removal of BigQuery views, MDE system tables versioning, the Delete button in MDE UI, and the Grafana Terraform module.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Resolved various issues for improved stability</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:manufacturing-data-engine:2025-08-29:security:3</id>
    <published>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><strong>Improvement (427447932)</strong>: Brought Docker images to versions without vulnerabilities reported at the time of the release.</li>
<li><strong>Improvement (361290775)</strong>: Modified Terraform deployment scripts to enforce TLS v1.2 for an external MDE UI Load Balancer.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Docker images updated to remove vulnerabilities. Terraform scripts updated to enforce TLS v1.2 for external MDE UI Load Balancer.</summary>
    <title>Security: Security Improvements</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:manufacturing-data-engine:2025-08-29:changed:4</id>
    <published>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><strong>Improvement (407009198)</strong>: Improved the error handling when <code>upload</code> and <code>parsing</code> configuration packages.</li>
<li><strong>Improvement (423531705):</strong> Improved MDE logging for BigQuery sink related operations.</li>
<li><strong>Improvement (423530033):</strong> Improved manifest validation on configuration package uploads.</li>
<li><strong>Improvement (423554635)</strong>: Added <code>CreatedAt</code> column with default sorting on the MDE UI configuration packages page.</li>
<li><strong>Improvement (430962108):</strong> Added more sorting options on the MDE UI <em>Configurations</em> and <em>Metadata Instances</em> pages.</li>
<li><strong>Improvement (423531714)</strong>: Various improvements on Helm charts, including image tag management, and k8s secrets/configmaps.</li>
<li><strong>Improvement (407037164)</strong>: More descriptive message added to MDE UI to confirm Type deletion.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Error handling for upload and parsing configuration packages has been improved. Logging for BigQuery sink operations and manifest validation on uploads have also been enhanced. Additionally, new sorting options and a 'CreatedAt' column have been added to the MDE UI.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Configuration package improvements</title>
  </entry>
</feed>