<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Cortex Framework</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Cortex Framework</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cortex-framework</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/cortex-framework/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cortex-framework:2025-12-17:fixed:0</id>
    <published>2025-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><strong>SAP</strong>: Added support for future dates to <code>currency_conversion</code>.</li>
<li><strong>Cloud Build Image</strong>: Updated gcloud SDK to v541 and Python library
  dependencies used during Cloud Build deployment.</li>
<li><strong>Composer DAG</strong>: Corrected propagation of location parameterization.</li>
<li><strong>Cortex for Marketing</strong>: Updated references to Google Ads API v22.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>This release includes updates for SAP currency conversion to support future dates. Additionally, Cloud Build images and Composer DAGs have been improved, and Cortex for Marketing references have been updated to the latest Google Ads API version.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: SAP currency support and tool updates</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cortex-framework:2025-12-17:change:1</id>
    <published>2025-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><strong>SAP</strong>: The column <code>DUMMY_SDDOCPARTNER_INCL_EEW_PS</code> has been removed from
  <em>SalesOrderPartnerFunction</em> (ECC and S/4) as it is a non-standard column not
  used for reporting.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>The DUMMY_SDDOCPARTNER_INCL_EEW_PS column has been removed from SalesOrderPartnerFunction in both ECC and S/4 systems. This change was made because the column is non-standard and not utilized for reporting purposes.</summary>
    <title>Change: SalesOrderPartnerFunction column removed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cortex-framework:2025-12-17:deprecated:2</id>
    <published>2025-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><strong>SAP</strong>: Cortex's Data Mesh functionality has been deprecated. This change
  is prompted by the evolution of Google Cloud data management services. The Data
  Mesh solution was built using Data Catalog for metadata management, which is
  now being replaced by the more advanced
  <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/dataplex/docs/introduction">Dataplex Universal Catalog</a>.
  Dataplex Universal Catalog provides a unified API, enhanced metadata capabilities, and
  new features for a more comprehensive data governance experience. For existing
  Cortex Framework users who have implemented the Data Mesh feature, we recommend
  transitioning to Dataplex Universal Catalog to ensure continued support and access to the
  latest features. For a detailed migration guide, see
  <a href="https://cloud.google.com/dataplex/docs/transition-to-dataplex-catalog">Transition to Dataplex Universal Catalog</a>.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>The Data Mesh functionality within Cortex is now deprecated. This is due to advancements in Google Cloud's data management services, specifically the introduction of Dataplex Universal Catalog, which offers enhanced metadata management and data governance. We recommend transitioning to Dataplex Universal Catalog for continued support and improved capabilities.</summary>
    <title>Deprecated: Data Mesh functionality deprecated</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cortex-framework:2025-12-17:release 6.3.3:3</id>
    <published>2025-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[]]></content>
    <summary>We are pleased to announce the release of version 6.3.3. This update includes important bug fixes and performance enhancements to improve your experience.</summary>
    <title>Release 6.3.3: Release 6.3.3 is Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cortex-framework:2025-09-19:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><strong>1-Click Deployer</strong>: 1-Click deployer now deploys the
  <a href="https://cloud.google.com/cortex/docs/dun-and-bradstreet">Sustainability</a> module when SAP ECC or S/4 is selected.</li>
<li><strong>SAP</strong>:</li>
<li>The CDC script now considers the <code>L</code> flag alongside <code>I</code> and <code>U</code> when
    determining which records are updated in the raw dataset. This is to account
    for situations where the pipeline is somehow re-configured after data load,
    but the CDC dataset can still be reused to avoid re-processing existing data.</li>
<li>Column names in <code>StockInHand</code> views (ECC and S/4) for <code>MATNR</code> and
    <code>WERKS</code> have been aligned with other views to be <code>MaterialNumber_MATNR</code>
    and <code>Plant_WERKS</code>. Previous column names <code>ArticleNumber_MATNR</code> and
    <code>Site_WERKS</code> still exist for compatibility reasons, but will be removed in
    a future release. Customers are advised to change their upstream consumption assets accordingly.</li>
<li>Column names in <code>SalesOrders_V2</code> views (ECC and S/4) for <code>ERDAT</code> and
    <code>ERZET</code> have been aligned to new names <code>SalesDocumentCreationDate_ERDAT</code>,
    <code>SalesOrderItemCreationDate_ERDAT</code>, <code>SalesOrderCreationTime_ERZET</code> and
    <code>SalesDocumentItemCreationTime_ERZET</code> to account for the correct
    granularity of their source table (either <code>VBAP</code> or <code>VBAK</code>) . Previous
    column names <code>CreationDate_ERDAT</code> and <code>CreationTime_ERZET</code> still exist for
    compatibility reasons, but will eventually be removed in a future release.
    Customers are advised to change their upstream consumption assets
    accordingly. Also, Sales Order Item level calendar dimensions are now added
    by default.</li>
<li>Column names in <code>Deliveries</code> view for <code>VGBEL</code>, <code>VGPOS</code>, and <code>XBLNR</code> are
    updated to <code>InternalReferenceDocumentNumber_VGBEL</code>,
    <code>InternalReferenceDocumentItem_VGPOS</code> <code>ExternalReferenceDocumentNumber_XBLNR</code>
    for more clarity. Previous column names <code>SalesOrderNumber_VGBEL</code>,
    <code>SalesOrderItem_VGPOS</code>, and <code>ReferenceDocumentNumber_XBLNR</code> still exist for
    compatibility reasons, but will eventually be removed in a future release.
    Customers are advised to change their upstream consumption assets
    accordingly.</li>
<li>Sales Order Item level calendar dimensions are now added by default.</li>
<li>In <code>AccountingDocuments</code> view as well as the downstream
    <code>AccountingDocumentsReceivables</code> views, <code>DoubtfulReceivables</code>, and
    <code>DaysInArrear</code> metrics are now positive instead of negative to align with
    <a href="https://help.sap.com/docs/SAP_S4HANA_ON-PREMISE/3cb1182b4a184bdd93f8d62e3f1f0741/39a73b581aee2160e10000000a44147b.html">official SAP guidelines</a>.</li>
<li><code>SalesFulfillment</code> and <code>SalesFulfillment_PerOrder</code> views are updated
    to use <code>SalesOrders_V2</code> instead of <code>SalesOrders</code> view as their upstream
    source for both ECC and S/4. The view signatures are unchanged.</li>
<li>ERD for both <a href="https://cloud.google.com/cortex/docs/operational-sap#sap-ecc">ECC</a> and
    <a href="https://cloud.google.com/cortex/docs/operational-sap#sap-s4-hana">S/4</a> have been cleaned up and
    updated based on the latest changes.</li>
<li><strong>Marketing</strong>: Cortex for Meridian reporting views adapted to TikTok, Meta,
  and YouTube (DV360) to focus on top of the funnel marketing campaigns. Search
  Ads data is skipped from aggregates as higher quality data is now available from
  Marketing Mix Modeling (MMM) Data Platform.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>The 1-Click Deployer now includes the Sustainability module for SAP ECC and S/4. Several SAP views have updated column names for clarity and alignment with SAP guidelines, including StockInHand, SalesOrders_V2, Deliveries, and AccountingDocuments. Sales Fulfillment views now use SalesOrders_V2 as their source. Marketing reporting views for TikTok, Meta, and YouTube have been adapted, and Search Ads data is now excluded from aggregates.</summary>
    <title>Changed: SAP and Marketing Updates</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cortex-framework:2025-09-19:fixed:1</id>
    <published>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><strong>SAP</strong>:</li>
<li><code>Qty</code> field data type in <code>StockInHand</code> views (ECC and S/4) has been
    changed from <code>STRING</code> to <code>NUMERIC</code>.</li>
<li>Currency conversion and currency decimal shift in <code>PurchaseDocuments_Flow</code>
    views (ECC and S/4) now align with the logic implemented in all other SAP
    reporting views.</li>
<li>Fixed incorrect GR quantity caused by an incorrect <code>JOIN</code> condition.</li>
<li>Removed an excessive <code>LEFT JOIN</code> in the Unit of Measure Function and View
    Utility code to avoid possible duplicate rows.</li>
<li>Cleaned up unnecessary date casting and <code>ORDER BY</code> clauses in some views
    to improve performance.</li>
<li><strong>Salesforce (SFDC):</strong></li>
<li>Currency conversion logic is now updated to account for possible source
    currency fields that are not corporate currency in the objects
    (for example, <code>Opportunities</code>).</li>
<li>Updated ERD to include proper linkage to calendar dimension.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>This release includes several fixes for SAP and Salesforce modules. Key updates include data type changes for the Qty field in StockInHand views, improved currency conversion logic in PurchaseDocuments_Flow views and Salesforce opportunities, and performance enhancements through code cleanup and optimized JOIN conditions. Additionally, the ERD has been updated for better calendar dimension linkage.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: SAP and Salesforce fixes</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cortex-framework:2025-09-19:deprecated:2</id>
    <published>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><strong>SAP</strong>: The views <code>GLDocumentsHdr</code> and <code>RegionsMD</code> are now removed as
  they are no longer relevant.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>The SAP views GLDocumentsHdr and RegionsMD have been removed as they are no longer relevant.</summary>
    <title>Deprecated: SAP Views Removed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cortex-framework:2025-09-19:issue:3</id>
    <published>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><strong>Oracle</strong> builds may time out when using a private worker pool created
  with default parameters.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Oracle builds may time out when using a private worker pool with default parameters.</summary>
    <title>Issue: Oracle builds may time out</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cortex-framework:2025-09-19:release 6.3.2:4</id>
    <published>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[]]></content>
    <summary>We are happy to announce the release of version 6.3.2. This release includes important security patches and performance improvements. We recommend all users to update to this version at their earliest convenience.</summary>
    <title>Release 6.3.2: Release 6.3.2</title>
  </entry>
</feed>