<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Google Cloud Marketplace</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Google Cloud Marketplace</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-marketplace</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/google-cloud-marketplace/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-marketplace:2025-11-06:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now offer Terraform Kubernetes apps through Google Cloud Marketplace with
usage-based pricing, in which customers pay for your app based on measurements
that you choose, called <em>metrics</em>, such as the number of containers or storage
time. For more information, see
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/marketplace/docs/partners/terraform-kubernetes#pricing">Pricing models for Terraform Kubernetes apps</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Google Cloud Marketplace now supports usage-based pricing for Terraform Kubernetes applications. This allows customers to pay based on chosen metrics like the number of containers or storage time.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Terraform Kubernetes apps now available with usage-based pricing on Google Cloud Marketplace</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-marketplace:2025-10-06:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We've updated the Cloud Commerce Procurement API's <code>GET Account</code> resource to
provide the reseller parent Cloud Billing account ID for transactions
associated with resold Cloud Billing accounts. For transactions on
direct Cloud Billing accounts, no value is returned for the reseller
parent Cloud Billing account id. For details, see the
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/marketplace/docs/partners/commerce-procurement-api/reference/rest/v1/providers.accounts/get">Cloud Commerce Procurement API documentation</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Cloud Commerce Procurement API's GET Account resource has been updated to include the reseller parent Cloud Billing account ID for resold accounts. Direct accounts will not return this value.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Cloud Commerce Procurement API Update</title>
  </entry>
</feed>