<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Organization Policy Service</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Organization Policy Service</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:organization-policy-service</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/organization-policy-service/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:organization-policy-service:2025-10-14:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can use custom constraints with Organization Policy to provide more granular control over specific fields for some Datastream resources. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/datastream/docs/custom-constraints">Manage Application Integration resources using custom constraints</a>. This feature is <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">generally available</a> (GA).</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Organization Policy now supports custom constraints for more granular control over specific Datastream resource fields. This generally available feature enhances resource management.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New granular controls for Datastream resources</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:organization-policy-service:2025-10-10:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can use custom constraints with Organization Policy to provide more granular control over specific fields for some Application Integration resources. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/application-integration/docs/custom-constraints">Manage Application Integration resources using custom constraints</a>. This feature is available in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">Preview</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Organization Policy now supports custom constraints for Application Integration, offering finer control over resources. This feature is currently in Preview.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New controls for Application Integration</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:organization-policy-service:2025-10-06:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can use custom constraints with Organization Policy to provide more granular control over specific fields for some Dataform resources. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/dataform/docs/create-custom-constraints">Create custom organization policy constraints</a>. This feature is <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">generally available</a> (GA).</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Organization Policy now supports custom constraints for Dataform resources, offering more granular control over specific fields. This generally available feature enhances resource management.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New granular control for Dataform resources</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:organization-policy-service:2025-10-03:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Select Workload Identity Federation resources let you use custom constraints to define your own restrictions on Google Cloud services. To learn which Workload Identity Federation resources support custom constraints and to view sample use cases, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/iam/docs/workload-identity-federation-custom-constraints">Use custom organization policies for Workload Identity Federation</a>.</p>
<p>This feature is available in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">General Availability</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now use custom constraints to define your own restrictions on Google Cloud services for Workload Identity Federation resources. This feature is in General Availability.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Workload Identity Federation Now Supports Custom Constraints</title>
  </entry>
</feed>