<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Apigee API hub</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Apigee API hub</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/apigee-api-hub/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-09-11:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>API hub navigation update</strong></p>
<p>The <strong>API hub</strong> section is now moved to the top level of the Apigee left navigation menu. This change improves discoverability and access to the API hub features.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The API hub has been relocated to the top level of the Apigee left navigation menu, enhancing user access and discoverability of its features.</summary>
    <title>Changed: API hub now at top level</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-09-11:libraries:1</id>
    <published>2025-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Updated Go client library. For more information, see <a href="https://github.com/googleapis/google-cloud-go/releases/tag/apihub/v0.2.0">apihub: v0.2.0</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Go client library has been updated to version v0.2.0.</summary>
    <title>Libraries: Go client library updated</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-09-08:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enable and disable semantic search</strong></p>
<p>You can now enable and disable semantic search from the <strong>API hub &gt; Settings&gt; Actions</strong> page in the Google Cloud console.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/search-apis#enable-semantic-search">Enable and disable semantic search</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new feature allows users to enable and disable semantic search directly from the API hub settings in the Google Cloud console.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Semantic Search Feature</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-09-08:changed:1</id>
    <published>2025-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Automatic discovery of OpenAPI Spec from Apigee proxy resources</strong></p>
<p>API hub now automatically discovers and ingests valid OpenAPI specifications when they are included in an Apigee API proxy resource. This applies to all new and existing Apigee and Apigee hybrid runtime projects that are attached in API hub.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/auto-register-apigee-proxies#auto-oas-discovery">Auto-discovery of OpenAPI specs from Apigee proxies</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>API hub now automatically discovers and ingests OpenAPI specifications from Apigee API proxy resources for all attached Apigee and Apigee hybrid runtime projects.</summary>
    <title>Changed: OpenAPI Spec Discovery</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-09-08:deprecated:2</id>
    <published>2025-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Deprecation of Vertex AI Extensions in API hub</strong></p>
<p>The Vertex AI Extensions feature is no longer supported in API hub as of <strong>September 8, 2025</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Vertex AI Extensions are no longer supported in API hub starting September 8, 2025.</summary>
    <title>Deprecated: Vertex AI Extensions Deprecation</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-09-01:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>New API versions view</strong></p>
<p>API version information is now available as a separate tab in the <strong>API details</strong> page. You can view your API version details, copy API ID, create new API versions and more using the API versions tab.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/manage-versions">Manage versions</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>API version information is now available as a separate tab in the API details page. You can view your API version details, copy API ID, create new API versions and more using the API versions tab.</summary>
    <title>Changed: New API versions tab</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-08-22:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Deprovision API hub in the UI</strong></p>
<p>You can now deprovision an API hub instance from the <strong>API hub &gt; Settings &gt; Actions</strong> page in the Google Cloud console.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/deprovision">Deprovision Apigee API hub</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Deprovision API hub in the UI</summary>
    <title>Feature: Deprovision API hub in the UI</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-08-22:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Create and delete custom plugins in the UI</strong></p>
<p>You can now create and delete custom plugins from the <strong>API hub &gt; Settings &gt; Plugins</strong> page in the Google Cloud console.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/create-custom-plugins">Create custom plugins</a> and <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/manage-custom-plugins">Manage custom plugins</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Create and delete custom plugins in the UI</summary>
    <title>Feature: New feature: Custom plugins</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-08-12:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>API observations in API hub (<a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">Preview</a>)</strong></p>
<p>API observations in API hub helps you tackle the challenges of undocumented and unmanaged APIs in your API infrastructure. It leverages Apigee <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/api-observation/shadow-api-discovery">shadow API discovery</a> and uses automated discovery processes to bring all your APIs, <strong>across Google Cloud projects</strong>, into a unified, managed view.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/api-observation-overview">API observations in API hub</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> Rollouts of this feature will begin today, and may take five or more business days to be completed across all Google Cloud zones. You may not be able to view or use API observations until the rollout is complete. </p>]]></content>
    <summary>Discover and manage undocumented APIs.</summary>
    <title>Feature: API Observations in API Hub</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-07-31:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>New data source support for plugins</strong></p>
<p>API hub now supports importing API metadata through new dedicated plugins for the following data sources:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://docs.apigee.com/api-platform/get-started/apigee-edge-uapim">Apigee Edge Public Cloud</a></li>
<li><a href="https://docs.apigee.com/private-cloud/v4.53.00/privatecloud-uapim-overview">Apigee Edge Private Cloud (OPDK)</a></li>
</ol>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/plugins">Plugins overview</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>New data source support for plugins</summary>
    <title>Feature: New data source support for plugins</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-07-31:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Push-based plugin ingestion</strong></p>
<p>API hub now supports push-based plugin ingestion. This method allows for more real-time synchronization of API metadata. All new <strong>Apigee, Apigee hybrid, Apigee Edge Public Cloud, and Apigee Edge Private Cloud (OPDK)</strong> plugins are created with push-based ingestion by default.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/plugins#plugin-data-ingestion-methods">Plugin data ingestion methods</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> Rollouts of this feature will begin today, and may take five or more business days to be completed across all Google Cloud zones. You may not be able to create push-based plugins until the rollout is complete.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Real-time synchronization of API metadata with push-based plugin ingestion.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Push-based plugin ingestion</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-07-31:feature:2</id>
    <published>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Create custom plugins [API only]</strong></p>
<p>You can now use the <code>Create Plugin</code> API to create custom plugins in API hub. Custom plugins are created manually to connect API hub to a specific API data source.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/create-custom-plugins">Create custom plugins</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Create custom plugins using the new API Hub feature.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Custom Plugins Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-07-31:issue:3</id>
    <published>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Default Apigee plugin instance not auto-created during runtime attachment</strong></p>
<p><strong>Issue:</strong> When provisioning API hub as part of Apigee provisioning, the default <code>Apigee X and hybrid</code> plugin instance is not automatically created. This prevents API proxies from being auto-registered.</p>
<p><strong>Workaround:</strong> You can manually attach an Apigee runtime instance and import the Apigee assets. See <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/auto-register-apigee-proxies#attach-a-runtime-project">Attach a runtime project</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Default Apigee plugin instance not auto-created</summary>
    <title>Issue: Issue with Apigee plugin instance creation</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-07-31:changed:4</id>
    <published>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Delete plugin instance changes</strong></p>
<p>API hub no longer retains any ingested metadata from a plugin after its deletion. Deleting a plugin instance also permanently deletes all the associated API data from API hub.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/manage-plugin-instances#delete-plugin-instance">Delete a plugin instance</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Plugin instances and their data are permanently deleted from API hub upon removal.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Plugin Instance Deletion</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-07-31:changed:5</id>
    <published>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Provisioning changes and Apigee API proxy registration</strong></p>
<p>API hub changed how it registers API proxies from Apigee and how it creates default plugin instances during provisioning.</p>
<p>API hub now automatically creates a default <code>Apigee X and hybrid</code> plugin instance and auto-registers API proxies only when you provision it as part of Apigee provisioning.</p>
<p>If you provision API hub directly from the API hub UI, API hub does not automatically create a default plugin instance, nor does it auto-register proxies.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/auto-register-apigee-proxies#project-associations-and-plugins">Project attachments and plugins</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>API hub has updated its process for registering Apigee API proxies and creating default plugin instances during provisioning. Proxies are now auto-registered and a default plugin instance is created only when API hub is provisioned as part of Apigee provisioning. Direct provisioning via the API hub UI will not include these automatic actions.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Provisioning and Registration Updates</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-07-31:changed:6</id>
    <published>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>New tutorial: Enrich API data in API hub</strong></p>
<p>A new tutorial is available for enriching API data in Apigee API hub.</p>
<p>It shows you how to use API hub's custom curation features to automatically fetch OpenAPI specifications from a Cloud Storage bucket and associate them with their corresponding Apigee API proxies. The custom curation logic is defined using an integration in Application Integration.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/tutorials/enrich-api-data">Enrich API data with custom curation in API hub</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>New tutorial on enriching API data in API hub using custom curation and Application Integration.</summary>
    <title>Changed: API Hub Data Enrichment Tutorial</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-07-31:deprecated:7</id>
    <published>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Deprecation of pull-based ingestion for Apigee plugins</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/plugins#plugin-data-ingestion-methods">Pull-based ingestion</a> is no longer supported for <code>Apigee and Apigee hybrid</code> plugins as of <strong>July 31, 2025</strong>. For existing projects that have pull-based Apigee X and hybrid plugins configured, these plugins will continue to function and will be automatically migrated to the push-based type starting <strong>August 2025</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Pull-based ingestion for Apigee plugins is deprecated starting July 31, 2025. Existing plugins will be migrated to push-based by August 2025.</summary>
    <title>Deprecated: Apigee Plugins: Pull-based Ingestion Deprecated</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-07-31:deprecated:8</id>
    <published>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Deprecation of Apigee proxy deployment attributes</strong></p>
<p>As of <strong>July 31st, 2025</strong>, the <code>Apigee X and Hybrid Environment</code> and <code>Apigee X and Hybrid Organization</code> attributes will no longer be added to new Apigee proxy deployments. This change specifically applies when you import deployments into API hub by attaching a runtime project.</p>
<p>If your existing projects use these attributes in filtered search queries, we recommend updating them. To ensure your searches continue to work, use the <code>Source project</code> and <code>Source environment</code> fields as alternatives.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Apigee proxy deployment attributes are deprecated starting July 31st, 2025. Update existing filtered searches to use 'Source project' and 'Source environment' instead.</summary>
    <title>Deprecated: Apigee Deployment Attributes Deprecation</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-07-22:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>API hub provisioning now enables Apigee API</strong></p>
<p>When you provision API hub, it now enables the Apigee API (<code>apigee.googleapis.com</code>) in your Google Cloud project. If Apigee isn't already provisioned, an Apigee organization is also automatically created in your project as part of the provisioning process.</p>
<p>API hub remains a free service. Enabling the Apigee API has no additional pricing or billing implications for your project.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/provision">Provision API hub in the Cloud console</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>API hub provisioning now enables the Apigee API.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Apigee API Enabled with API Hub Provisioning</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-07-22:changed:1</id>
    <published>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>API hub deprovisioning changes</strong></p>
<p>Deprovisioning an API hub instance now also deletes any associated Apigee organizations from your Google Cloud project, provided those Apigee organizations have no Apigee instances.</p>
<p>If you deprovision an API hub instance, you can reprovision it later, but you'll need to wait 7 days before you can do so.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/deprovision">Deprovision Apigee API hub</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>API hub deprovisioning now deletes associated Apigee organizations if they have no instances. Reprovisioning is possible after a 7-day wait.</summary>
    <title>Changed: API Hub Deprovisioning Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-07-22:changed:2</id>
    <published>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>VPC Service Controls (VPC-SC) is GA</strong></p>
<p>VPC Service Controls in API hub is now <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">GA</a>.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/vpc-service-control">VPC Service Controls for API hub</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>VPC Service Controls for API hub is now generally available.</summary>
    <title>Changed: VPC-SC for API hub now GA</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-07-18:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Apigee and hybrid plugin instance management</strong></p>
<p>You can now create and delete plugin instances for Apigee and Apigee Hybrid while associating the respective Apigee runtime projects to API hub.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/auto-register-apigee-proxies">Auto-register Apigee proxies</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now create and delete plugin instances for Apigee and Apigee Hybrid, associating them with API hub and relevant Apigee runtime projects. This feature simplifies the management of plugin instances and their integration with API hub.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Manage Apigee and hybrid plugin instances</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-07-18:breaking:1</id>
    <published>2025-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Apigee and Apigee hybrid plugin creation now requires source project ID</strong></p>
<p>When creating new instances of the <strong>Apigee X and hybrid</strong> plugin, you must now provide a source project ID. This source project ID is the Google Cloud project from which the plugin will import data.</p>
<p>This is a breaking change and will affect any existing API calls that create these plugins without explicitly providing this ID.</p>
<p><strong>Action Required:</strong> Update your API calls to include the appropriate source project ID when creating new Apigee X and hybrid plugins. Failing to do so will result in creation errors.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You must now provide a source project ID when creating new Apigee X and hybrid plugin instances. This change affects existing API calls that do not explicitly provide this ID. Please update your API calls to include the source project ID to avoid creation errors.</summary>
    <title>Breaking: Apigee plugin creation requires source project ID</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-07-18:changed:2</id>
    <published>2025-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Edit plugin instances changes</strong></p>
<p>You can now change or modify the name and curation logic of your plugin instance.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/manage-plugin-instances#edit-plugin-instance">Edit a plugin instance</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now modify the name and curation logic of your plugin instances. For more details, see the documentation on editing a plugin instance.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Edit plugin instances</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-07-18:changed:3</id>
    <published>2025-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Resource URI format for Apigee deployments</strong></p>
<p>To ensure optimal functionality and consistency while creating or updating <strong>Apigee</strong> deployments, we now recommend that the <strong>Resource URI</strong> conforms to the following format:
<code>organizations/([^/]+)/environments/([^/]+)/apis/([^/]+)$</code></p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/deployments-intro">Introduction to deployments</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Resource URI format for Apigee deployments has been updated to organizations/([^/]+)/environments/([^/]+)/apis/([^/]+)$ to ensure optimal functionality and consistency.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Apigee Deployment URI Format Changed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-06-03:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On June 3, 2025, we released an updated version of Apigee.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The new version of Apigee was released on June 3, 2025.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Updated Apigee Version Released</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-api-hub:2025-06-03:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Apigee API hub is enabled for new Apigee organizations in supported regions.</strong></p>
<p>With this release, we are enabling <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/what-is-api-hub">Apigee API hub</a> for new Apigee organizations <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/locations#available-apigee-api-analytics-regions">in regions where API hub is supported</a>. All new Apigee organizations, including hybrid organizations, that select an API hub-supported region <em>for their Apigee Analytics region</em> during provisioning will have access to API hub features at no additional cost.</p>
<p>API hub allows you to view, organize, and manage all of the APIs in your Apigee organization in one central location. To learn more, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/what-is-api-hub">What is Apigee API hub?</a></p>
<p>No action on your part is required to provision API hub for your organization, with the following exceptions:</p>
<ul>
<li>If your Apigee organization has Data Residency or VPC Service Controls enabled, you must configure your API hub instance manually to support these services. See <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/vpc-service-control">VPC Service Controls for API hub</a> and <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/locations#drz-api-hub">API hub and data residency</a> for more information.</li>
<li>If your Apigee organization uses Customer-Managed Encryption Keys (CMEK), you must deprovision the Apigee API hub instance provided by default and recreate it to support CMEK. See <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/deprovision">Deprovision Apigee API hub</a> and <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/apihub/provision">Provision API hub in the Cloud console</a> for step-by-step instructions.</li>
</ul>
<p>Contact <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/support/getting-started-with-support">Google Cloud Support</a> for questions or assistance.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Apigee API hub is now available for new Apigee organizations in supported regions. This feature provides a central location to view, organize, and manage all your APIs at no extra cost. Specific configurations may be required for organizations using Data Residency, VPC Service Controls, or Customer-Managed Encryption Keys.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Apigee API hub now available</title>
  </entry>
</feed>