<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Looker</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Looker</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/looker/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-11-12:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/conversational-analytics-overview">Conversational Analytics</a> is now generally available for Looker instances that are on Looker 25.18 or later.</p>
<p>You can now use Conversational Analytics in your Looker instance without having to enable the <strong>Trusted Testers</strong> settings. Enablement of the <strong>Gemini in Looker</strong> setting is still required.</p>
<p>For Looker (Google Cloud core) instances, this launch includes support for Conversational Analytics in instances that are within a VPC perimeter.</p>
<p>Enablement of the <strong>Trusted Tester Features</strong> setting is still required when using the <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/conversational-analytics-looker-code-interpreter">Code Interpreter</a> with Conversational Analytics in Looker.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Conversational Analytics is now generally available for Looker instances on version 25.18 and later. While Gemini in Looker enablement is still required, the Trusted Testers setting is no longer necessary for most users. Support is also extended to Looker (Google Cloud core) instances within a VPC perimeter.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Conversational Analytics Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-11-11:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now schedule a daily, zero-downtime export for Looker (Google Cloud core) instances. For more information, see the <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/looker-core-scheduled-export">Create a scheduled export job for a Looker (Google Cloud core) instance</a> documentation page. This feature is being rolled out and will appear in all instances within a few weeks.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker now supports scheduled daily exports, ensuring zero downtime. This feature is rolling out over the next few weeks.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Scheduled Export for Looker</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-11-05:other:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Looker 25.20</strong> is expected to include the following changes, features, and fixes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Expected Looker (original) deployment start: <strong>Thursday, November 6, 2025</strong></li>
<li>Expected Looker (original) final deployment and download available: <strong>Thursday, November 13, 2025</strong></li>
<li>Expected Looker (Google Cloud core) deployment start: <strong>Thursday, November 6, 2025</strong></li>
<li>Expected Looker (Google Cloud core) final deployment: <strong>Tuesday, November 18, 2025</strong></li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>The Looker 25.20 release is scheduled for November 2025, with deployments for both Looker (original) and Looker (Google Cloud core) beginning on November 6th. The original version will be finalized by November 13th, while the Google Cloud core version will conclude by November 18th.</summary>
    <title>Other: Looker 25.20 Release</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-11-05:breaking:1</id>
    <published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Looker now recognizes results from the <code>YEAR</code> function as a number and not a date in MySQL 8.4. This change replicates the behavior of MySQL 8.0 and earlier.</p>
<p>To undo this change for a MySQL connection, add the following parameter to the Additional JDBC parameters section: <code>yearIsDateType=true</code></p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker now treats YEAR function results as numbers in MySQL 8.4, aligning with earlier versions. To revert this, set `yearIsDateType=true` in your MySQL connection settings.</summary>
    <title>Breaking: Looker now recognizes YEAR function results as numbers in MySQL 8.4</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-11-05:breaking:2</id>
    <published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When you use <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/elite-system-activity">Elite System Activity</a>, the System Activity fields <code>sql_query.sql</code> and <code>sql_text.text</code> are limited to a length of 1.9 MB. Any data beyond the 1.9 MB limit will be truncated. (This release note was updated on November 10, 2025 to specify Elite System Activity.)</p>]]></content>
    <summary>System Activity fields `sql_query.sql` and `sql_text.text` are limited to 1.9 MB when using Elite System Activity. Data exceeding this limit will be truncated.</summary>
    <title>Breaking: System Activity Fields Truncation</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-11-05:feature:3</id>
    <published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/connecting-to-your-db#max_number_of_pdt_builder_connections">Max Number of PDT Builder Connections</a> limit has been increased from 10 to 100.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The maximum number of PDT Builder connections has been increased from 10 to 100.</summary>
    <title>Feature: PDT Builder Connections Limit Increased</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-11-05:feature:4</id>
    <published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Looker 25.20 contains the following accessibility improvements:</p>
<ul>
<li>The character count for the custom message field of a schedule is now accessible to screen readers.</li>
<li>The text for errors on custom filters is now accessible to screen readers.</li>
<li>The list of visualization types in the Visualization section of an Explore is now accessible to screen readers.</li>
<li>The reload button and corresponding "last refreshed" timestamp on a dashboard are now accessible to screen readers.</li>
<li>The timezone selector on an Explore is now accessible to screen readers.</li>
<li>The sort indicators in an Explore are now accessible to screen readers.</li>
<li>The text formatting options in the Series tab of an Explore are now accessible to screen readers.</li>
<li>Contrast is improved for elements that are selected when you set up dashboard filters.</li>
<li>Contrast is improved for fields that are selected when Looker suggests a field name in the table calculations editor.</li>
<li>Contrast is improved for tabs that are selected on the Schedule Delivery dialog.</li>
<li>Contrast is improved for radio buttons that are selected on dialogs such as the download dialog.</li>
<li>Dashboard filter options are no longer incorrectly classified as dialogs.</li>
<li>The drill links in a single value visualization are now classified as buttons and can be accessed using the keyboard.</li>
<li>The destination of an alert is now a required field.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker 25.20 includes several accessibility enhancements, making features like custom messages, error texts, visualization types, dashboard elements, and explore options more accessible to screen readers. Additionally, contrast has been improved in various elements, including dashboard filters, table calculations, and dialog boxes, with several UI elements reclassified for better keyboard navigation and usability.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Accessibility Improvements in Looker 25.20</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-11-05:fixed:5</id>
    <published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where a measure of <code>type: period_over_period</code> could be referenced in the <code>sql</code> parameter for a measure of <code>type: number</code>. Attempting to do so now correctly displays an error in the LookML validator. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The LookML validator now correctly displays an error when a measure of type `period_over_period` is referenced in the `sql` parameter for a measure of type `number`. This resolves a previous issue where such references would not be properly flagged, ensuring the feature now performs as expected.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Period Over Period Measure Error Fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-11-05:fixed:6</id>
    <published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where the <strong>Clear field keep filter</strong> button on an Explore could incorrectly become disabled when a user used the field search bar in the field picker. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Clear field keep filter button on an Explore can now be used as expected after a fix for an issue where it was incorrectly disabled when using the field search bar.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Clear field keep filter button fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-11-05:fixed:7</id>
    <published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where SQL Runner could return a <code>NoMethodError</code> when trying to query a LookML model that doesn't exist in the user's development mode. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The SQL Runner 'NoMethodError' issue has been resolved. It now functions correctly when querying non-existent LookML models in development mode.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: SQL Runner Error Fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-11-05:feature:8</id>
    <published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new Labs feature, Internal Dashboard Theming, lets users apply predefined themes to a Looker dashboard. These themes, which are distinct from the themes that are used for embedded dashboards, can be managed by users with the <code>manage_internal_themes</code> permission.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Users can now apply predefined themes to their Looker dashboards with the new Internal Dashboard Theming feature. This allows for easier customization and a more personalized user experience.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Internal Dashboard Theming</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-11-05:feature:9</id>
    <published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Visual Drilling feature is now out of Labs and generally available on the Admin &gt; General Settings page.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Visual Drilling feature has been released from Labs and is now generally available. You can find this new feature on the Admin &gt; General Settings page.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Visual Drilling Now Generally Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-11-05:fixed:10</id>
    <published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where disabling the Favoriting LookML Dashboards Labs feature prevented users from moving LookML dashboards in folders. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Users can once again move LookML dashboards between folders after an issue with the Favoriting LookML Dashboards Labs feature has been resolved. The feature now functions correctly.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: LookML dashboards can now be moved</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-11-05:feature:11</id>
    <published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Visual Drilling feature is now generally available on the Admin &gt; General Settings page.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The new Visual Drilling feature is now generally available on the Admin &gt; General Settings page. This feature provides enhanced capabilities for data exploration and analysis.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Visual Drilling Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-31:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Looker (Google Cloud core) instances that use Private Service Connect now offer a simplified method for configuring outbound connections to external domains or the Looker Marketplace. For more information, see the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/looker-core-create-psc#configure-outbound">Configure outbound connections</a> documentation.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker instances using Private Service Connect now have an easier way to set up connections to external domains and the Looker Marketplace. This update simplifies the process for users needing to connect Looker to external resources.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Simplified Outbound Connections for Looker</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-23:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Conversational Analytics in Looker</strong></p>
<p>The following features are available in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">Preview</a> for use with <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/conversational-analytics-overview">Conversational Analytics in Looker</a> instances that are running Looker 25.18 or later:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/events">Event and event attribute information</a> is now available in <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/usage-reports-with-system-activity-explores#system_activity_explores">System Activity Explores</a>.</li>
<li>A <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/system-activity-dashboards#conversational_analytics">Conversational Analytics System Activity dashboard</a> is now available to surface usage data for Conversational Analytics features in Looker, including the most popular data agents, the most popular Explores that are used in conversations, and the most active users.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Conversational Analytics in Looker is now available in preview. This feature allows users to access event and event attribute information in System Activity Explores and provides a new dashboard to track usage data for Conversational Analytics features.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Conversational Analytics Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-23:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Looker now supports <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/create-projects#cloning_a_public_git_repository_from_the_new_project_page">cloning a public Git repository using an <code>https://</code> URL</a>. Looker does not support cloning Git repositories using <code>git://</code> URLs.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker now supports cloning public Git repositories from the new project page using an https:// URL.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Git repository cloning support</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-21:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The new <a href="https://status.cloud.google.com/looker">Looker Status Dashboard</a> provides real-time updates about service availability or disruptions for <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/choosing-hosting-option#looker-hosted-pros-cons">Looker-hosted instances</a>. For more information, see the <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/status-dashboard-help">Monitor Looker status</a> documentation page.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new dashboard provides real-time updates on Looker service availability and disruptions.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Looker Status Dashboard</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-10:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Conversational Analytics in Looker</strong></p>
<p>The following features are available in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">Preview</a> for use with <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/studio/conversational-analytics-looker">Conversational Analytics in Looker</a> instances that are running Looker 25.18.9 or later:</p>
<ul>
<li>New model-specific Looker permissions are available to manage and use the <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/studio/conversational-data-agents-looker#before-you-begin">Conversational Analytics data agents</a> that are created to chat with Looker Explores. You can grant these permissions to users as part of a <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/admin-panel-users-roles#create-custom-roles">custom role</a>, or use one of two new <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/admin-panel-users-roles#default_roles">default roles</a>, <strong>Conversational Analytics Agent Manager</strong> and <strong>Conversational Analytics User</strong>, to manage and use agents, respectively.</li>
<li>You can now select up to five Looker Explores as data sources for a data agent in Looker.</li>
<li>Users with the <code>admin_agents</code> permission can now <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/studio/conversational-data-agents-looker#share-data-agents">share data agents</a> to let other users chat with your agent and its Explores. Starting in Looker 25.18.10, users with either the <code>save_agents</code> or the <code>admin_agents</code> permission can share data agents with other users.</li>
</ul>
<p>(This release note was updated on October 10, 2025 to correct the Looker version for this release. This release note was updated on October 23, 2025 to correct the Looker version for data agent sharing permissions.)</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Introducing new features for Conversational Analytics in Looker, now in Preview. This update includes enhanced model-specific permissions for data agents, allowing up to five Looker Explores as data sources. Additionally, data agents can now be shared, enabling collaboration and broader access to insights.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Conversational Analytics in Looker</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Looker 25.18</strong> is expected to include the following changes, features, and fixes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Expected Looker (original) deployment start: <strong>Tuesday, October 7, 2025</strong></li>
<li>Expected Looker (original) final deployment and download available: <strong>Thursday, October 16, 2025</strong></li>
<li>Expected Looker (Google Cloud core) deployment start: <strong>Tuesday, October 7, 2025</strong></li>
<li>Expected Looker (Google Cloud core) final deployment: <strong>Monday, October 20, 2025</strong></li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>The Looker 25.18 release is scheduled for October 2025, with deployments for both Looker (original) and Looker (Google Cloud core) beginning on October 7th.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Looker 25.18 Release</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now set the Auto Resize Value setting on single value visualizations. This setting has no effect if the Smart Single Value Text Size setting is enabled on the Admin &gt; General Settings page.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Users can now configure the Auto Resize Value setting for individual single value visualizations.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Auto Resize Value for Single Value Visualizations</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:feature:2</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Athena JDBC driver version has been upgraded from 2.1.5 to 2.2.2. The Athena JDBC driver is used for connections to <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/db-config-amazon-athena">Amazon Athena</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Athena JDBC driver has been upgraded to version 2.2.2.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Athena JDBC Driver Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:changed:3</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Conversational Analytics users with the <code>save_agents</code> permission can now <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/studio/conversational-data-agents-looker">share data agents</a>, which lets other users chat with the data agent and its Explores. (This release note was added on October 9, 2025.)</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Users with the necessary permissions can now share data agents, enabling others to interact with the agent and its associated Explores.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Data agents can now be shared</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:fixed:4</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Looker 25.18 contains the following accessibility improvements:</p>
<ul>
<li>You can navigate drill menus by using a keyboard.</li>
<li>When you select a button toggle with a keyboard, the focus ring uses more contrasting colors.</li>
<li>You can switch button toggles on or off by using the Enter key.</li>
<li>When you use a keyboard to select a Look, dashboard, or folder that's inside a folder, a focus ring will appear around the selected item.</li>
<li>You can now use a keyboard to edit boards.</li>
<li>You can now use the keyboard to access LookML field definitions in the field picker.</li>
<li>The Alerts dialog is now compatible with screen readers.</li>
<li>The Series tab of the visualization editor is now compatible with screen readers.</li>
<li>Tile notes are now added to ARIA descriptions.</li>
<li>Actions for pivot columns are now accessible with a keyboard.</li>
<li>The color contrast has been improved on large text boxes such as the custom filter editor.</li>
<li>The options in the visualization settings panel now have names that can be read by screen readers.</li>
<li>The state of expanded dialogs on the Explore page, such as the field picker and visualization settings panel, can now be read by screen readers.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker 25.18 includes several keyboard navigation and screen reader compatibility enhancements, making the platform more accessible.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Looker 25.18: Accessibility Improvements</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:fixed:5</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where, when dashboard filters were updated, column widths could resize on table visualizations that included pivoted values. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Pivoted values in table visualizations no longer cause column widths to resize unexpectedly when dashboard filters are updated. This issue has been resolved, and the feature now functions as intended.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Table visualizations with pivoted values now display column widths correctly after dashboard filter updates.</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:fixed:6</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where non-string values that were entered in the expression element of the <code>dynamic_fields</code> section of a LookML dashboard could cause the LookML validator to crash. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Non-string values in dynamic fields no longer cause validator crashes.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: LookML Validator Fix</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:fixed:7</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where subtotal values could display incorrect values after a filter was added or updated. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Subtotal values may have previously displayed incorrectly after filters were applied. This has now been fixed and the feature is working as expected.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Subtotal values now display correctly</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:fixed:8</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where, when dashboard filters were updated, table visualizations could get incorrectly cropped to exclude the Total row and scroll bar. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Table visualizations in dashboards will no longer be incorrectly cropped when filters are updated. The Total row and scroll bar will now display as expected.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Dashboard table visualizations now display correctly</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:fixed:9</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where the Collapse Subtotal toggle wasn't collapsing subtotals on table visualizations. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Collapse Subtotal toggle functionality has been fixed and now correctly collapses subtotals in table visualizations.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Collapse Subtotal Toggle Fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:fixed:10</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where the maximum column limit warning could obscure the contents of a visualization. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The maximum column limit warning no longer obscures visualizations. This issue is now resolved.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Visualization column limit warning fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:fixed:11</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where users couldn't sort tables that included pivoted values. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Users can now sort tables with pivoted values as expected. This resolves a previous issue that prevented this functionality.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Table sorting with pivoted values fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:fixed:12</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>LookML dashboards that aren't deployed to production can no longer be moved into folders other than the LookML Dashboards folder.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Fixed an issue where LookML dashboards not deployed to production could be moved to folders other than the LookML Dashboards folder.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: LookML Dashboards Deployment</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:fixed:13</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>LookML project parse errors now include the LookML file path as well as the line number of the error.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>LookML project parse errors now include the LookML file path and line number.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: LookML Parse Errors Improved</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:fixed:14</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where Databricks connections that used OAuth could not be saved if the password field was blank. You can now use OAuth without entering a password on the connections page.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Fixed an issue where Databricks connections using OAuth could not be saved if the password field was blank. Users can now successfully configure these connections without needing to enter a password.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Databricks connections with OAuth can now be saved without a password</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:fixed:15</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where users were sometimes unable to add line breaks to table calculations. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Users can now add line breaks to table calculations without issues. This feature is working as expected.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Line breaks in table calculations fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:fixed:16</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where certain countries would not be displayed when a custom TopoJSON file was used. The following country names are now supported:</p>
<ul>
<li>Czechia for Czech Republic</li>
<li>Eswatini for Swaziland</li>
<li>Brunei Darussalam for Brunei</li>
<li>North Macedonia for Macedonia</li>
<li>Timor-Leste for East Timor</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Fixed an issue where some countries weren't displayed with custom TopoJSON files. Supported country names now include Czechia, Eswatini, Brunei Darussalam, North Macedonia, and Timor-Leste.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Country display issue fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:feature:17</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Prerender iframes for custom visualizations feature is now generally available on the Admin &gt; Content Guardrails page.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Prerender iframes for custom visualizations feature is now generally available.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Prerender iframes for custom visualizations</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:feature:18</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Smart single value text size feature is now generally available on the Admin &gt; General Settings page.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Smart single value text size feature is now available on the Admin &gt; General Settings page.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Smart single value text size</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:feature:19</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The API endpoint <code>search_lookml_dashboards</code> is now generally available. This endpoint is similar to the <code>search_dashboards</code> endpoint except that it searches LookML dashboards instead of user-defined dashboards.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The search_lookml_dashboards API endpoint is now generally available. It allows you to search specifically for LookML dashboards, distinguishing them from user-defined ones.</summary>
    <title>Feature: LookML Dashboards Search API Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:feature:20</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Data History Playback feature is now generally available on the Admin &gt; Settings page.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Data History Playback feature has been launched and is now accessible on the Admin &gt; Settings page. This feature allows users to review past data changes and activity.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Data History Playback Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:feature:21</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Reduce Filter Queries feature is now generally available on the Admin &gt; Settings page.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Reduce Filter Queries feature is now available on the Admin &gt; Settings page.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Reduce Filter Queries</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:breaking:22</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Looker admins can no longer create or edit individual users' API keys. Instead, from the Admin &gt; Users page, admins can enable users to manage their own API keys. Once a user has API key management enabled, they can create, view, edit, and delete their API keys from their Looker account page. <strong>Note:</strong> This item was changed on October 9, 2025 to specify that it supports Looker (Google Cloud core) only, and it was changed again on October 22, 2025 to indicate that it's a breaking change.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker admins can no longer manage individual users' API keys. Users can now manage their own API keys from their account page after admins enable this feature.</summary>
    <title>Breaking: API key management changes for Looker admins</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:feature:23</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Prerender iframes for custom visualizations feature is now out of Labs and generally available on the Admin &gt; Content Guardrails page.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Prerender iframes for custom visualizations are now generally available.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Prerender iframes for custom visualizations</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:feature:24</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Smart single value text size feature is now out of Labs and generally available on the Admin &gt; General Settings page.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Smart single value text size feature is no longer in Labs and is now generally available. You can find this feature on the Admin &gt; General Settings page.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Smart single value text size feature is now generally available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:feature:25</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The API endpoint <code>search_lookml_dashboards</code> is now out of Labs and generally available. This endpoint is similar to the <code>search_dashboards</code> endpoint except that it searches LookML dashboards instead of user-defined dashboards.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The search_lookml_dashboards API endpoint is now generally available. This feature allows you to search LookML dashboards.</summary>
    <title>Feature: LookML Dashboards Search API Now Generally Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:feature:26</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Data History Playback Labs feature is is now out of Labs and generally available on the Admin &gt; Settings page.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Data History Playback feature has been released from Labs and is now generally available. You can find it on the Admin &gt; Settings page.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Data History Playback Now Generally Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-06:feature:27</id>
    <published>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Reduce Filter Queries Labs feature is now is now out of Labs and generally available on the Admin &gt; Settings page.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Reduce Filter Queries feature has been released from Labs and is now generally available on the Admin &gt; Settings page.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Reduce Filter Queries Now Generally Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-02:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <code>sql_preamble</code> parameter now <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/reference/param-explore-sql-preamble#using_liquid_in_sql_preamble">supports Liquid statements</a>. This update is supported on Looker 25.12 and later versions.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The sql_preamble parameter now supports Liquid statements on Looker 25.12 and later versions.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Liquid statements support in sql_preamble</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-30:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following features are coming soon for use with Conversational Analytics:</p>
<ul>
<li>New model-specific Looker permissions are available to <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/admin-panel-users-roles#gemini_ca_agent_manager">manage</a> and <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/admin-panel-users-roles#gemini_ca_agent_user">use</a> the <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/studio/conversational-data-agents-looker">Conversational Analytics data agents</a> that are created to chat with Looker Explores. You can grant these to users as part of a custom role, or use one of two new default roles, <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/admin-panel-users-roles#conversational_analytics_agent_manager">Conversational Analytics Agent Manager</a> and <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/admin-panel-users-roles#conversational_analytics_user">Conversational Analytics User</a>, to manage and use agents, respectively.</li>
<li>You can now select up to five Looker Explores as data sources for a data agent.</li>
<li>You can now <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/studio/conversational-data-agents-looker#share-data-agents">share data agents</a> to let other users chat with your agent and its Explores.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> This release note was published prematurely. It was amended on October 8, 2025 to reflect that these features are coming soon and amended on October 14, 2025 to indicate that the features <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/looker/docs/release-notes#October_10_2025">have been launched</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>New model-specific Looker permissions are available to manage and use Conversational Analytics data agents. You can now select up to five Looker Explores as data sources for a data agent and share data agents with other users.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New features for Conversational Analytics</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-23:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/connect-ide-to-looker-using-mcp-toolbox">connect to your Looker instance with the Gemini CLI</a> using a dedicated <a href="https://github.com/gemini-cli-extensions/looker">Gemini extension</a>. The Gemini extension can run queries, create Looks and dashboards, and retrieve elements of your LookML models.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Connect to your Looker instance using the Gemini CLI with a new extension. Run queries, create Looks and dashboards, and retrieve LookML model elements directly from your IDE.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Gemini CLI now connects to Looker</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Looker 25.16</strong> is expected to include the following changes, features, and fixes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Expected Looker (original) deployment start: <strong>Monday, September 15, 2025</strong></li>
<li>Expected Looker (original) final deployment and download available: <strong>Thursday, September 25, 2025</strong></li>
<li>Expected Looker (Google Cloud core) deployment start: <strong>Monday, September 15, 2025</strong></li>
<li>Expected Looker (Google Cloud core) final deployment: <strong>Monday, September 29, 2025</strong></li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>The Looker 25.16 release is scheduled for September 2025, with deployments for both Looker (original) and Looker (Google Cloud core) beginning on September 15th. Final deployments and downloads will be available through September 29th.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Looker 25.16 Release</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:breaking:1</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Looker no longer supports connections to Firebolt.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker has ended support for Firebolt connections.</summary>
    <title>Breaking: Looker and Firebolt</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:feature:2</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Suggest queries now respect the concurrency limit in the connection configuration.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Suggest queries now respect the concurrency limit in the connection configuration.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Suggest queries now respect the concurrency limit</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:feature:3</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Spanner JDBC Driver has been updated to version 2.32.1. This driver is used for connections to <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/db-config-cloud-spanner">Google Spanner</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Spanner JDBC Driver has been updated to version 2.32.1.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Spanner JDBC Driver Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:feature:4</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/excel-connector">Looker-Excel Connector</a> is now generally available. When your Looker admin enables the Looker-Excel Connector on the BI Connections admin page, Looker Explores display the Open in Excel option in the Explore gear menu. This option downloads the Explore results to a Windows PC in a format that Microsoft Excel recognizes.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Looker-Excel Connector is now generally available. Admins can enable this feature in Looker to allow users to download Explore results directly to Microsoft Excel.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Looker-Excel Connector Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:feature:5</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/powerbi-connector">LookerPower BI Connector</a> is now supported for <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/customer-hosted-installation-steps">customer-hosted Looker instances</a> and for Looker (Google Cloud core) instances that use <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/looker-core-networking-options#private_ip_connections">private connections</a>. <strong>Note:</strong> This item was added on September 19, 2025.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The LookerPower BI Connector is now supported for customer-hosted Looker instances and for Looker (Google Cloud core) instances utilizing private connections. This expansion enhances connectivity options for users with specific deployment needs.</summary>
    <title>Feature: LookerPower BI Connector Now Available for Customer-Hosted and Private Connection Instances</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:feature:6</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/tableau-connector">LookerTableau BI Connector</a> is now supported for <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/customer-hosted-installation-steps">customer-hosted Looker instances</a> and for Looker (Google Cloud core) instances that use <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/looker-core-networking-options#private_ip_connections">private connections</a>. <strong>Note:</strong> This item was added on September 19, 2025.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The LookerTableau BI Connector now supports customer-hosted Looker instances and Looker (Google Cloud core) instances utilizing private connections. This expansion enhances flexibility for various deployment scenarios.</summary>
    <title>Feature: LookerTableau BI Connector Now Supported for Customer-Hosted and Private Instances</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:7</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Looker 25.16 contains the following accessibility improvements:</p>
<ul>
<li>Improved keyboard navigation for embed folders.</li>
<li>Added ARIA labels to filter drop-down menu items.</li>
<li>Added ARIA labels to schedule options.</li>
<li>Added focus rings to navigation links.</li>
<li>Improved VoiceOver support for filter navigation.</li>
<li>Added the ability for users to close modals by using the Esc key. Users will be prevented from closing modals this way if there are unsaved changes in the modal.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker 25.16 includes several accessibility enhancements, such as improved keyboard navigation, ARIA labels for filters and schedules, better VoiceOver support, and the ability to close modals with the Esc key.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Accessibility Improvements in Looker 25.16</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:8</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When you upload a p12 file to a database connection, Looker now checks that it is a valid file before completing the upload.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker now validates p12 files during database connection uploads to ensure they are valid before completing the process.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: P12 validation improved</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:9</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where adding multiple filters to the same field could cause filter conditions to overwrite each other. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Multiple filters on the same field no longer overwrite each other.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed filter bug</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:10</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where changing the size of a visualization could cause the visualization to flicker. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The visualization flickering issue that occurred when resizing has been resolved. The feature now functions correctly.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Visualization flickering issue fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:11</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where users could enter color codes that were longer than six characters when they were updating custom color collections. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Users can no longer enter color codes longer than six characters when updating custom color collections. This resolves a previous issue and ensures the feature functions correctly.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed color code length issue</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:12</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where Explore drill links would not open correctly if cookieless embed was enabled. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Explore drill links now open correctly with cookieless embed enabled.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Explore drill links fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:13</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where generating a view inside a folder could fail if the folder's name contained special characters. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Generating a view inside a folder with special characters in its name will now work as expected.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: View generation with special characters fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:14</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where generating an embed URL from a LookML dashboard could fail with the following error: <code>'models' param cannot be converted to an array of String</code>. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The issue where generating an embed URL from a LookML dashboard could fail with an error has been resolved. The feature now works correctly.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Embed URL generation fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:15</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where loading JavaScript files for custom visualizations could take more than one second. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The loading time for JavaScript files used in custom visualizations has been improved and now performs as expected.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: JavaScript loading time improved</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:16</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where non-admin users were unable to select a project when they added a connection. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Non-admin users can now select projects when adding connections. This issue is resolved and the feature functions correctly.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Project Selection Issue Fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:17</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where scheduled deliveries could fail with the following error message: <code>Async delivery failed due to errors Internal server error. [Google Cloud Storage] undefined</code>. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The issue causing scheduled deliveries to fail with a Google Cloud Storage error has been resolved. Deliveries will now proceed as expected.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Scheduled deliveries issue fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:18</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where subtotal rows could fail to appear in downloaded result sets. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>An issue where subtotal rows failed to appear in downloaded result sets has been resolved. The feature now functions correctly.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Subtotal Rows Issue Fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:19</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where the OAuth client secret could not be updated in the Connections page. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The issue preventing updates to the OAuth client secret on the Connections page has been resolved. This functionality now operates correctly.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: OAuth Client Secret Update Fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:20</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where total references and row total references in table calculations could return the following error if there was no data: <code>Field either does not exist in the current query or is a measure.</code> This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>An issue causing errors in table calculations with no data has been resolved. Total references and row total references now function correctly.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: Table Calculation Error</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:21</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where updating a Spanner connection could fail to save changes. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>An issue where updating a Spanner connection could fail to save changes has been resolved. The feature now performs as expected.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Spanner connection update issue fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:22</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where users with only the <code>embed_browse_spaces</code> permission could be incorrectly classified as Standard users instead of Viewer users. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Users with embed_browse_spaces permission are now correctly classified as Viewer users.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Permissions issue fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:23</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where using the <code>matches_filter</code> function in custom filters could return an error. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The matches_filter function in custom filters previously returned an error, but this has now been resolved and the feature functions as expected.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: matches_filter function fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:24</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where visualizations could render twice when they were first loaded on an Explore or a dashboard. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>An issue where visualizations rendered twice on initial load has been fixed. The feature now functions as expected.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Visualizations rendering correctly</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:25</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Athena JDBC driver version has been downgraded from 2.2.1 to 2.1.5 to fix an issue with result set streaming. This feature now performs as expected. The Athena JDBC driver is used for connections to <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/db-config-amazon-athena">Amazon Athena</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Athena JDBC driver has been downgraded to version 2.1.5, resolving a result set streaming issue. The feature now works correctly.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Athena JDBC driver issue fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:26</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dashboards that are not configured to run on load no longer show past query results when you revisit the dashboard in the same browser session. You must click the Load button to run the queries again.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Dashboards not set to run on load will not display old results when revisited. Users must click 'Load' to refresh queries.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Dashboards no longer show stale data</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:27</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where the Collapse subtotal toggle on table visualizations was unresponsive. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The collapse subtotal toggle on table visualizations was unresponsive and has now been fixed. The feature is working as expected.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Collapse Subtotal Toggle Fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:28</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where updating a customer-hosted instance could fail with the following error message: <code>Data import is in progress and some features will not be available</code>. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The issue where updating a customer-hosted instance failed with the 'Data import is in progress' error has been resolved. The feature now functions correctly.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Update issue fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:29</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where SQL Runner could fail to return new results after running a second query. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The SQL Runner now correctly displays new results after executing a second query, resolving a previous issue.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: SQL Runner performance improved</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:feature:30</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new Labs feature, Favoriting LookML Dashboards, enables LookML dashboards to be <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/finding-content#navigating_to_content_in_folders">marked as favorites</a> causing the LookML dashboards to appear on the Looker Favorites tab.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now favorite LookML dashboards so they appear on the Looker Favorites tab.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Favoriting LookML Dashboards</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:feature:31</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Full Screen Visualizations Labs feature is now generally available. You can turn it on and off on the Admin - General page.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Full Screen Visualizations Labs feature has been released and is now generally available. You can enable or disable this feature through the Admin - General settings page.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Full Screen Visualizations Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:32</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where updating the Host URL in the Admin - Settings page could fail to be saved. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The issue where updating the Host URL in the Admin - Settings page failed to save has been resolved. This feature now works correctly.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Host URL update issue fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:fixed:33</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where visualization templates could be edited by API users without the need for the <code>explore</code> permission.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Users with API access could edit visualization templates without the required explore permission. This has now been fixed.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Visualization templates editable without explore permission</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:feature:34</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Looker (Google Cloud core) 90-day trial instances are now available.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker instances with a 90-day trial are now available.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Looker 90-day trial instances</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-09-10:feature:35</id>
    <published>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Full Screen Visualizations feature is now generally available. You can turn it on and off on the Admin - General page.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The new Full Screen Visualizations feature is now generally available. You can enable or disable this feature on the Admin - General page.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Full Screen Visualizations Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-10-08:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Conversational Analytics in Looker</strong></p>
<p>The following features are now available in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">Preview</a> for use with <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/studio/conversational-analytics-looker">Conversational Analytics in Looker</a> instances that are running Looker 25.18 or later:</p>
<ul>
<li>New model-specific Looker permissions are available to manage and use the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/studio/conversational-data-agents-looker#before-you-begin">Conversational Analytics data agents</a> that are created to chat with Looker Explores. You can grant these permissions to users as part of a <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/admin-panel-users-roles#create-custom-roles">custom role</a>, or use one of two new <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/admin-panel-users-roles#default_roles">default roles</a>, <strong>Conversational Analytics Agent Manager</strong> and <strong>Conversational Analytics User</strong>, to manage and use agents, respectively.</li>
<li>You can now select up to five Looker Explores as data sources for a data agent in Looker.</li>
<li>You can now <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/studio/conversational-data-agents-looker#share-data-agents">share data agents</a> to let other users chat with your agent and its Explores.</li>
</ul>
<p>(This release note was updated on October 9, 2025 to correct the Looker version for this release.)</p>]]></content>
    <summary>New features are available for Conversational Analytics in Looker, including model-specific permissions for data agents, the ability to select up to five Looker Explores as data sources for a data agent, and the option to share data agents with other users.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New features for Conversational Analytics in Looker</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Looker 25.14</strong> is expected to include the following changes, features, and fixes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Expected Looker (original) deployment start: <strong>Monday, August 18, 2025</strong></li>
<li>Expected Looker (original) final deployment and download available: <strong>Thursday, August 28, 2025</strong></li>
<li>Expected Looker (Google Cloud core) deployment start: <strong>Monday, August 18, 2025</strong></li>
<li>Expected Looker (Google Cloud core) final deployment: <strong>Monday, September 1, 2025</strong></li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker 25.14 Release</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Looker 25.14 Release</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For projects that are enabled for the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/reference/param-manifest-new-lookml-runtime">New LookML Runtime</a>, the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/reference/param-field"><code>synonyms</code> parameter</a> is now supported. The <code>synonyms</code> parameter lets LookML developers provide additional context about their data that will help <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/studio/conversational-analytics">Conversational Analytics</a> and other features to answer questions more accurately.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Synonyms parameter now supported for LookML projects enabled for the New LookML Runtime.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New LookML Runtime Synonyms Support</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:feature:2</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/usage-reports-with-system-activity-explores#api_usage_hourly">API Usage Hourly System Activity Explore</a> is now available. This Explore provides a detailed, hourly summary of the volume and performance of API calls that are made to your Looker instance.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The API Usage Hourly System Activity Explore is now available.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Looker API Usage Report</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:feature:3</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Denodo 9 databases are now supported.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Denodo 9 databases are now supported.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Denodo 9 Support</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:feature:4</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Maria JDBC Driver has been updated to version 3.5.3. This driver is used for connections to <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/db-config-mysql-mariadb-singlestore">MySQL, MySQL 8.0.12+, MariaDB, SingleStore, SingleStore 7+</a>, <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/db-config-amazon-aurora-mysql">Amazon Aurora MySQL</a>, <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/db-config-google-cloud-sql">Google Cloud SQL</a>, and HyperSQL. <strong>NOTE:</strong> This item was updated on September 10, 2025.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Maria JDBC Driver has been updated to version 3.5.3, supporting various database connections.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Maria JDBC Driver Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:feature:5</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Athena driver has been updated to version 2.2.1. This driver is used for connections to <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/db-config-amazon-athena">Amazon Athena</a>. <strong>Note</strong>: This change was made in Looker 25.10. This item was updated on August 18, 2025. <strong>NOTE:</strong> This item was updated on September 10, 2025.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Athena driver has been updated to version 2.2.1. This change was made in Looker 25.10.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Athena driver updated</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:feature:6</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Databricks JDBC driver has been upgraded to version 2.7.3. This driver is used for connections to <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/db-config-databricks">Databricks</a>.
<strong>Note</strong>: This change was made in Looker 25.10. This item was updated on August 18, 2025 and September 10, 2025.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Databricks JDBC driver has been updated to version 2.7.3. This update is relevant for users connecting to Databricks. The change was implemented in Looker version 25.10.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Databricks JDBC Driver Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:feature:7</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new JavaScript event, <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/embedded-javascript-events#dashboardtilemerge"><code>dashboard:tile:merge</code></a>, has been added.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new JavaScript event, dashboard:tile:merge, has been added.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New JavaScript Event</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:feature:8</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Looker now displays a notice to instance admins if the instance license has been revoked. Admins will have 14 days to correct any problems before the instance will be shut down.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Instance license revocation notice.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Looker Instance License Revocation</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:feature:9</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/events">Looker events</a> are now visible in the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/usage-reports-with-system-activity-explores#event">System Activity Events Explore</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>create_project</code></li>
<li><code>delete_project</code></li>
<li><code>update_project</code></li>
<li><code>create_git_deploy_key</code></li>
<li><code>delete_repository_credential</code></li>
<li><code>update_repository_credential</code></li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>New project events are available in the System Activity Events Explore.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Project Events</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:feature:10</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new Customer Engineer Advanced Editor <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/admin-panel-users-roles#customer_engineer_advanced_editor">default role</a> has been added and can be used to <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/admin-panel-general-support-access">grant support access</a> to Google Cloud customer engineers.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new role, Customer Engineer Advanced Editor, is available to grant support access to Google Cloud customer engineers.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Role Added</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:feature:11</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/usage-reports-with-system-activity-explores#query_concurrency">Query Concurrency System Activity Explore</a> is now available. This Explore can help you identify periods of high load and investigate performance bottlenecks that are related to database connection limits. <strong>Note:</strong> This feature was included in the Looker 25.12 release notes but its launch was delayed.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Identify high load periods and investigate performance bottlenecks related to database connection limits.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Query Concurrency System Activity Explore Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:feature:12</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>New visualizations have been added to the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/system-activity-dashboards#database_performance">Database Performance dashboard</a> and the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/system-activity-dashboards#instance_performance">Instance Performance dashboard</a> in System Activity.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>New visualizations are now available in the System Activity dashboards.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New visualizations in System Activity</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:feature:13</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following updates have been made for <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/period-over-period">Period-over-period (PoP) measures</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>The PoP measure feature is out of Preview and is now generally available. <strong>Note:</strong> This item was added on August 21, 2025.</li>
<li>PoP measures are now supported for MySQL 8.0.12+ connections to Looker. <strong>Note:</strong> This item was added on August 18, 2025.</li>
<li>You can now specify the following types of measures in the PoP measure's <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/period-over-period#based_on"><code>based_on</code></a> parameter: <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/reference/param-measure-types#list"><code>list</code></a>, <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/reference/param-measure-types#median"><code>median</code></a>, <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/reference/param-measure-types#median_distinct"><code>median_distinct</code></a>, <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/reference/param-measure-types#number"><code>number</code></a>, <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/reference/param-measure-types#percentile"><code>percentile</code></a>, <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/reference/param-measure-types#percentile_distinct"><code>percentile_distinct</code></a>. <strong>Note:</strong> This item was added on August 21, 2025.</li>
<li>For queries with PoP measures and time-based filters, in order to calculate data for the PoP measure Looker now automatically retrieves an extra time period of the coarsest time granularity in the query. (Previously, the user was required to adjust the granularity of time-based filters in order to account for the PoP measure calculations.) <strong>Note:</strong> This item was added on August 21, 2025.</li>
<li>For queries with PoP measures, if no time-based dimensions are included in the query from the Explore's field picker, Looker can now infer the time period from time-based dimensions in the Explore's filters. (Previously, for queries with PoP measures, the user was required to specify a time-based dimension from the Explore's field picker.) See <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/period-over-period#explore-requirements">Requirements for Explore queries with PoP measures</a> for more information. <strong>Note:</strong> This item was added on August 21, 2025.</li>
<li>PoP measures are now supported with <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/connected-sheets">Connected Sheets</a>. <strong>Note:</strong> This item was added on August 21, 2025.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Period-over-period measures are now generally available and support MySQL connections and Connected Sheets.</summary>
    <title>Feature: PoP Measures Now Generally Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:fixed:14</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Looker 25.14 contains the following accessibility improvements:</p>
<ul>
<li>ARIA labels have been added to iframes that contain custom visualizations.</li>
<li>ARIA labels have been added to legends on visualizations.</li>
<li>ARIA labels have been added to modals.</li>
<li>ARIA labels have been added to the Looker page header and logo.</li>
<li>ARIA labels have been added to untitled dashboard tiles.</li>
<li>Keyboard focus has been improved on modals.</li>
<li>Text contrast has been increased on banners.</li>
<li>Dashboard filters stay in focus while users are typing.</li>
<li>Users can use the Explore from here link in a drill menu by using the keyboard.</li>
<li>Users can interact with Single Value visualizations by using the keyboard.</li>
<li>PDF rendering progress messages have been updated to better integrate with screen readers.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker 25.14: Accessibility Improvements</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Looker 25.14 release notes</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:fixed:15</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The LookML validation spinner now correctly stops if there is an error with the server's validation process.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>LookML validation spinner stops on server error.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: LookML Validation Fix</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:fixed:16</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where a route that wasn't intended for embedding was allowed to be embedded. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Route embedding fixed.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: Route Embedding</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:fixed:17</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where "Create view from table" would fail if it was initiated from a LookML subfolder. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The "Create view from table" feature now works correctly, even when initiated from a LookML subfolder.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: "Create view from table" issue in LookML subfolders</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:fixed:18</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where color palettes with Japanese labels could not be added or removed. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Japanese labels for color palettes fixed.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: Color Palette Issue</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:fixed:19</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where getting LookML for dashboards wouldn't preserve all query filters even if they overlapped with dashboard-level filters. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>LookML dashboards now preserve all query filters.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: LookML dashboard filters</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:fixed:20</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where <code>include</code> statements for empty folders that used single-slash syntax returned an unrecognized project reference error. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>`include` statements for empty folders with single-slash syntax now work correctly, resolving an unrecognized project reference error.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: Include statements for empty folders</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:fixed:21</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where multiple tooltips could be displayed at once. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Multiple tooltips displayed at once have been fixed.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: Multiple Tooltips Issue</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:fixed:22</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where project names weren't fully sanitized. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Project names are now fully sanitized.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed project name sanitization</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:fixed:23</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where projects that have not been deployed to production wouldn't appear in a user's list of available projects. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Projects not deployed to production now appear in the user's project list.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed project visibility</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:fixed:24</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where removing fields from embedded dashboard tiles could become impossible. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Fix for embedded dashboard tile field removal.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Issue Fix</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:fixed:25</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where resetting a project's git connection and attempting to use a bare repo would fail. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Fixed an issue with bare repo git connections.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Git Connection Fix</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:fixed:26</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where sorting a pivoted column in the drill modal could sort all pivoted columns instead of just the selected one. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Sorting pivoted columns in drill modal now works correctly.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: Sorting Issue in Drill Modal</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:fixed:27</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where special characters such as slashes, ampersands, and question marks were allowed in BigQuery and Spanner connection names. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Special characters are no longer allowed in BigQuery and Spanner connection names.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: Special characters in connection names</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:fixed:28</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where the HTTP error codes for moving and copying dashboards and Looks could return 422 when they should return 404. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>HTTP error codes for moving and copying dashboards and Looks now return 404 as expected, instead of 422.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: HTTP error codes for dashboard and Look operations</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:fixed:29</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where the last accessed time for Looks that were saved to a dashboard as Looks wasn't updated when the dashboard was accessed. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looks that were saved to a dashboard were not updating their last accessed time. This has been fixed.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Look Last Accessed Time Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:fixed:30</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where the MoreVert button would not be disabled when no options were available in the menu. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The MoreVert button is now correctly disabled when no menu options are available.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: MoreVert Button Behavior</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:fixed:31</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where the new dashboard name wasn't preserved when a LookML dashboard was copied to a folder. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Dashboard name preserved after copying LookML dashboard to a folder.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: Dashboard name preservation</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:fixed:32</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where unfavoriting a dashboard or Look on a board would not persist. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Unfavoriting dashboards and Looks on a board now persists.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed unfavoriting issue</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-08-13:feature:33</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Note:</strong> This item was removed on August 27, 2025.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>This feature has been removed effective August 27, 2025.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Feature Announcement</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-25:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/studio/conversational-analytics-code-interpreter">Code Interpreter in Conversational Analytics</a> is available in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">Preview</a> for Looker (original) and Looker (Google Cloud core) instances. The Code Interpreter translates your natural language questions into Python code and executes that code to provide advanced analysis and visualizations. The Code Interpreter is disabled by default.</p>
<ul>
<li>Looker (original) instances must be on Looker 25.8 or later. Looker admins can manage enablement for the Code Interpreter on the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/admin-panel-platform-gil#enable-and-disable-gil-original"><strong>Gemini in Looker</strong> admin page</a> of the Looker (original) instance.</li>
<li>Looker (Google Cloud core) instances must be on Looker 25.10 or later. Looker admins can manage enablement for the Code Interpreter on the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/looker-core-admin-gemini#enable-ci-core"><strong>Gemini in Looker</strong> admin page</a> of the Looker (Google Cloud core) instance.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Introducing the Code Interpreter for advanced analysis and visualizations, now in Preview for Looker.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: New Code Interpreter Feature</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Looker 25.12</strong> is expected to include the following changes, features, and fixes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Expected Looker (original) deployment start: <strong>Monday, July 28, 2025</strong></li>
<li>Expected Looker (original) final deployment and download available: <strong>Thursday, August 7, 2025</strong></li>
<li>Expected Looker (Google Cloud core) deployment start: <strong>Monday, July 28, 2025</strong></li>
<li>Expected Looker (Google Cloud core) final deployment: <strong>Wednesday, July 30, 2025</strong></li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker 25.12 Release</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Looker 25.12 Release</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:breaking:1</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Because of security concerns, text tiles no longer support the <code>form</code> and <code>input</code> Markdown elements.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Text tiles no longer support form and input Markdown elements due to security concerns.</summary>
    <title>Breaking: Breaking News</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:feature:2</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Oracle JDBC driver has been updated to version 19.25.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Oracle JDBC driver updated.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Oracle JDBC Driver Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:feature:3</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For faster response time for queries in BigQuery, Looker will execute BigQuery queries by using <a href="https://cloud.google.com/bigquery/docs/reference/rest/v2/jobs/query#jobcreationmode"><code>jobCreationMode=JOB_CREATION_OPTIONAL</code></a>. If BigQuery can return immediate results, it will run the query without creating a job, so the record in the Looker query history will have a BigQuery query ID instead of a BigQuery job ID. See the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/query-performance-metrics#bigquery_bi_engine_metrics">Understanding query performance metrics</a> documentation page for more information about the BigQuery BI Engine metrics.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker now uses an improved method for running BigQuery queries, leading to faster response times.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Faster BigQuery Queries in Looker</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:feature:4</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/usage-reports-with-system-activity-explores#query_concurrency">Query Concurrency System Activity Explore</a> is now available. This Explore can help you identify periods of high load and investigate performance bottlenecks that are related to database connection limits. <strong>Note:</strong> This feature launch was delayed and is now available in Looker 25.14. This item was updated on August 13, 2025.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Query concurrency is now available to help identify load periods and investigate performance bottlenecks.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Feature: Query Concurrency</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:5</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where certain API calls would fail to time out and would instead run indefinitely. <strong>Note:</strong> This item was added August 18, 2025.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>API calls no longer run indefinitely.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed indefinite API calls</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:6</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Looker 25.12 contains the following accessibility improvements:</p>
<ul>
<li>Improved contrast for exit buttons on dialogs</li>
<li>Improved contrast for checkbox borders</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Accessibility improvements in Looker 25.12</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Looker 25.12 Accessibility Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:7</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where pull requests could display a different user than the pull request's owner. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Pull requests now display the correct owner.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: Pull Request Owner Display Issue</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:8</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where the System Activity Query Metrics Explore was not reliably populating with data. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>System Activity Query Metrics Explore data population issue fixed.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed System Activity Query Metrics Explore</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:9</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where API users could view a list of users on a Looker instance, even if they didn't have the <code>see_users</code> permission. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>API users can now only view users if they have the `see_users` permission.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: API user permissions</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:10</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where the response headers from some API calls were not set by Looker. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker API response headers are now correctly set.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Looker API Header Fix</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:11</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where exploring from a dashboard tile while editing a dashboard could result in a permissions error, even if the user had permission to view the Explore. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Permissions error fixed when exploring from dashboard tile.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: Dashboard tile exploration error</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:12</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where the row limit in an Explore could display a blank field when the row limit was set to 5,000. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Row limit in explore now displays correctly.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: Explore Row Limit Issue</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:13</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where some users were unable to create or edit BigQuery OAuth connections. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Fixed an issue with BigQuery OAuth connections.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: BigQuery OAuth Connection Issue Fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:14</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where SQL Runner would display a blank page if a user changed the visualization type after pivoting on a dimension. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>SQL Runner fixed blank page issue after visualization change.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Bug Fix</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:15</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where some queries to the internal database were unoptimized, affecting instance performance. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Internal database queries optimized.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: Instance performance improved</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:16</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where a visualization template could fail to be displayed in the list of templates if the name contained certain unicode characters. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Visualization template display issue fixed.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: Visualization template issue</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:17</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where invalid query killing statements could cause unnecessarily verbose log outputs. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Invalid query killing statements no longer produce verbose logs.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed verbose logs</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:18</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where API users without the <code>explore</code> permission could access visualization templates. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>API users without explore permission can no longer access visualization templates.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: Visualization template access</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:19</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where Looker could return a 500 error while retrieving dashboard details if the details contained non-UTF-8 characters. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker dashboard error fixed.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Looker error fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:20</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where forecasting didn't work properly on fields that were based on JSON data. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Forecasting on JSON-based fields now works correctly.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Forecasting Fix</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:21</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where Looker didn't properly sanitize slash characters in git references that were used for remote dependencies. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker no longer has issues with git references.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed Git Reference Issue</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:22</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where fields could be sorted differently when a visualization was downloaded or scheduled as a PNG. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Fields are now sorted correctly in downloaded PNGs.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: Visualization Sort Order</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:23</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where the <code>all_connections</code> API call could ignore the <code>fields</code> parameter. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The `all_connections` API call now correctly handles the `fields` parameter.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: API Call Fix</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:24</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where a map visualization would display drill links for fields that were hidden from the visualization. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Map visualization drill links fixed.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: Map visualization drill links</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:25</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where some System Activity tables were missing the <code>element_id</code> field. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>System Activity tables missing element_id field fixed.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: System Activity Tables</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:26</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where subtotals could be incorrectly formatted in PDF downloads when an HTML parameter was defined on the field and the "Expand tables to show all rows" option was enabled. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Subtotals formatting in PDF downloads has been fixed when HTML parameters are used with row expansion enabled.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Formatting Issue Resolved</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:27</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Looker IDE now checks for subparameters in local and remote dependencies and displays a more informative error if the subparameters are missing. Local dependencies must be defined with a project subparameter, while remote dependencies require both a <code>url</code> subparameter and a <code>ref</code> subparameter.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>IDE now checks for subparameters in local and remote dependencies. Local dependencies require a project subparameter, while remote dependencies need both url and ref subparameters for more informative error messages.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: IDE dependency checks improved</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:28</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where editing a merged query in an embedded session would open in a new tab. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Editing a merged query in an embedded session now opens in a new tab as expected.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Bug Fix for Merged Query Editing</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:29</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where Looker could generate duplicate SQL table references if a PDT referenced a table directly as well as through a join. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker no longer generates duplicate SQL table references when a PDT references a table directly as well as through a join.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed duplicate SQL references in Looker</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:30</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where some PDT regeneration events were not tracked in System Activity. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>PDT regeneration events were not tracked in System Activity.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed PDT regeneration tracking</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:31</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When an Explore is saved as a new dashboard, Looker will create advanced filter type dashboard filters, rather than drop-down type dashboard filters, for number type parameters.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker now creates advanced filters for number parameters when saving an Explore as a dashboard.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Looker dashboard filter update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:32</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where SAML authentication could fail for a Looker (Google Cloud core) instance. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>SAML authentication issue fixed.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: SAML authentication fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:33</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where the Looker Marketplace toggle was not being displayed in Looker core instances for users who were granted Admin permissions with an IAM role. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker Marketplace toggle now displayed correctly for IAM admins.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Looker Marketplace Fix</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-07-24:fixed:34</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where installing multiple drivers for the same database type on a customer-hosted instance could cause Looker to display an error. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>An issue with installing multiple drivers for the same database type on a customer-hosted instance has been fixed.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed driver installation issue</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-30:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Fast Dev Mode Transition feature is out of Labs and is now generally available. The Fast Dev Mode Transition feature improves the performance of <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/dev-mode-prod-mode#development_mode">Development Mode</a> on your instance by loading LookML projects in read-only mode until a developer clicks the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/git-command-reference#create-developer-copy">Create Developer Copy</a> button for the project. <strong>Note:</strong> This item was added on July 8, 2025.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Fast Dev Mode Transition is now generally available, improving development mode performance by loading LookML projects in read-only mode until a developer creates a copy.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Fast Dev Mode Transition Now Generally Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-30:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Fast Dev Mode Transition feature is now available for Looker (Google Cloud core). The Fast Dev Mode Transition feature improves the performance of <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/dev-mode-prod-mode#development_mode">Development Mode</a> on your instance by loading LookML projects in read-only mode until a developer clicks the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/git-command-reference#create-developer-copy">Create Developer Copy</a> button for the project. <strong>Note:</strong> This item was added on July 8, 2025.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker's Fast Dev Mode Transition is now available, improving instance performance by loading LookML projects in read-only mode until a developer initiates a copy. This enhancement applies to Looker (Google Cloud core).</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Fast Dev Mode Transition for Looker</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-24:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following feature is generally available for Looker reports:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Looker connector can now connect to a <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/looker-core-networking-options#private_ip_connections">private IP (private services access) only</a> Looker (Google Cloud core) instance or to a <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/looker-core-networking-options#psc">private IP (Private Service Connect)</a> Looker (Google Cloud core) instance <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/looker-core-connect-to-private-ip-lsp-sil">using the Looker instance ID</a>.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>The Looker connector now supports connecting to Looker (Google Cloud core) instances using private IP addresses, including those with Private Service Connect.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Looker connector supports private IP connections</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Looker 25.10</strong> is expected to include the following changes, features, and fixes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Expected Looker (original) deployment start: <strong>Tuesday, June 17, 2025</strong></li>
<li>Expected Looker (original) final deployment and download available: <strong>Thursday, June 26, 2025</strong></li>
<li>Expected Looker (Google Cloud core) deployment start: <strong>Monday, June 16, 2025</strong></li>
<li>Expected Looker (Google Cloud core) final deployment: <strong>Monday, June 30, 2025</strong></li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker 25.10 release is scheduled for June 2025, with deployments for Looker (original) starting June 17th and Looker (Google Cloud core) starting June 16th. Final deployments and downloads will be available by June 26th for original and June 30th for Google Cloud core.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Looker 25.10 Release Notes</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:breaking:1</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/embed-sdk-intro">Embed SDK</a> has been upgraded to release 2.0.0. While the 2.0.0 API is backwards-compatible with Embed SDK 1.8.x, the underlying implementation has changed for some functionality. SDK 1.8.x exported a number of classes. SDK 2.0.0 replaces these classes with interfaces that are marked as deprecated (alternative interfaces are identified). We recommend that applications use the interfaces that have an 'I' prefix (the interfaces that have prefixes are identical to the interfaces that don't have them). Applications that are upgraded to SDK 2.0.0 should continue to work and behave as they did previously. To take advantage of the API improvements, some refactoring will be required. The following major changes are included in Embed SDK 2.0.0:</p>
<ul>
<li>Navigating between dashboards, Explores, and Looks no longer requires that an iframe be recreated. Instead, the <code>loadDashboard</code>, <code>loadLook</code>, <code>loadExplore</code>, and <code>loadUrl</code> methods can be used to navigate within the Looker iframe.</li>
<li><code>connect</code> now returns a unified connection rather than a connection that is related only to a dashboard, a Look, or an Explore. The unified connection allows embedding applications to detect a user navigating inside the iframe.</li>
<li>Support for additional Looker embedded content has been added for Looker reports and query visualizations.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> This item was added on June 13, 2025.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Embed SDK has been upgraded to version 2.0.0. This new version is backward-compatible with 1.8.x but introduces changes to how classes are exported, recommending the use of interfaces instead. Key improvements include eliminating the need to recreate iframes for navigation, a unified connection object for better event detection, and expanded support for Looker reports and query visualizations. Some refactoring may be needed to leverage the new features.</summary>
    <title>Breaking: Embed SDK upgraded to 2.0.0</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:feature:2</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For period-over-period (PoP) measures, a new subparameter, <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/period-over-period#value_to_date"><code>value_to_date</code></a>, is available. When a PoP measure is defined with <code>value_to_date:yes</code>, Looker will calculate the amount of time in the current timeframe at the time that the query is run and apply that amount of time when it calculates the values for previous periods.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker's period-over-period measures now support a `value_to_date` subparameter. This allows for more accurate calculations of previous periods by considering the current timeframe when the query is executed.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New subparameter for period-over-period measures</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:feature:3</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Firebolt JDBC driver has been updated to version 3.5.0.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Firebolt JDBC driver has been updated to version 3.5.0, offering improved performance and reliability for data connectivity.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Firebolt JDBC driver updated to version 3.5.0</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:feature:4</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Hive JDBC driver has been updated to version 4.0.1.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Hive JDBC driver has been updated to version 4.0.1.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Hive JDBC driver updated</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:feature:5</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The MS SQL JDBC driver has been updated to version 12.10.0.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The MS SQL JDBC driver has been updated to version 12.10.0.</summary>
    <title>Feature: MS SQL JDBC driver updated</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:feature:6</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Teradata JDBC driver has been updated to version 20.00.00.45.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Teradata JDBC driver has been updated to version 20.00.00.45.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Teradata JDBC driver updated</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:feature:7</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Vertica JDBC driver has been updated to version 24.2.0-1.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Vertica JDBC driver has been updated to version 24.2.0-1.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Vertica JDBC Driver Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:feature:8</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The new Content Guardrails admin panel lets Looker admins limit both the ability for users to add or execute merged results queries on dashboards and the use of the dashboard auto-refresh option. Limiting merged results queries and dashboard auto-refreshes can reduce the number of queries that are sent to the database and improve dashboard performance. <strong>Note:</strong> This item was added on June 12, 2025.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker admins can now control user access to merged results queries and dashboard auto-refresh functionality. This feature helps reduce database load and enhance dashboard performance by limiting query execution.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Control Merged Results and Auto-Refresh</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:feature:9</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Looker <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/continuous-integration">Continuous Integration (CI)</a> features let you run tests on your LookML project to deliver more reliable, efficient, and user-friendly data experiences. You can use the CI validators to catch issues with SQL, data test, content, and LookML before they hit production to verify your LookML and prevent query errors for your users. You can also configure the CI validators to run automatically when a pull request is submitted to your LookML repository. <strong>Note:</strong> This item was added on June 23, 2025.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker's new Continuous Integration features enable automated testing of your LookML projects, catching SQL, data test, content, and LookML issues before they reach production. This ensures more reliable and user-friendly data experiences by preventing query errors.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Looker CI Features</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:10</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This release contains the following accessibility improvements:</p>
<ul>
<li>Increased contrast ratio for graphic elements, including icon bullets</li>
<li>Improved contrast for download links and unemphasized text to comply with Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) Level AA</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>This release includes accessibility improvements such as increased contrast for graphic elements and links, ensuring compliance with WCAG Level AA standards.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Accessibility Improvements</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:11</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Tile Actions kebab menu now includes the name of the dashboard tile in its <code>aria-label</code> value.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Tile Actions kebab menu's aria-label now includes the dashboard tile's name for improved accessibility.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Accessibility improvements for Tile Actions menu</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:12</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where SDK API calls could return a 500 error if optional headers were not specified. The API calls now work as expected even if optional headers are not included.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>SDK API calls now correctly handle missing optional headers, resolving the 500 error.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: SDK API call errors</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:13</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where the PDT Override Service Account field was not available for connections that use OAuth credentials. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The PDT Override Service Account field is now available for connections using OAuth credentials, resolving a previous issue.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: PDT Override Service Account Field Fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:14</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where the Manage Access dialog on a folder could load slowly if the Looker instance has a large number of groups. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Manage Access dialog for folders now loads quickly, even with a large number of groups in the Looker instance.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Manage Access dialog performance improved</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:15</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where, previously, testing a new OAuth connection before saving would run connection tests on an empty connection. OAuth settings must now be saved before running connection tests. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Previously, testing a new OAuth connection before saving would run connection tests on an empty connection. OAuth settings must now be saved before running connection tests. This feature now performs as expected.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed: OAuth connection testing</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:16</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The OAuth Tenant ID field will no longer appear in connections for which it is not relevant. The only connection type that supports this field is Trino.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The OAuth Tenant ID field is now hidden for irrelevant connections. This field is only relevant for Trino connections.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: OAuth Tenant ID field updated</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:17</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where the API calls to run git connection tests would fail unless the user was in dev mode. These calls now work as expected whether the user is in production or development mode.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>API calls for git connection tests now function correctly in both production and development modes, resolving a previous issue where they only worked in dev mode.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed git connection test API calls</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:18</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where drill downs wouldn't be displayed for a field if the first field value had null values. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Drill downs now display correctly even if the first field value is null.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Drill down issue fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:19</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where assigning the user attribute
<code>looker_internal_email_domain_allowlist</code> on the SAML config page would return a 500 error. This user attribute is not designed to be assigned at the user level, so the option to assign it has been removed from the SAML config page.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The ability to assign the user attribute `looker_internal_email_domain_allowlist` on the SAML config page has been removed due to a bug that caused a 500 error. This attribute is not intended for user-level assignment.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: User attribute assignment fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:20</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where restarting the Looker instance during a folder sync could cause the instance to fail to start.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Looker instance could fail to start after being restarted during a folder sync. This issue has now been resolved.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Looker instance startup issue fixed</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:21</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where selecting fields from the Session view in the System Activity User Explore could cause fanout. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The fanout issue when selecting fields from the Session view in the System Activity User Explore has been resolved. This feature now functions correctly.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed fanout issue in System Activity User Explore</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:22</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where the <code>count</code> table calculation function could return incorrect values if its inputs included a list with null values. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The `count` table calculation function now correctly handles lists with null values, returning accurate results.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed incorrect calculation in `count` table function</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:23</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where the drill menu did not properly translate some entries when the locale was set to Swedish (sv_SE). This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The drill menu in the product now correctly translates all entries when the locale is set to Swedish.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Drill menu translation fixed for Swedish locale</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:24</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where drilling on a query with subtotals could display incorrect values. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Drilling on a query with subtotals now displays the correct values, resolving a previous issue.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed incorrect values in queries with subtotals</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:25</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where filtering on a custom dimension that references a <code>datetime</code> type field could return the following error message: <code>No matching signature</code>. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Filtering on a custom dimension that references a datetime type field could return an error. This issue has now been resolved and the feature performs as expected.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed issue with custom dimension filtering</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:26</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where the LookML validator would return a 500 error if a LookML file contained a <code>sum_distinct</code> measure for a database that doesn't support <code>sum_distinct</code> measures. The LookML validator now returns a more descriptive error message.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The LookML validator no longer returns a 500 error for LookML files with `sum_distinct` measures on unsupported databases. Instead, it provides a more informative error message, improving the developer experience.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed LookML validator error for sum_distinct measures</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:27</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where entering the value <code>12:00</code> in the Time field of an alert schedule dialog would input <code>00:00</code> instead.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Time field in alert schedules would incorrectly display 00:00 when 12:00 was entered. This issue has now been resolved.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Time field input corrected</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:28</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where changes to PDT override settings would not be saved. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary> PDT override settings are now saved correctly after an issue that prevented this has been resolved. The feature is functioning as expected.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed issue with PDT override settings</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:29</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where PDTs could fail to rebuild with the following error message: <code>undefined method trace_id_hex</code>. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>PDTs failing to rebuild due to an "undefined method trace_id_hex" error have been resolved. The feature now functions correctly.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed PDT rebuild issue</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:feature:30</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/embed-reports">embed Looker reports</a> on Looker (original) instances when Looker reports and the Embed Looker reports Labs features are enabled for your instance. Looker reports are available in preview.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Looker reports are now available for embedding on Looker (original) instances with the relevant features enabled. This feature is currently in preview.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Embedding Looker reports is now available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:fixed:31</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An issue has been fixed where LDAP authentication could fail with the following error message: <code>no implicit conversion of Hash into String</code>. This feature now performs as expected.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>LDAP authentication no longer fails with a hash to string conversion error.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed LDAP authentication issue</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-11:feature:32</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/studio/conversational-analytics-code-interpreter">Code Interpreter in Conversational Analytics</a> is now available in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">Preview</a>. The Code Interpreter translates your natural language questions into Python code and executes that code to provide advanced analysis and visualizations. The Code Interpreter is disabled by default. Admins of Looker (Google Cloud core) instances can manage enablement for the Code Interpreter on the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/looker-core-admin-gemini#enable-ci-core">Gemini in Looker admin page</a>. <strong>Note:</strong> This item was added on June 23, 2025.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new code interpreter feature is available for conversational analytics, allowing users to translate natural language questions into Python code for advanced analysis and visualizations. This feature is disabled by default and can be managed by instance administrators.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Code Interpreter Available for Conversational Analytics</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-09:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Gemini in Looker will be enabled by default for Looker (original) instances that meet at least one of the following criteria:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Automated Gemini in Looker enablement and user management setting on the Settings page in the Looker Admin panel was previously enabled.</li>
<li>The instance is updated to Looker 25.6 or later after June 9, 2025.</li>
</ul>
<p>Instances that are hosted in the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/looker-original-locations">EMEA region</a> and those that are enrolled in Looker's <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/standard-extended-support-release-program-overview">Extended Support Release (ESR) program</a> are exempt from automatic enablement.</p>
<p>Looker admins can still manage Gemini in Looker enablement manually on the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/admin-panel-platform-gil">Gemini in Looker</a> page in the Admin panel.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Gemini in Looker will be automatically enabled by default for Looker (original) instances starting with version 25.6, provided they meet specific criteria or had the feature enabled previously. However, instances in the EMEA region or those in the ESR program are exempt from this automatic enablement. Admins retain manual control over the feature</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Gemini in Looker enablement update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:looker:2025-06-09:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/admin-panel-general-settings#gemini_default_enablement">Automated Gemini in Looker enablement and user management</a> setting is enabled, the Gemini Default Users group
is created automatically for instances that use an <a href="https://cloud.google.com/looker/docs/access-levels#open_and_closed_systems_of_access_to_folders">open system configuration</a>. The Gemini Default Users group is populated automatically with all existing users and any new users who are added to the instance.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new feature is available for Looker, regarding the Automated Gemini enablement and user management. When the relevant setting is enabled, a Gemini Default Users group is automatically created and populated with all existing and new users for instances using an open system configuration.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Automated Gemini in Looker</title>
  </entry>
</feed>