<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Apigee APIM Operator</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Apigee APIM Operator</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-apim-operator</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/apigee-apim-operator/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-apim-operator:2025-09-24:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On September 24, 2025, we released an updated version of Apigee.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new version of Apigee was released on September 24, 2025.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Apigee Updated</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:apigee-apim-operator:2025-09-24:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>ApigeeBackendService for the Apigee Operator for Kubernetes (GA)</strong></p>
<p>The ApigeeBackendService resource for the Apigee Operator for Kubernetes is <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">Generally Available (GA)</a>.</p>
<p>This new resource enables the integration of the Apigee Operator for Kubernetes with the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine/docs/concepts/about-gke-inference-gateway">Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE) Inference Gateway</a>. The GKE Inference Gateway is an extension to the GKE Gateway that provides optimized routing and load balancing for serving generative Artificial Intelligence (AI) workloads. It simplifies the deployment, management, and observability of AI inference workloads.</p>
<p>With this new integration, GKE Inference Gateway users can now leverage Apigee's full suite of features to manage, govern and monetize their AI workload through APIs.</p>
<p>To learn more, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/apigee/docs/api-platform/apigee-kubernetes/apigee-apim-operator-apigeebackendservice">Create an ApigeeBackendService</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Apigee Operator for Kubernetes has reached General Availability, introducing the ApigeeBackendService resource. This feature allows seamless integration with the GKE Inference Gateway, simplifying the management and deployment of generative AI workloads.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Apigee Operator for Kubernetes Now Generally Available</title>
  </entry>
</feed>