<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Speech-to-Text</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Speech-to-Text</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:speech-to-text</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/speech-to-text/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:speech-to-text:2025-11-13:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Speech-to-Text has just launched <code>chirp_3</code> in public preview for the regions <code>asia-south1</code>, <code>europe-west2</code>, <code>europe-west3</code> and <code>northamerica-northeast1</code>.</p>
<p>For more information about the Chirp 3 model, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/speech-to-text/docs/models/chirp-3">Chirp 3 Transcription: Enhanced multilingual accuracy</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Chirp 3 model is now in public preview in asia-south1, europe-west2, europe-west3 and northamerica-northeast1.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Chirp 3 Now in Public Preview</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:speech-to-text:2025-10-13:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Speech-to-Text is excited to announce the General Availability (GA) of the Chirp 3: Transcription, the latest generation of Google's multilingual Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR)-specific generative model, delivering state-of-the-art ASR accuracy and multilingual capabilities. Available exclusively in the Speech-to-Text API V2, Chirp 3 delivers significant enhancements in transcription accuracy and speed over previous versions.
Under the new <code>chirp_3</code> model identifier, you can now leverage powerful new capabilities, including speaker diarization to identify different speakers and automatic language detection for multilingual audio. The model supports all major recognition methods —<code>StreamingRecognize</code>, <code>Recognize</code>, and <code>BatchRecognize</code>- making it suitable for both real-time and batch processing. Chirp 3 also offers advanced features such as speech adaptation for custom vocabularies and a built-in denoiser to improve results from noisy audio.</p>
<p>To explore the new Chirp 3: Transcription model's capabilities and learn how to leverage its full potential, please visit our <a href="https://cloud.google.com/speech-to-text/v2/docs/chirp_3-model">updated documentation page</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Google</summary>
    <title>Feature: Introducing Chirp 3: Advanced Speech Recognition</title>
  </entry>
</feed>