<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Storage Transfer Service</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Storage Transfer Service</subtitle>
  <updated>2026-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:storage-transfer-service</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/storage-transfer-service/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:storage-transfer-service:2026-01-14:feature:0</id>
    <published>2026-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2026-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Storage Transfer Service event-driven transfers are now available for Azure Blob
Storage and Data Lake Storage Gen2 sources. Event-driven transfers listen
to Azure Event Grid notifications via Azure Storage Queues to automatically
transfer new or updated objects from your Azure container to
Cloud Storage.</p>
<p>For more information, see
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/storage-transfer/docs/event-driven-azure">Event-driven transfers from Azure Blob Storage or Data Lake Storage Gen2</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Storage Transfer Service now supports event-driven transfers from Azure Blob Storage and Data Lake Storage Gen2. This feature automatically transfers new or updated objects from Azure to Cloud Storage by listening to Azure Event Grid notifications. This enhances efficiency by ensuring data is transferred as soon as it's available.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Event-driven transfers from Azure Storage</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:storage-transfer-service:2025-12-02:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now transfer data from AWS S3 or Azure Blob Storage to Cloud Storage
over a private network connection, using Cross-Cloud Interconnect or
Partner Interconnect. Transferring data over a private connection can
optimize costs, provide dedicated bandwidth, and help meet compliance needs by
keeping data off the public internet.</p>
<p>See <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/storage-transfer/docs/create-transfers/agentless/customer-managed-private-network">Transfer from AWS or Azure over a customer-managed private
network</a>
for details.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now transfer data from AWS S3 or Azure Blob Storage to Cloud Storage over a private network connection. This method optimizes costs, provides dedicated bandwidth, and helps meet compliance needs.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Data Transfer from AWS/Azure</title>
  </entry>
</feed>