<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Google Cloud VMware Engine</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Google Cloud VMware Engine</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-12-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-vmware-engine</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/google-cloud-vmware-engine/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-vmware-engine:2025-12-25:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-12-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-12-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>VMware Engine <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/vmware-engine/docs/concepts/node-types"><code>ve2</code> nodes</a> are now available in the Milan, Italy (<code>europe-west8-b</code>) zone in the Milan, Italy, Europe region (<code>europe-west8</code>).</p>]]></content>
    <summary>VMware Engine `ve2` nodes are now available in the Milan, Italy zone (`europe-west8-b`) within the `europe-west8` region. This expansion brings enhanced capabilities closer to European customers.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: VMware Engine nodes now in Milan</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-vmware-engine:2025-12-05:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>VMware Engine now supports private clouds with mixed node families (<code>ve1</code> and <code>ve2</code>). While a private cloud can contain mixed node families, each cluster within that private cloud must contain nodes of the same type. This feature is available in the following regions and zones:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ashburn, North America (<code>us-east4-a</code>, <code>us-east4-b</code>)</li>
<li>Iowa, North America (<code>us-central1-a</code>)</li>
<li>Montreal, North America (<code>northamerica-northeast1-a</code>)</li>
<li>Sydney, Australia (<code>australia-southeast1-a</code>, <code>australia-southeast1-b</code>)</li>
<li>Frankfurt, Europe (<code>europe-west3-a</code>, <code>europe-west3-b</code>)</li>
<li>Santiago, South America (<code>southamerica-west1-b</code>)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> To create a new cluster of a different node family, contact Cloud Customer Care.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>VMware Engine private clouds can now have mixed node families (ve1 and ve2), but clusters must remain single-family. This is available in Ashburn, Iowa, Montreal, Sydney, Frankfurt, and Santiago.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Private clouds now support mixed node families</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-vmware-engine:2025-11-26:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>VMware Engine <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/vmware-engine/docs/concepts/node-types"><code>ve2</code> nodes</a> are now available in the Dallas, Texas, North America region (<code>us-south1-b</code>).</p>]]></content>
    <summary>VMware Engine nodes are now available in the Dallas, Texas, North America region.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: VMware Engine nodes now in Dallas</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-vmware-engine:2025-11-14:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>VMware Engine <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/vmware-engine/docs/concepts/node-types"><code>ve2</code> nodes</a> are now available in the Tokyo, Japan region (<code>asia-northeast1-a</code>).</p>]]></content>
    <summary>VMware Engine nodes are now available in the Tokyo region.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: VMware Engine nodes now in Tokyo</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-vmware-engine:2025-11-04:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>VMware Engine <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/vmware-engine/docs/concepts/node-types"><code>ve2</code> nodes</a> are now available in the London, England, Europe (<code>europe-west2-b</code>) zone in the London, England, Europe region (<code>europe-west2</code>).</p>]]></content>
    <summary>VMware Engine nodes are now available in the London, England, Europe region. This expansion provides more options for users in Europe.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: VMware Engine nodes now in London</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-vmware-engine:2025-10-31:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>VMware Engine <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/vmware-engine/docs/concepts/node-types"><code>ve1</code> nodes</a> are now available in the Mumbai, India (<code>asia-south1-b</code>) zone in the Mumbai region (<code>asia-south1</code>).</p>]]></content>
    <summary>VMware Engine nodes are now available in the Mumbai, India zone. This expansion provides users with more options for deploying VMware solutions in the Asia region.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: VMware Engine nodes now in Mumbai</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-vmware-engine:2025-10-03:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is to notify you about upcoming changes in licensing model with Google Cloud VMware Engine following <a href="https://blogs.vmware.com/cloud-foundation/2025/08/29/vmware-cloud-foundation-cloud-on-your-terms/">Broadcom's recent announcement</a> to move to a "bring your own" subscription model for VMware Cloud Foundation (VCF).</p>
<p>You can renew or add additional capacity of VMware Engine nodes with VCF-license included until <strong>October 15, 2025</strong>. After that, Google Cloud will not be able to sell new VMware Engine VCF license-included nodes. You can buy new VMware Engine BYOL nodes and use them with "bring your own" VCF subscriptions (purchased by you from Broadcom) for new capacity after <strong>October 15, 2025</strong>.</p>
<p>For any questions, please reach out to your Google Cloud sales team, who can help review your specific scenarios, discuss the implications of these changes for your organization, and help you manage this transition.</p>
<p>For more details, see the <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/vmware-engine/docs/service-announcements#2025-10-03">October 3, 2025</a> service announcement.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>VMware Engine is updating its licensing model in line with Broadcom's announcement. You can purchase VCF license-included nodes until October 15, 2025. After this date, new capacity will require a Bring Your Own License (BYOL) subscription for VCF purchased directly from Broadcom. Please contact your Google Cloud sales team for assistance with this transition.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: VMware Engine Licensing Changes</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-vmware-engine:2025-09-26:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>VMware Engine <code>ve2</code> nodes are now available in the following additional region:</p>
<ul>
<li>Doha, Qatar (<code>me-central1</code>, <code>v-zone-a</code>)</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>VMware Engine `ve2` nodes are now available in Doha, Qatar. This expansion offers new options for customers in the region.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: VMware Engine nodes now in Doha</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-vmware-engine:2025-09-24:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All 3-year <a href="https://cloud.google.com/docs/cuds">Committed Use Discounts (CUDs)</a> for VMware Engine <code>ve1</code> SKUs are now End-of-Sale across all regions where the service is available.</p>
<p>The following specific 3-year commitments are impacted by this change:</p>
<ul>
<li>3-year commitment (monthly payments), Fully Licensed Pricing - "postpaid"</li>
<li>3-year commitment (upfront payments), Fully Licensed Pricing - "prepay"</li>
<li>3-year commitment (monthly payments), Fully Licensed convertible commitment - "postpaid"</li>
<li>3-year commitment (upfront payments), Fully Licensed convertible commitment - "prepay"</li>
<li>3-year commitment (monthly payments), Portable License Pricing - "postpaid"</li>
<li>3-year commitment (upfront payments), Portable License Pricing - "prepay"</li>
<li>3-year commitment (monthly payments), Protected License Pricing - "postpaid"</li>
<li>3-year commitment (upfront payments), Protected License Pricing - "prepay"</li>
</ul>
<p>Refer to <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vmware-engine/docs/concepts-node-types">VMware Engine node types</a> for the regional availability of <code>ve1</code> SKUs.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>All 3-year Committed Use Discounts for VMware Engine ve1 SKUs are now End-of-Sale. This impacts various commitment types, including monthly and upfront payments with different licensing options. Please refer to the VMware Engine node types documentation for regional availability.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: 3-year VMware Engine CUDs End-of-Sale</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-vmware-engine:2025-09-15:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>VMware Engine <code>ve2</code> nodes are now available in the following additional region and zone:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Milan, Italy, Europe region (<code>europe-west8-a</code>).</li>
<li>The Melbourne, Australia (<code>australia-southeast2-b</code>) zone in the Melbourne, Australia region (<code>australia-southeast2</code>).</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>VMware Engine `ve2` nodes are now available in the Milan, Italy region (europe-west8-a) and the Melbourne, Australia zone (australia-southeast2-b).</summary>
    <title>Announcement: New VMware Engine nodes in Milan and Melbourne</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-vmware-engine:2025-09-11:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now use Privileged Access Manager (PAM) to accelerate the deletion of "soft deleted" private clouds. For more information, see the documentation on how to <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vmware-engine/docs/private-clouds/howto-delete-private-cloud">delete a private cloud</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Privileged Access Manager (PAM) now speeds up the deletion of </summary>
    <title>Feature: Accelerate Private Cloud Deletion</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-vmware-engine:2025-08-28:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>VMware Engine <code>ve2</code> nodes are now available in the London, England, Europe region (<code>europe-west2-a</code>).</p>]]></content>
    <summary>VMware Engine `ve2` nodes are now available in the London, England, Europe region (`europe-west2-a`).</summary>
    <title>Announcement: VMware Engine nodes now in London</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-vmware-engine:2025-08-14:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>VMware Engine <code>v2</code> nodes are now available in the Santiago, Chile (<code>southamerica-west1-b</code>) zone in the Santiago region (<code>southamerica-west1</code>) region.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>VMware Engine v2 nodes are now available in Santiago, Chile.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: New VMware Engine nodes in Santiago</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-vmware-engine:2025-08-08:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>VMware Engine <code>ve2</code> nodes are now available in the Dammam, KSA (<code>me-central2</code>) region.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>VMware Engine `ve2` nodes are available in Dammam, KSA (`me-central2`) region.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: VMware Engine nodes now in Dammam</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-vmware-engine:2025-07-14:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>VMware Engine <code>ve2</code> nodes are now available in the São Paulo, Brazil (<code>southamerica-east1-c</code>) zone in the São Paulo region (<code>southamerica-east1</code>).</p>]]></content>
    <summary>VMware Engine `ve2` nodes are now available in the São Paulo zone (`southamerica-east1-c`), in the São Paulo region (`southamerica-east1`). This expansion brings dedicated bare-metal compute capacity closer to customers in South America.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: VMware Engine nodes now in São Paulo</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-vmware-engine:2025-07-07:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When upgrading to Windows Server 2022 or newer images on your GCVE private clouds, you can use a combination of Windows Server BYOL for Windows Server 2019 and earlier images and on-demand licensing for Google-provided Windows Server 2022. For more information, see
<a href="https://cloud.google.com/vmware-engine/docs/vmware-ecosystem/microsoft-licensing#combination-mode">Use a combination of BYOL and on-demand Windows Server licenses from Google</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now use a combination of Windows Server BYOL and on-demand licensing for Google-provided Windows Server 2022 images when upgrading your GCVE private clouds. This provides flexibility for managing your Microsoft licenses.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Windows Server Licensing Options for GCVE</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-vmware-engine:2025-07-01:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>VMware Engine single-node private clouds, created after June 4th 2025, will no longer delete after 60 days. All single-node private clouds will have no time limit. Single-node private clouds have limitations to <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vmware-engine/sla?e=48754805&amp;hl=en">SLA</a>, <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vmware-engine/docs/concepts-private-cloud#single-node">patching</a>, and <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vmware-engine/docs/concepts-private-cloud#single-node">upgrades</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Single-node VMware Engine private clouds created after June 4th, 2025, will no longer have a 60-day deletion limit. All single-node private clouds will now have unlimited usage. However, these single-node private clouds have specific limitations regarding SLA, patching, and upgrades.</summary>
    <title>Feature: VMware Engine single-node private clouds have unlimited usage</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-vmware-engine:2025-06-11:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>VMware Engine <code>ve2</code> nodes are now available in Toronto, Canada (<code>northamerica-northeast2</code>).</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The `ve2` nodes for VMware Engine are now available in Toronto, Canada.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: VMware Engine nodes now in Toronto</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-vmware-engine:2025-06-09:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>VMware Engine <code>ve2</code> nodes are now available in the following additional region:</p>
<ul>
<li>Melbourne, Australia (<code>australia-southeast2-a</code>)</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>VMware Engine `ve2` nodes are now available in Melbourne, Australia.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: VMware Engine nodes now in Melbourne</title>
  </entry>
</feed>