<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Google Cloud Contact Center as a Service</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Google Cloud Contact Center as a Service</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-11-03:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Google Cloud CCaaS 3.41 pre-release notes</strong></p>
<p>Here are the pre-release notes for Google Cloud CCaaS 3.41. When we release version 3.41, we expect the new capabilities to be as shown here.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>New capabilities are coming in version 3.41 of Google Cloud CCaaS. Please review the pre-release notes for details.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Google Cloud CCaaS 3.41 Pre-release Notes</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-11-03:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Nested disposition lists</strong></p>
<p>You can now organize your disposition lists by grouping them into nested folders, making it easier for agents to find the disposition codes they need. This is available in the agent adapter and the agent desktop.</p>
<p>Administrators: The <strong>Disposition Codes</strong> dialog at <strong>Settings &gt; Operation Management &gt; Wrap-up &gt; Manage Disposition Codes</strong> has a new <strong>Tree</strong> tab.</p>
<p>User experience change: If you've configured nested disposition lists, the <strong>Disposition</strong> screen in the agent adapter displays links to the nested disposition lists.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Organize your disposition lists into nested folders for easier agent access.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Nested Disposition Lists</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-11-03:feature:2</id>
    <published>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Skip language selection and IVR menu readout</strong></p>
<p>You can configure your call flow to skip language selection and the IVR menu readout. Instead, callers get the default language and are routed to the default queue. This creates a faster call connection experience for end-users.</p>
<p>Administrators:</p>
<ul>
<li>In the <strong>Settings &gt; Languages &amp; Messages &gt; Languages</strong> pane, there's a new <strong>Skip language selection</strong> option.</li>
<li>In the <strong>Settings &gt; Queue &gt; IVR (Interactive Voice Response) &gt; IVR Queue Menu Readout</strong> section, there's a new <strong>Skip IVR Menu readout</strong> option.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Configure your call flow to bypass language selection and IVR menu readouts. Callers will be connected faster to the default language and queue.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Faster Call Connections</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-11-03:feature:3</id>
    <published>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Transfer an email session to a queue</strong></p>
<p>Agents can now transfer an email session to a queue. This resolves the problem of multiple email sessions being created when an agent forwards an email directly to an agent to transfer it.</p>
<p>Administrators: The <strong>General</strong> pane on the <strong>Email</strong> page at <strong>Settings &gt; Email</strong> contains a new <strong>Enable Email Transfer Between Queues</strong> checkbox.</p>
<p>User experience change: In the email adapter, a new <strong>Transfer</strong> button appears when an agent views an assigned email.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Agents can now transfer email sessions to a queue, preventing multiple email sessions and streamlining the transfer process. An 'Enable Email Transfer Between Queues' option is available in settings, and a new 'Transfer' button appears for agents in the email adapter.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Email Session Transfer</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-11-03:feature:4</id>
    <published>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Virtual agent to virtual agent direct chat transfers</strong></p>
<p>You can configure Dialogflow payloads to transfer chat sessions from one virtual agent directly to another virtual agent, using the destination virtual agent's agent ID.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Enable direct chat transfers between virtual agents using agent ID configuration.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Virtual agent chat transfers</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-11-03:feature:5</id>
    <published>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Extensions for support numbers</strong></p>
<p>You can assign a phone number extension to an agent that an end-user can use to directly call the agent. You can also set up an extension directory that end-users can use to find the extension for an agent that they want to call.</p>
<p>Administrators:</p>
<ul>
<li>The <strong>Agent Extensions</strong> pane on the <strong>Call</strong> page at <strong>Settings &gt; Call</strong> contains a new <strong>Consumer to Agent Calls</strong> section.</li>
<li>The <strong>Add new menu</strong> dialog at <strong>Settings &gt; Queue &gt; IVR (Interactive Voice Response) &gt; Menu Structure</strong> contains a new <strong>Extension Directory</strong> toggle.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Assign phone number extensions to agents for direct calls and set up an extension directory.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Agent Extensions</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-11-03:fixed:6</id>
    <published>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We addressed the following issues in this release:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where hyperlinks in the after-hours message of the web SDK were broken.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the language selector mistakenly appeared in the chat UI.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where an authentication request with an invalid or expired authentication token caused an agent's browser to become unresponsive and crash.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where an end-user using the iOS mobile SDK couldn't play a video that they had sent to an agent during a web chat session.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue for Android mobile SDK users where the <strong>Send</strong> icon in the end-user's chat input field didn't appear correctly.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where an instance using an Agent Assist profile with Conversation Summarization disabled incorrectly returned errors.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue that caused inaccurate virtual agent chat analytics. Affected metrics included <code>response_count</code>, <code>response_time_total</code>, <code>response_time_avg</code>, and <code>response_time_max</code>.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue for Microsoft Windows users where the scroll down button in the web chat pane wasn't working correctly.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue that occurred after an administrator deactivated the chat channel or the email channel. Instead of sending a single notification email for this change, the system was sending multiple notification emails.</li>
<li>Fixed a reporting discrepancy between the <strong>Agent Metrics (Historical)</strong> explore and the <strong>Chat Agent Metrics (Historical)</strong> explore in the advanced reporting dashboards.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in the <strong>Operation Management &gt; Virtual Agent</strong> settings pane. After configuring the virtual agent to assign records to a specific user, subsequent changes to other settings couldn't be saved.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the <code>sub_status</code> property was missing from the session metadata file.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue for HubSpot users where the inbound phone number in the call adapter displayed as <strong>null null</strong>.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue for Kustomer users that caused calls to be disconnected and the agent to be moved to <code>Unavailable</code> status.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the target response time timer in the chat adapter was resetting when the end-user sent a message instead of when the agent sent a message.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue that occurred when agents used the chat adapter to send email addresses containing underscores. The email addresses resolved incorrectly in the end-user's chat pane, breaking the links.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue that caused inaccurate chat analytics. Affected metrics included <code>response_time_total</code>, <code>response_time_avg</code>, and <code>chat_duration</code>.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the queue-level overcapacity callback limit was ignored, and the global setting was enforced instead.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue for Kustomer users where the ticket for an outbound call incorrectly showed the recipient's number in the <strong>From</strong> field and left the <strong>To</strong> field blank.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the agent adapter froze when an agent making an outbound call changed the outbound call number using their favorites list.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue that prevented a new chat from appearing in the agent desktop. This occurred when an agent had both the agent desktop and the standard chat adapter open in separate browser tabs.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue that caused a significant delay in displaying contact detail information in the call adapter for campaign calls.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where users with read-only roles were able to change settings on the developer settings page.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>This release includes fixes for various issues across web and mobile SDKs, agent tools, and reporting. Key fixes involve broken hyperlinks, incorrect language selectors, unresponsive agent browsers due to authentication errors, video playback problems on iOS, display issues with the send icon on Android, and inaccurate virtual agent analytics. Additionally, problems with chat analytics, scroll bar functionality, multiple notification emails, reporting discrepancies, virtual agent settings, missing session metadata, HubSpot and Kustomer integrations, response time timers, email address resolution, overcapacity callback limits, and agent desktop behavior have been resolved.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Resolved Issues in Recent Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-31:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Google Cloud CCaaS 3.40</strong></p>
<p>We've released version 3.40 of Google Cloud CCaaS, including the web SDK.</p>
<p>The timing of the update to your instance depends on the deployment schedule that you have chosen. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/deployment-schedules">Deployment schedules</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Version 3.40 of Google Cloud CCaaS has been released, featuring the web SDK. The update schedule for your instance varies based on your chosen deployment plan.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Google Cloud CCaaS 3.40</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-31:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>New variables for custom lookup URLs</strong></p>
<p>We've added the following five variables for custom lookup URLs:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>CUSTOMER_PHONE_NUMBER</strong>: the end-user's phone number</li>
<li><strong>SUPPORT_PHONE_NUMBER</strong>: your call center's phone number that an end-user calls in on</li>
<li><strong>OUTBOUND_NUMBER</strong>: the phone number an agent uses when making an outbound call</li>
<li><strong>SESSION_ID</strong>: the session ID</li>
<li><strong>CUSTOM_AGENT_ID</strong>: an optional agent ID</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/custom-crm#custom_lookup_url_configuration">Custom lookup URL configuration</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>New variables are available for custom lookup URLs, including customer and support phone numbers, outbound number, session ID, and custom agent ID.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New variables for custom lookup URLs</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-31:feature:2</id>
    <published>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Agent desktop maintains state after refresh</strong></p>
<p>While you're using the agent desktop, if you refresh your browser, the agent desktop now maintains its state. This means that active conversations, finished tabs, and recently closed sessions remain as they were before the refresh.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The agent desktop now preserves its state when the browser is refreshed. Active conversations, recently closed sessions, and finished tabs will remain as they were before the refresh.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Agent desktop maintains state after refresh</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-31:feature:3</id>
    <published>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Search in email channel by email address and name</strong></p>
<p>Agents can now search for email sessions by email address and name in the email adapter.</p>
<p>User experience change: The search pane in the email adapter includes two new fields: <strong>Email Address</strong> and <strong>Name</strong>.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/email-adapter#search-for-emails">Search for emails</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now search for email sessions using the sender's email address or name in the email adapter.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Search Emails by Name or Email Address</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-31:feature:4</id>
    <published>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Customize the color of the Start Screen Share button</strong></p>
<p>You can now control the color of the <strong>Start Screen Share</strong> button to match the color palette of your brand. For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/cobrowse#customize-start-screen-share-button">Customize the Start Screen Share button</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now customize the color of the Start Screen Share button to align with your brand's color palette.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Customize Start Screen Share Button Color</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-31:feature:5</id>
    <published>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>The europe-west4 and europe-west6 regions are available for Agent Assist conversation profiles</strong></p>
<p>The <code>europe-west4</code> and <code>europe-west6</code> regions are now available when you create an Agent Assist conversation profile for a Dialogflow CX virtual agent. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/create-a-dialogflow-agent#create-cp">Create conversation profile for Dialogflow CX virtual agents</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Agent Assist conversation profiles can now be created in the europe-west4 and europe-west6 regions. This expansion allows for greater flexibility and localization for Dialogflow CX virtual agents.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Agent Assist Now Available in More European Regions</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-31:feature:6</id>
    <published>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Web SDK: Support for hiding the download transcript option</strong></p>
<p>You can now configure the web SDK to do the following on the end-user's chat screen:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/web-sdk-v3-getting-started#hide-command-to-download-transcript-during-session">Hide the command to download a transcript during a session</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/web-sdk-v3-getting-started#hide-button-to-download-transcript-at-end-of-session">Hide the button to download a transcript at the end of a session</a>.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now configure the web SDK to hide the download transcript option during and at the end of a session.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Hide Transcript Download Option</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-31:feature:7</id>
    <published>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Web SDK: Support for hiding the Start a new conversation button</strong></p>
<p>You can now configure the web SDK to hide the <strong>Start a new conversation</strong> button on the end-user's chat screen after the session ends. For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/web-sdk-v3-getting-started#hide-start-new-conversation-button">Hide the button to download a transcript at the end of a session</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now hide the 'Start a new conversation' button on the chat screen after a session ends.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Hide Start New Conversation Button</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-31:fixed:8</id>
    <published>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following issues were addressed in this release:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue that prevented administrators from configuring virtual agents on the top level for IVR queues.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where attempting to configure automatic redirection settings for the top level of an IVR queue returned an error.</li>
<li>Fixed in issue that caused incorrect agent monitoring and reporting data when a virtual agent escalated a call to a queue in a different language.</li>
<li>Fixed issue for HubSpot users where the call adapter got stuck on a non-functional reconnect page after a session expired.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue for HubSpot users where the <strong>Delay call record creation until the call is connected to agent</strong> checkbox didn't appear in the <strong>CRM Record Creation Details</strong> pane.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue that prevented agents from ending direct SMS chat sessions.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue for Microsoft Windows 11 users that prevented agents from entering Japanese characters in the chat screen during chat sessions and into the notes during wrap-up.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where SDK custom data that was passed using the web SDK didn't appear in the agent adapter.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue that prevented custom links entered in the chat adapter from being converted into clickable links.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in the chat screen of the chat adapter where the <strong>Missed target response time</strong> message was partially obscured by the formatting toolbar.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where agents couldn't initiate a callback to a missed agent-to-agent call from the <strong>History</strong> tab of the agent adapter.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where predictive outbound calling campaigns stalled and incorrectly moved contacts to the <strong>Redialed</strong> list before retrying them. This prevented the campaigns from completing successfully.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in the <strong>Call Details</strong> pane where the <strong>Recording Message Sequence</strong> settings were incorrectly inactive when the <strong>Play Call Recording Messages</strong> checkboxes were cleared.</li>
</ul>
<p>Administrators: In the <strong>Call Details</strong> pane, we changed <strong>Recording Message Sequence</strong> to <strong>Recording Message Sequence for Outbound Calls</strong> for clarity.
* Fixed an issue where the customized greeting for an automatic redirection rule didn't play for calls that entered the queue using a Direct Access Phone (DAP) number.
* Fixed an issue that occurred when a call was made from the global contact list. On the <strong>Details</strong> tab of the call adapter, the destination name didn't display. Instead, the destination phone number displayed.
* Fixed an agent desktop issue where an agent status that was configured with a role restriction mistakenly appeared in the status list for a user assigned to that restricted role.
* Fixed an issue where searching for an inbound-only queue on the <strong>Phone Number Management</strong> page failed to return a result.
* Fixed an issue that caused queue duration and wait duration to be reported as <code>0</code>. This occurred when the <strong>Call Service Level Target</strong> on a queue settings page was set to a number that exceeded the maximum allowed limit.
* Fixed an issue where a team assigned to a preference profile added only 1 user to the profile's users count, instead of adding the total number of users on the team.
* Fixed an issue where agents were timed out for inactivity while composing an email in the email adapter.
* Fixed an issue where users with a custom role were unable to save changes in the <strong>Chat Settings</strong> pane, even when their role had <strong>View</strong> and <strong>Edit</strong> permissions.
* Fixed an issue that occurred after an agent configured their own hours of operation settings in the agent adapter. Those settings didn't appear for administrators in the agent's user profile on the <strong>Settings &gt; Users &amp; Team &gt; Manage Users &amp; Teams</strong> page. This prevented the administrator from making other edits to the agent's profile without overwriting the agent's hours of operation settings.
* Fixed an issue where CRM tickets weren't created for some calls.
* Fixed an issue where outbound SIP calls incorrectly appended data parameters, causing calls to fail.
* Fixed a Web SDK security vulnerability associated with DOMPurify.
* Fixed an issue where chat metadata wasn't saved to external storage. This occurred when an end-user ended a chat after escalating from a virtual agent but before being connected to a human agent.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>This release addresses several issues, including problems with virtual agent configuration, call redirection errors, inaccurate reporting data, HubSpot integration glitches, SMS chat session handling, Japanese character input on Windows 11, SDK data display, custom link conversion, chat screen message visibility, callback initiation from the History tab, predictive outbound campaign stalling, and incorrect recording message settings. Additionally, fixes were implemented for customized greetings on automatic redirection rules, destination name display in the Call Details pane, agent status visibility with role restrictions, inbound-only queue searches, queue duration and wait duration reporting, team assignment to preference profiles, agent inactivity timeouts during email composition, custom role permission issues, agent hours of operation settings synchronization, CRM ticket creation, outbound SIP call data parameter issues, a Web SDK security vulnerability, and chat metadata saving for escalated chats.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Bug Fixes and Improvements</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-30:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Advanced reporting dashboards version 3.40</strong></p>
<p>We've released version 3.40 of the advanced reporting dashboards.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Version 3.40 of the advanced reporting dashboards has been released.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Advanced reporting dashboards v3.40</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-30:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>New Agent Preference table in the Agent Availability dashboard</strong></p>
<p>We've added a new <strong>Agent Preference</strong> table to the <strong>Agent Availability</strong> dashboard. This table can help you ensure that queues have properly skilled agents assigned to them. It can also help identify agents who improperly change their availability filters. For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/dashboards-agent-availability">Agent availability dashboard</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new Agent Preference table has been added to the Agent Availability dashboard. This feature helps ensure correct agent skill assignment to queues and identifies misuse of availability filters.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Agent Availability Dashboard Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-30:feature:2</id>
    <published>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>New Audit Log dashboard</strong></p>
<p>We've added a new <strong>Audit log</strong> dashboard to help you track changes to the configuration of your instance. The dashboard tracks changes to the settings on the <strong>Developer Settings</strong> page, and displays information such as the type of change, who made the change, and when. This dashboard is similar in format to the advanced reporting dashboards, but you can't save it as a new dashboard. You access the <strong>Audit Log</strong> dashboard from the <strong>Settings</strong> menu. For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/dashboards-audit-log">Audit log dashboard</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Track configuration changes with the new Audit Log dashboard. See what changed, who changed it, and when. Access it from the Settings menu.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Audit Log Dashboard</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-30:fixed:3</id>
    <published>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We addressed the following issues in this release:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where the queue groups dashboard failed to display data for users with a custom role assigned to a queue or queue group.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue that caused the <strong>Agent Activity Timeline</strong> dashboard to display inaccurate or incomplete data.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue on the <strong>Virtual Agent - Calls</strong> dashboard where the <strong>Virtual Agent Name</strong> and <strong>Queue</strong> filters didn't display available values.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue on the <strong>Dispositions - Chats</strong> dashboard that prevented the <strong>Agent Email</strong>, <strong>Agent ID</strong>, and <strong>Location</strong> filters from displaying available values.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue on the <strong>Virtual Agent - Chats</strong> dashboard that prevented the <strong>Virtual Agent Name</strong> filter from displaying available values.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue on the <strong>Virtual Agent - Chats</strong> dashboard where the <strong>Date</strong> filter was incorrectly labeled <strong>Time Range</strong>.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue on the <strong>Abandons - Calls</strong> dashboard where <strong>Customer ANI</strong> values weren't appearing in the <strong>Queue Abandon Details</strong> and <strong>IVR Abandon Details</strong> tables despite the customer signing the waiver.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue on the <strong>Agent Activity Timeline</strong> dashboard where the <strong>Agent Name</strong> filter wasn't working properly.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Various dashboard issues have been resolved, including problems with data display, filter functionality, and data accuracy across multiple dashboards such as Queue Groups, Agent Activity Timeline, Virtual Agent, and Dispositions.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Dashboard Fixes</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-15:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Mobile SDK patch 2.14.1 is released</strong></p>
<p>This patch adds the <code>didHandleUjetError</code> function to the iOS SDK. The <code>didHandleUjetError</code> function can listen for and handle the following errors:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>networkError</code></li>
<li><code>authenticationError</code></li>
<li><code>authenticationJwtError</code></li>
<li><code>voipConnectionError</code></li>
<li><code>voipLibraryNotFound</code></li>
<li><code>chatLibraryNotFound</code></li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/ios-sdk-guide#fallback">Fallback</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new patch for the Mobile SDK, version 2.14.1, is now available. This update includes the `didHandleUjetError` function for the iOS SDK, which allows for handling various network and authentication-related errors. More details can be found in the documentation.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Mobile SDK patch 2.14.1 released</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-09:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Version 3.39 is released</strong></p>
<p>All release notes published on this date are part of version 3.39.</p>
<p>The timing of the update to your instance depends on the deployment schedule that you have chosen. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/deployment-schedules">Deployment schedules</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Version 3.39 has been released, including all release notes published on this date. The update timing depends on your chosen deployment schedule.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Version 3.39 Released</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-09:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Destination queue name and session history is available in the agent adapter</strong></p>
<p>The agent adapter now displays the destination queue during transfers and deflections for IVR calls. The agent adapter also displays transfer history in the <strong>Call details</strong> and <strong>Chat details</strong> tabs.</p>
<p>User experience changes:</p>
<ul>
<li>The <strong>Call details</strong> and <strong>Chat details</strong> tabs in the agent adapter have a new <strong>Transfer History</strong> section.</li>
<li>The chat pane in the chat adapter has a new <strong>Transfers</strong> button that opens the <strong>Transfer History</strong> pane.</li>
</ul>
<p>Administrators: There's a new checkbox at <strong>Settings &gt; Operation Management &gt; Transfer history</strong> for turning on transfer history in the agent adapter.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/queue-info-transfer-history-agent-adapter">Transfer history and queue information in the agent adapter</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The agent adapter now shows destination queue names during transfers and deflections. Additionally, transfer history is available in the Call details and Chat details tabs, providing a clearer view of call progression. Administrators can enable this feature via settings.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Agent Adapter Enhancements</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-09:feature:2</id>
    <published>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Improved controls over the ordering of key-value pairs in the agent adapter and CRM records</strong></p>
<p>Google Cloud CCaaS has improved controls over the ordering of the key-value pairs that appear in the agent adapter and in CRM records. Here's how the ordering controls work:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Virtual agents</strong>: When you configure session variables, you can use the new <code>display_order_in_adapter</code> property to specify the order that the session variables appear in the agent adapter and in CRM records. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/va-custom-payload#capture_from_intent_response">Capture from intent response</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Web SDK</strong>: Web SDK custom data is displayed in the agent adapter and CRM records in the order that the key-value pairs appear in the JSON custom data file. For more information about JSON custom data files, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/web-sdk#chat-unsigned-custom-data">Chat unsigned custom data</a>.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now control the order of key-value pairs in the agent adapter and CRM records for virtual agents and Web SDK custom data.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Improved Key-Value Pair Ordering</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-09:feature:3</id>
    <published>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Virtual agents for the SMS channel</strong></p>
<p>Virtual agents are now available for the SMS channel. This lets you create virtual agents and assign them to SMS queues, offering virtual agent support to end-users in SMS chat sessions. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/virtual-agents-for-sms">Virtual agents for SMS</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Virtual agents can now be used for the SMS channel. You can create virtual agents and assign them to SMS queues to provide support to end-users in SMS chat sessions.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Virtual Agents for SMS</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-09:feature:4</id>
    <published>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Search in the email channel</strong></p>
<p>Agents can now search for emails in the agent adapter by keyword, session ID, or subject. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/email-adapter#search-for-emails">Search for emails</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Agents can now search emails using keywords, session ID, or subject.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Email Search Feature</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-09:feature:5</id>
    <published>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Cancel scheduled calls with the callback calls API</strong></p>
<p>You can now use the callback calls API to cancel a single scheduled callback call or a list of calls. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/callback-call-api">Callback call API</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now cancel scheduled calls using the callback calls API.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cancel scheduled calls</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-09:feature:6</id>
    <published>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Mid-session authentication is supported by all CRM types</strong></p>
<p>Mid-session authentication is supported by all CRM types, not just custom CRMs. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/mid-session-authentication-apps-api">Mid-Session authentication by API</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Mid-session authentication is now available for all CRM types, not limited to custom CRMs.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Mid-session authentication for all CRMs</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-09:feature:7</id>
    <published>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>New advanced reporting dashboards</strong></p>
<p>The following new advanced reporting dashboard is available:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Deflections</strong>. Get deflection information by queue and for your entire contact center. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/dashboards-deflections">Deflections dashboards</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Agent activity timeline</strong>. See the historical activity for an agent. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/dashboards-agent-activity-timeline">Agent activity timeline dashboard</a>.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Check out the new advanced reporting dashboards for Deflections and Agent Activity Timeline to gain deeper insights into your contact center operations.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Reporting Dashboards Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-09:feature:8</id>
    <published>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Advanced reporting dashboard updates</strong></p>
<p>We've made the following updates to the advanced reporting dashboards:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Queue Group Dashboards All dashboard</strong>: The tiles and tables on this dashboard have been replaced with the following tables:</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Queue Group Performance Calls</strong>: displays detailed performance information for calls by queue group.</p>
</li>
<li><strong>Queue Group Performance Chats</strong>: displays detailed performance information for chats by queue group.</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/dashboards-queue-group-perf#queue-group-dashboards-all">Queue Group Dashboards All</a>.
* <strong>Queue interval dashboards</strong>: The <strong>Queue Interval - Calls</strong> and <strong>Queue Interval - Chats</strong> dashboards have a new <strong>Total Queue Entries</strong> column in the table tile. This is the sum of all inbound interactions that have entered a queue, excluding transfers.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/dashboards-queue-interval">Queue interval dashboards</a>.
* <strong>Virtual agent dashboards</strong>: On both the <strong>Virtual Agent Dashboard Calls</strong> and <strong>Virtual Agent Dashboard Chats</strong> dashboards, the virtual agent metrics table contains a new <strong>Interaction Outcome</strong> column.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/dashboards-virtual-agent">Virtual agent dashboards</a>.
* <strong>All Interactions - Chat dashboard</strong>: In the <strong>All Chat Interactions (Historical)</strong> table, if you configure chat transcript storage for your CRM, the values in the <strong>Chat ID</strong> column become links to the chat transcripts.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/dashboards-all-interactions">All interactions dashboards</a>.
* <strong>New metrics in the Call Queue Metrics (Historical) Explore</strong>: We've added the following two metrics to the <strong>Call Queue Metrics (Historical)</strong> Explore:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>CSL %</strong>: Custom Service Level. This is calculated as follows: The number of queued interactions within SLA / The number of queued interactions answered.</li>
<li><strong>Total Queued Answered</strong>: The number of queued interactions answered by a human agent.</li>
</ul>
<p>For information about metrics in an Explore, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/dashboards-add-tiles-to-dashboard#create_a_new_metrics_tile_in_a_dashboard">Create a new metrics tile in a dashboard</a>.
* <strong>Additional dashboards with advanced capabilities</strong>: the following dashboards now appear on the <strong>Advanced Reporting Landing Page</strong>. This means you can use them to create new custom dashboards or create Looks to link to custom dashboards.</p>
<p><strong>Performance</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Dispositions / Calls</strong></li>
<li><strong>Dispositions / Chats</strong></li>
<li><strong>Deflections / Calls</strong></li>
<li><strong>Deflections / Chats</strong></li>
<li><strong>CSAT / Calls</strong></li>
<li><strong>CSAT / Chats</strong></li>
<li><strong>Co-browse / Calls</strong></li>
<li><strong>Co-browse / Chats</strong></li>
<li><strong>Failed / Calls</strong></li>
<li><strong>Failed / Chats</strong></li>
<li><strong>Missed / Calls</strong></li>
<li><strong>Missed / Chats</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Agent Reporting</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Agent Activity Timeline</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Monitoring Dashboards</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Calls Connected</strong></li>
<li><strong>Chats Connected</strong></li>
<li><strong>Calls Queued</strong></li>
<li><strong>Chats Queued</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/dashboards-advanced-capabilities">Advanced capabilities</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The advanced reporting dashboards have been updated with new and improved features, including enhanced queue group and interval dashboards, new metrics for virtual agents and call queues, and additional advanced dashboards for performance and agent reporting.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Updated Reporting Dashboards</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-09:fixed:9</id>
    <published>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following issues were addressed in this release:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where incoming chats took precedence over the in-progress chat.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>User experience change</strong>: When a new chat appears in the agent adapter, it no longer takes focus away from the in-progress chat. The in-progress retains focus.
* Fixed a web SDK issue where sensitive data sent by an end-user was redacted for both the end-user and the agent, instead of just for the agent.
* Fixed an issue where the contact list in the agent adapter wouldn't load the full list of contacts.
* Fixed an issue where an agent clicking an email in the agent adapter returned an <strong>Email Not Found</strong> error.
* Fixed an issue where managers assigned to multiple teams were unable to view agent statistics for every team they were assigned to.
* Fixed an issue for ServiceNow users where <code>call_duration</code> was using the earliest <code>connected_at</code> time instead of the latest <code>connected_at</code> time, causing call durations to appear longer than they actually were.
* Fixed an issue in the <strong>Settings &gt; Developer Settings &gt; External Storage</strong> pane where language checkboxes were associated with the <strong>Co-browse Recordings</strong> checkbox instead of the <strong>Session Data Feed</strong> checkbox.</p>
<p><strong>Administrators</strong>: In the <strong>Settings &gt; Developer Settings &gt; External Storage</strong> pane, the languages checkboxes have moved from the <strong>Co-browse Recordings</strong> checkbox to the <strong>Session Data Feed</strong> checkbox.
* Fixed an issue where agent-initiated outbound calls were using the default number for the selected queue instead of the number chosen by the agent.
* Fixed an issue where the downloaded session chat data report contained an extra quotation mark.
* Fixed an issue where users received an email telling them to create a password after Single Sign-On (SSO) was turned on.
* Fixed an issue where SSO configuration settings in the user's instance were deleted after they turned off SSO.
* Fixed an issue where an administrator couldn't configure agent status restrictions without exposing them to agents.
* Fixed an issue where custom contact lists could only be replaced, and not removed, after they were assigned to a team.
* Fixed an issue where the inheritance indicator and <strong>Reset to parent</strong> button was missing from the queue level <strong>Contact List Management</strong> pane.
* Fixed an issue where the SMS and Web chat availability preferences in the agent adapter were the reverse of how they were configured.
* Fixed an issue where queue transfer restrictions were not saved after being configured.
* Fixed an issue that occurred when a user attempted to name a new queue. The name field abruptly lost focus after the first character, forcing the user to enter the queue name again.
* Fixed an issue where creating an instance would time out and fail.
* Fixed an issue that prevented reports from being downloaded.
* Fixed an issue where the chat history for blended SMS sessions failed to save.
* Fixed an issue where the <strong>Transfer failed</strong> message didn't appear. This occurred when an agent failed to pick up a transferred call before the transferred call expiration time expired.
* Fixed an issue where IVR call recordings failed to save or were corrupted. This resulted in recordings that were only one second long, were saved in the wrong format, or weren't saved at all.
* Fixed an issue where completed chat sessions appeared in the chats waiting area of agent desktop.
* Fixed an issue for CRM users with voicemails that are attached directly to tickets. An incorrect "External Storage must be configured" warning appeared when configuring voicemail options for IVR queues.
* Fixed an issue where transfer restrictions that were configured and saved for a web queue did not appear correctly the next time the <strong>Transfer Restrictions</strong> pane for that queue was viewed.
* Fixed an issue where the unread message count in the chat pane was inconsistent when viewing it from multiple browser tabs.
* Fixed an issue in virtual assistant reporting where the <code>finish_reason</code> property was incorrectly assigned to the <code>undefined</code> value. Now the <code>finish_reason</code> property is assigned to descriptive values that describe the reason for the conclusion of the chat session.
* Fixed an issue where PDF transcripts of chat sessions contained malformed links.
* Fixed an issue in historical reports where the fields in the <strong>Failed Reason Description</strong> column were blank.
* Fixed an issue where CSAT scores were missing from some advanced reporting dashboards.
* Fixed an issue for HubSpot users that caused long delays in case creation for inbound calls.
* Fixed an issue where the photo and video files that the agent provided in pre-session Smart Actions didn't appear in the CRM.
* Fixed an issue where agents in <code>Unavailable</code> status couldn't see waiting web chats.
* Fixed an issue where HTML was not rendering properly in virtual agent messages in the agent adapter
* Fixed an issue where agents were not switching into <code>Wrap-up Exceeded</code> status after a breakthrough call.
* Fixed an agent desktop issue where administrators were unable to assign announcements to some teams or agents.
* Fixed an agent desktop issue where agents couldn't copy text to the clipboard from an agent desktop custom panel.
* Fixed an agent desktop issue where the term "Anonymous User" wasn't being translated into French.
* Fixed an issue where the <code>UJET_ID</code> and <code>ANI</code> variables weren't passed correctly for SIP calls.
* Fixed an issue where the chat adapter froze when agents switched between chats.
* Fixed an issue on the <strong>Agents</strong> page of the Google Cloud CCaaS portal where administrators couldn't switch between session types.
* Fixed an issue where a newly added Agent Assist platform displayed as <code>Invalid</code> even though it was valid.
* Fixed an issue for Salesforce users where the call button didn't work when an agent attempted to call a number that was attached to a record for a previous call.
* Fixed an issue where audio files with accented characters in their file names failed to play back when using a storage proxy.
* Fixed an agent desktop issue where the <code>UJET_ID</code> variable in the custom URL for a custom panel wasn't being passed correctly.
* Fixed an issue where calls originating from a native campaign generated two CRM tickets for the same interaction.
* Fixed latency issues with web SDK Telnyx calls.
* Fixed an issue where outbound Bring Your Own Carrier (BYOC) calls used a number other than the one agents selected in the agent adapter.
* Fixed a Telnyx chatbot worker failure issue where background jobs related to call processing and chatbot escalations were failing and consuming excessive system resources.
* Fixed an issue where calls to the bulk user upload endpoint returned a success status even when the uploads failed.
* Fixed an issue in the chat waiting field of the agent desktop when multiple chats were in wrap-up. Instead of displaying <strong>Wrap-up in progress</strong> for all sessions in wrap-up, some sessions displayed <strong>Auto answered</strong>.
* Fixed an issue in the queue group dashboard where the <strong>Callbacks waiting</strong> tile incorrectly included callbacks that were completed, abandoned, or failed.
* Fixed an issue that caused inbound calls to disconnect if they were routed to an agent with a disabled microphone.
* Fixed an issue for HubSpot users where logging the "call started" event (<code>create_activity</code>) in the ticket was delayed.
* Fixed an issue that prevented transferred calls from being routed to available agents.
* Fixed an issue in the agent adapter for French (Canada) where words weren't translated or were translated incorrectly.
* Fixed an issue in call queue reporting where the Failed Reason Description for voice-scheduled mobile calls was not appearing.
* Fixed an issue that prevented external chat transcripts from being passed into new chat sessions.
* Fixed an advanced reporting issue where CSAT ratings were not appearing correctly when creating custom dashboards.
* Fixed an advanced reporting issue where callbacks waiting metrics didn't match in the following dashboards: <strong>Queue Groups Dashboard Calls</strong> and <strong>Queued Calls Status Dashboard</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>This release addresses numerous bugs and user experience improvements across the platform. Key fixes include improved chat handling, accurate data redaction, contact list loading, and error resolution for email and call duration tracking. Administrator settings for external storage and agent statistics have also been refined. Additionally, several issues related to Single Sign-On, queue management, and reporting accuracy have been resolved, ensuring a more stable and efficient user experience.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Resolved various issues</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-14:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Portal version 3.40 pre-release notes</strong></p>
<p>Here are the pre-release notes for portal version 3.40. When we release version 3.40, we expect the new capabilities to be as shown here.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Pre-release notes for version 3.40 of the portal are now available, detailing expected new capabilities upon release.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Portal Version 3.40 Pre-Release Notes</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-14:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>New variables for custom lookup URLs</strong></p>
<p>We've added the following five variables for custom lookup URLs:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>CUSTOMER_PHONE_NUMBER</strong>: the end-user's phone number</li>
<li><strong>SUPPORT_PHONE_NUMBER</strong>: your call center's phone number that an end-user calls in on</li>
<li><strong>OUTBOUND_NUMBER</strong>: the phone number an agent uses when making an outbound call</li>
<li><strong>SESSION_ID</strong>: the session ID</li>
<li><strong>CUSTOM_AGENT_ID</strong>: an optional agent ID</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/custom-crm#custom_lookup_url_configuration">Custom lookup URL configuration</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>We've added five new variables (CUSTOMER_PHONE_NUMBER, SUPPORT_PHONE_NUMBER, OUTBOUND_NUMBER, SESSION_ID, and CUSTOM_AGENT_ID) for custom lookup URLs. This enhancement allows for greater customization in how you integrate with external systems using lookup URLs.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New variables for custom lookup URLs</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-14:feature:2</id>
    <published>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Agent desktop maintains state after refresh</strong></p>
<p>While you're using the agent desktop, if you refresh your browser, the agent desktop now maintains its state. This means that active conversations, finished tabs, and recently closed sessions remain as they were before the refresh.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The agent desktop now preserves its state even when the browser is refreshed. Active conversations, closed tabs, and recently ended sessions will remain as they were prior to the refresh.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Agent desktop state maintained after refresh</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-14:feature:3</id>
    <published>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Search in email channel by email address and name</strong></p>
<p>Agents can now search for email sessions by email address and name in the email adapter.</p>
<p>User experience change: The search pane in the email adapter includes two new fields: <strong>Email Address</strong> and <strong>Name</strong>.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/email-adapter#search-for-emails">Search for emails</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Easily find email conversations using sender's email address or name.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Search emails by name</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-14:feature:4</id>
    <published>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Customize the color of the Start Screen Share button</strong></p>
<p>You can now control the color of the <strong>Start Screen Share</strong> button to match the color palette of your brand. For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/cobrowse#customize-start-screen-share-button">Customize the Start Screen Share button</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now customize the color of the Start Screen Share button to align with your brand's color palette.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Customize the Start Screen Share button color</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-14:feature:5</id>
    <published>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>The europe-west4 and europe-west6 regions are available for Agent Assist conversation profiles</strong></p>
<p>The <code>europe-west4</code> and <code>europe-west6</code> regions are now available when you create an Agent Assist conversation profile for a Dialogflow CX virtual agent. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/create-a-dialogflow-agent#create-cp">Create conversation profile for Dialogflow CX virtual agents</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Agent Assist conversation profiles can now be created in the europe-west4 and europe-west6 regions for Dialogflow CX virtual agents.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Agent Assist now available in europe-west4 and europe-west6</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-14:feature:6</id>
    <published>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Web SDK: Support for hiding the download transcript option</strong></p>
<p>You can now configure the web SDK to do the following on the end-user's chat screen:</p>
<ul>
<li>Hide the <strong>Download transcript</strong> menu option during a chat session</li>
<li>Hide the <strong>Download transcript</strong> button after a chat session ends</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Users can now hide the download transcript option in the web SDK.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Download Transcript Hidden</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-14:feature:7</id>
    <published>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Web SDK: Support for hiding the Start a new conversation button</strong></p>
<p>You can now configure the web SDK to hide the <strong>Start a new conversation</strong> button on the end-user's chat screen after the session ends.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The web SDK now supports hiding the "Start a new conversation" button after a chat session ends.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Start a new conversation button support</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-14:fixed:8</id>
    <published>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following issues were addressed in this release:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue that prevented administrators from configuring virtual agents on the top level for IVR queues.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where attempting to configure automatic redirection settings for the top level of an IVR queue returned an error.</li>
<li>Fixed in issue that caused incorrect agent monitoring and reporting data when a virtual agent escalated a call to a queue in a different language.</li>
<li>Fixed issue for HubSpot users where the call adapter got stuck on a non-functional reconnect page after a session expired.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue for HubSpot users where the <strong>Delay call record creation until the call is connected to agent</strong> checkbox didn't appear in the <strong>CRM Record Creation Details</strong> pane.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue that prevented agents from ending direct SMS chat sessions.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue for Microsoft Windows 11 users that prevented agents from entering Japanese characters in the chat screen during chat sessions and into the notes during wrap-up.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where SDK custom data that was passed using the web SDK didn't appear in the agent adapter.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue that prevented custom links entered in the chat adapter from being converted into clickable links.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in the chat screen of the chat adapter where the <strong>Missed target response time</strong> message was partially obscured by the formatting toolbar.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where agents couldn't initiate a callback to a missed agent-to-agent call from the <strong>History</strong> tab of the agent adapter.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where predictive outbound calling campaigns stalled and incorrectly moved contacts to the <strong>Redialed</strong> list before retrying them. This prevented the campaigns from completing successfully.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in the <strong>Call Details</strong> pane where the <strong>Recording Message Sequence</strong> settings were incorrectly inactive when the <strong>Play Call Recording Messages</strong> checkboxes were cleared.</li>
</ul>
<p>Administrators: In the <strong>Call Details</strong> pane, we changed <strong>Recording Message Sequence</strong> to <strong>Recording Message Sequence for Outbound Calls</strong> for clarity.
* Fixed an issue where the customized greeting for an automatic redirection rule didn't play for calls that entered the queue using a Direct Access Phone (DAP) number.
* Fixed an issue that occurred when a call was made from the global contact list. On the <strong>Details</strong> tab of the call adapter, the destination name didn't display. Instead, the destination phone number displayed.
* Fixed an agent desktop issue where an agent status that was configured with a role restriction mistakenly appeared in the status list for a user assigned to that restricted role.
* Fixed an issue where searching for an inbound-only queue on the <strong>Phone Number Management</strong> page failed to return a result.
* Fixed an issue that caused queue duration and wait duration to be reported as <code>0</code>. This occurred when the <strong>Call Service Level Target</strong> on a queue settings page was set to a number that exceeded the maximum allowed limit.
* Fixed an issue where a team assigned to a preference profile added only 1 user to the profile's users count, instead of adding the total number of users on the team.
* Fixed an issue where agents were timed out for inactivity while composing an email in the email adapter.
* Fixed an issue where users with a custom role were unable to save changes in the <strong>Chat Settings</strong> pane, even when their role had <strong>View</strong> and <strong>Edit</strong> permissions.
* Fixed an issue that occurred after an agent configured their own hours of operation settings in the agent adapter. Those settings didn't appear for administrators in the agent's user profile on the <strong>Settings &gt; Users &amp; Team &gt; Manage Users &amp; Teams</strong> page. This prevented the administrator from making other edits to the agent's profile without overwriting the agent's hours of operation settings.
* Fixed an issue where CRM tickets weren't created for some calls.
* Fixed an issue where outbound SIP calls incorrectly appended data parameters, causing calls to fail.
* Fixed a Web SDK security vulnerability associated with DOMPurify.
* Fixed an issue where chat metadata wasn't saved to external storage. This occurred when an end-user ended a chat after escalating from a virtual agent but before being connected to a human agent.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>This release addresses numerous issues, including problems with virtual agent configuration, call redirection errors, inaccurate reporting data, and various user interface glitches for HubSpot and Windows 11 users. It also resolves issues related to SMS chat sessions, SDK data display, link conversion, missed call callbacks, predictive outbound campaigns, and recording message settings. Additionally, fixes were implemented for customized greetings, call details display, agent status visibility, queue search functionality, duration reporting, team assignments, agent inactivity timeouts, custom role permissions, agent hours of operation, CRM ticket creation, outbound SIP call failures, a Web SDK security vulnerability, and chat metadata saving.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Bug Fixes and Improvements</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-21:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Advanced reporting dashboards version 3.40</strong></p>
<p>We've released version 3.40 of the advanced reporting dashboards.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>New version 3.40 of advanced reporting dashboards released.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Advanced reporting dashboards</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-21:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>New Agent Preference table in the Agent Availability dashboard</strong></p>
<p>We've added a new <strong>Agent Preference</strong> table to the <strong>Agent Availability</strong> dashboard. This table can help you ensure that queues have properly skilled agents assigned to them. It can also help identify agents who improperly change their availability filters. For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/dashboards-agent-availability">Agent availability dashboard</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new Agent Preference table is now available in the Agent Availability dashboard. This feature helps ensure correct agent skills are assigned to queues and identifies improper use of availability filters.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Agent Preference Table Added</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-21:feature:2</id>
    <published>2025-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>New Audit Log dashboard</strong></p>
<p>We've added a new <strong>Audit log</strong> dashboard to help you track changes to the configuration of your instance. The dashboard tracks changes to the settings on the <strong>Developer Settings</strong> page, and displays information such as the type of change, who made the change, and when. This dashboard is similar in format to the advanced reporting dashboards, but you can't save it as a new dashboard. You access the <strong>Audit Log</strong> dashboard from the <strong>Settings</strong> menu. For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/dashboards-audit-log">Audit log dashboard</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Track configuration changes with the new Audit Log dashboard. See who changed what and when, with a format similar to advanced reporting.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Audit Log Dashboard</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-10-21:fixed:3</id>
    <published>2025-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We addressed the following issues in this release:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue that caused the <strong>Agent Activity Timeline</strong> dashboard to display inaccurate or incomplete data.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue on the <strong>Virtual Agent - Calls</strong> dashboard where the <strong>Virtual Agent Name</strong> and <strong>Queue</strong> filters didn't display available values.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue on the <strong>Dispositions - Chats</strong> dashboard that prevented the <strong>Agent Email</strong>, <strong>Agent ID</strong>, and <strong>Location</strong> filters from displaying available values.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue on the <strong>Virtual Agent - Chats</strong> dashboard that prevented the <strong>Virtual Agent Name</strong> filter from displaying available values.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue on the <strong>Virtual Agent - Chats</strong> dashboard where the <strong>Date</strong> filter was incorrectly labeled <strong>Time Range</strong>.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue on the <strong>Abandons - Calls</strong> dashboard where <strong>Customer ANI</strong> values weren't appearing in the <strong>Queue Abandon Details</strong> and <strong>IVR Abandon Details</strong> tables despite the customer signing the waiver.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue on the <strong>Agent Activity Timeline</strong> dashboard where the <strong>Agent Name</strong> filter wasn't working properly.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>This release resolves several issues, including inaccurate data on the Agent Activity Timeline dashboard and problems with filters on various dashboards such as Virtual Agent - Calls, Dispositions - Chats, and Virtual Agent - Chats. Additionally, it corrects an issue with the Date filter's label and ensures Customer ANI values are displayed correctly in abandon details tables.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Agent Activity Timeline and Dashboard Filters</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-09-25:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Web SDK version 2 will be shut down on June 26, 2026</strong></p>
<p>On June 26, 2025, we announced the launch of <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/release-notes#June_26_2025">Web SDK version 3</a>. Starting on <strong>June 26, 2026</strong>, the web SDK v2 will no longer function. Be sure to <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/web-sdk-v3-upgrade">update your website</a> to use the web SDK v3 before that date to avoid breaking your integration with the web SDK. We are no longer adding new features to the web SDK v2.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Web SDK v2 will be shut down on June 26, 2026. Update to v3 to avoid integration issues.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Web SDK v2 Shutdown</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-09-04:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Agent desktop is GA</strong></p>
<p>Agent desktop is now <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products?e=48754805&amp;hl=en#product-launch-stages">generally available (GA)</a>. Agent desktop is a customizable interface that provides agents quick access to the information and tools they need to handle customer sessions. The desktop layout includes the agent adapter as well as configurable panels that display information or tools. You can configure a distinct desktop layout for each session type: inbound calls, outbound calls, or chats. You can then configure which desktop layout that an agent sees when they answer an inbound call, place an outbound call, or handle a chat. You can also configure announcements to communicate updates, alerts, and other important information directly to agents. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/agent-desktop-overview">Agent desktop</a>.</p>
<p>The agent desktop provides the following capabilities:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Create desktop layouts</strong>. With agent desktop, you can create customized desktop layouts for different use cases for your human agents. These include receiving inbound calls, placing outbound calls, and handling chat sessions. Your layouts can contain call adapters, chat adapters, and a wide variety of panels for other capabilities such as live transcripts, knowledge assist, disposition codes, and session data feeds. You can also configure custom panels to use as widgets that you can drag into panels. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/agent-desktop-create-desktop-layouts">Create desktop layouts</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Configure custom panels</strong>. A custom panel displays one or more URLs for external resources. These can be documentation, tools, or other resources. A custom panel appears as a widget in the desktop layout builder. Then, when you create desktop layouts, you can drag widgets into panels. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/agent-desktop-configure-widgets">Configure custom panels</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Use widgets</strong>. Widgets are containers of specific functionality that you can drag into panels in the desktop layout builder. The desktop layout builder comes with a number of pre-defined widgets, such as <strong>Session Data Feed</strong>, <strong>Disposition Codes and Notes</strong>, <strong>Knowledge Assist</strong>, and <strong>Live Transcript</strong>.</li>
<li><strong>Configure desktop layouts for agents</strong>. You can configure which desktop layout that agents see when they answer an inbound call, place an outbound call, or handle a chat. You can configure this globally, at the queue level, and at the team level. Queue-level layout settings take priority over global settings. Team-level settings take priority over both queue-level settings and default settings. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/agent-desktop-set-desktop-layouts">Configure desktop layouts for agents</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Configure announcements</strong>. With announcements, you can communicate updates, alerts, and other important information directly to agents. Announcements appear in the agent desktop as notification banners that persist until the agent dismisses them. Announcements also appear in the agent's announcement list. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/agent-desktop-configure-announcements">Configure announcements</a>.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Agent desktop is now generally available. This customizable interface provides agents with quick access to necessary information and tools, featuring configurable panels and layouts for different session types like calls and chats. It also supports announcements for direct communication with agents.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Agent Desktop Now Generally Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-09-02:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Mobile SDK 2.14 is released</strong></p>
<p>Mobile SDK 2.14 includes the following updates:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Android SDK and iOS SDK:</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Support for virtual agent to virtual agent chat transfers by queue.</p>
</li>
<li>Support for hiding the download transcript button in the options menu, the post-chat screen, or both. For the Android SDK, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/android-sdk-guide#sdk-configuration">SDK configuration</a>. For the iOS SDK, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/ios-sdk-guide#show-or-hide-download-transcript-button">Show or hide the download transcript button</a>.</li>
<li>Improved accessibility, including better navigation and screen reader support.</li>
<li>
<p>Android SDK:</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Support for hiding the SDK using the <code>Ujet.hideSDK()</code> method. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/android-sdk-guide#hide-sdk">Hide the SDK</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>New event types: <code>MessageLinkClicked</code> and <code>QuickReplyClicked</code>. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/android-sdk-guide#UUID-b0019caa-2311-8ca3-64d7-f181ea921d77">Event Notifications</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>To support the new virtual agent chat transfer capabilities of this release, we've added a new configuration setting in the Google Cloud CCaaS portal. You can use this setting to hide transfer system messages in chat sessions with virtual agent to virtual agent transfers.</p>
<p><strong>Administrators</strong>: In the <strong>Settings &gt; Chat &gt; Web &amp; Mobile Chat Settings</strong> pane, there's a new <strong>Transfers</strong> checkbox.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/va-to-va-transfers#hide-transfer-messages-in-chat-sessions">Hide transfer messages in chat sessions</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The latest Mobile SDK 2.14 release introduces enhanced features for both Android and iOS platforms. Key updates include support for virtual agent to virtual agent chat transfers, improved accessibility, and options to customize the user interface by hiding certain elements like the download transcript button. The Android SDK also gains new methods for hiding the SDK and additional event types for better interaction tracking. Administrators can configure these new transfer capabilities through the Google Cloud CCaaS portal.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Mobile SDK 2.14 Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-29:fixed:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fixed an issue where the Android SDK wouldn't minimize when an end-user clicked a deep link.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Android SDK now correctly minimizes when a user clicks a deep link.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Android SDK minimized</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-27:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Portal version 3.39 pre-release notes</strong></p>
<p>Here are the pre-release notes for portal version 3.39. When we release version 3.39, we expect the new capabilities to be as shown here.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>New capabilities are available in the upcoming portal version 3.39. Review the pre-release notes for details.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Portal Version 3.39 Pre-Release Notes</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-27:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Destination queue name and session history is available in the agent adapter</strong></p>
<p>The agent adapter now displays the destination queue during transfers and deflections for IVR calls. The agent adapter also displays transfer history in the <strong>Call details</strong> and <strong>Chat details</strong> tabs.</p>
<p>User experience changes:</p>
<ul>
<li>The <strong>Call details</strong> and <strong>Chat details</strong> tabs in the agent adapter have a new <strong>Transfer History</strong> section.</li>
<li>The chat pane in the chat adapter has a new <strong>Transfers</strong> button that opens the <strong>Transfer History</strong> pane.</li>
</ul>
<p>Administrators: There's a new checkbox at <strong>Settings &gt; Operation Management &gt; Transfer history</strong> for turning on transfer history in the agent adapter.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The agent adapter now displays the destination queue during call transfers and deflections. Additionally, transfer history is available in the Call details and Chat details tabs, with a new Transfers button in the chat pane for easy access. Administrators can enable this feature in the Transfer history settings.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Agent adapter now shows destination queue and transfer history</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-27:feature:2</id>
    <published>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Improved controls over the ordering of key-value pairs in the agent adapter and CRM records</strong></p>
<p>Google Cloud CCaaS has improved controls over the ordering of the key-value pairs that appear in the agent adapter and in CRM records. Here's how the ordering controls work:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Virtual agents</strong>: When you configure session variables, you can use the new <code>display_order_in_adapter</code> property to specify the order that the session variables appear in the agent adapter and in CRM records.</li>
<li><strong>Web SDK</strong>: Web SDK custom data is displayed in the agent adapter and CRM records in the order that the key-value pairs appear in the JSON custom data file.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>New controls allow users to specify the order of key-value pairs in agent adapters and CRM records.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Improved Key-Value Pair Ordering</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-27:feature:3</id>
    <published>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Virtual agents for the SMS channel</strong></p>
<p>Virtual agents are now available for the SMS channel. This lets you create virtual agents and assign them to SMS queues, offering virtual agent support to end-users in SMS chat sessions.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Virtual agents can now be used for SMS channels, allowing you to provide support through SMS chat sessions.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Virtual agents for SMS</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-27:feature:4</id>
    <published>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Search in the email channel</strong></p>
<p>Agents can now search for emails in the agent adapter by keyword, session ID, or subject.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Agents can now search for emails in the agent adapter by keyword, session ID, or subject.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Search emails by keyword, session ID, or subject</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-27:feature:5</id>
    <published>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Cancel scheduled calls with the callback calls API</strong></p>
<p>You can now use the callback calls API to cancel a single scheduled callback call or a list of calls.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now cancel single or multiple scheduled callback calls using the callback calls API.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cancel scheduled calls</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-27:feature:6</id>
    <published>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Mid-session authentication is supported by all CRM types</strong></p>
<p>Mid-session authentication is supported by all CRM types, not just custom CRMs. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/mid-session-authentication-apps-api">Mid-Session authentication by API</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Mid-session authentication is now available for all CRM types, expanding its compatibility beyond custom CRMs.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Mid-session authentication support for all CRM types</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-27:feature:7</id>
    <published>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>New advanced reporting dashboards</strong></p>
<p>The following new advanced reporting dashboard is available:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Deflections</strong>. Get deflection information by queue and for your entire contact center. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/dashboards-deflections">Deflections dashboards</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Agent activity timeline</strong>. See the historical activity for an agent.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Check out the new advanced reporting dashboards for Deflections and Agent activity timeline.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Reporting Dashboards</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-27:feature:8</id>
    <published>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Advanced reporting dashboard updates</strong></p>
<p>We've made the following updates to the advanced reporting dashboards:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Queue Group Dashboards All dashboard</strong>: The tiles and tables on this dashboard have been replaced with the following tables:</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Queue Group Performance Calls</strong>: displays detailed performance information for calls by queue group.</p>
</li>
<li><strong>Queue Group Performance Chats</strong>: displays detailed performance information for chats by queue group.</li>
<li><strong>Virtual agent dashboards</strong>: On both the <strong>Virtual Agent Dashboard Calls</strong> and <strong>Virtual Agent Dashboard Chats</strong> dashboards, the virtual agent metrics table contains a new <strong>Interaction Outcome</strong> column.</li>
<li><strong>All Interactions - Chat dashboard</strong>: In the <strong>All Chat Interactions (Historical)</strong> table, if you configure chat transcript storage for your CRM, the values in the <strong>Chat ID</strong> column become links to the chat transcripts.</li>
<li><strong>Additional dashboards with advanced capabilities</strong>: the following dashboards now appear on the <strong>Advanced Reporting Landing Page</strong>. This means you can use them to create new custom dashboards or create Looks to link to custom dashboards.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Performance</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Dispositions / Calls</strong></li>
<li><strong>Dispositions / Chats</strong></li>
<li><strong>Deflections / Calls</strong></li>
<li><strong>Deflections / Chats</strong></li>
<li><strong>CSAT / Calls</strong></li>
<li><strong>CSAT / Chats</strong></li>
<li><strong>Co-browse / Calls</strong></li>
<li><strong>Co-browse / Chats</strong></li>
<li><strong>Failed / Calls</strong></li>
<li><strong>Failed / Chats</strong></li>
<li><strong>Missed / Calls</strong></li>
<li><strong>Missed / Chats</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Agent Reporting</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Agent Activity Timeline</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Monitoring Dashboards</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Calls Connected</strong></li>
<li><strong>Chats Connected</strong></li>
<li><strong>Calls Queued</strong></li>
<li><strong>Chats Queued</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/dashboards-advanced-capabilities">Advanced capabilities</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>We have updated the advanced reporting dashboards with new tables for queue group performance in calls and chats. The virtual agent dashboards now include an "Interaction Outcome" column, and chat IDs can link to transcripts if storage is configured. Additionally, several new dashboards with advanced capabilities for performance, agent reporting, and monitoring are now available on the Advanced Reporting Landing Page.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New updates to advanced reporting dashboards</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-27:fixed:9</id>
    <published>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following issues were addressed in this release:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where incoming chats took precedence over the in-progress chat.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>User experience change</strong>: When a new chat appears in the agent adapter, it no longer takes focus away from the in-progress chat. The in-progress retains focus.
* Fixed a web SDK issue where sensitive data sent by an end-user was redacted for both the end-user and the agent, instead of just for the agent.
* Fixed an issue where the contact list in the agent adapter wouldn't load the full list of contacts.
* Fixed an issue where an agent clicking an email in the agent adapter returned an <strong>Email Not Found</strong> error.
* Fixed an issue where managers assigned to multiple teams were unable to view agent statistics for every team they were assigned to.
* Fixed an issue for ServiceNow users where <code>call_duration</code> was using the earliest <code>connected_at</code> time instead of the latest <code>connected_at</code> time, causing call durations to appear longer than they actually were.
* Fixed an issue in the <strong>Settings &gt; Developer Settings &gt; External Storage</strong> pane where language checkboxes were associated with the <strong>Co-browse Recordings</strong> checkbox instead of the <strong>Session Data Feed</strong> checkbox.</p>
<p><strong>Administrators</strong>: In the <strong>Settings &gt; Developer Settings &gt; External Storage</strong> pane, the languages checkboxes have moved from the <strong>Co-browse Recordings</strong> checkbox to the <strong>Session Data Feed</strong> checkbox.
* Fixed an issue where agent-initiated outbound calls were using the default number for the selected queue instead of the number chosen by the agent.
* Fixed an issue where the downloaded session chat data report contained an extra quotation mark.
* Fixed an issue where users received an email telling them to create a password after Single Sign-On (SSO) was turned on.
* Fixed an issue where SSO configuration settings in the user's instance were deleted after they turned off SSO.
* Fixed an issue where an administrator couldn't configure agent status restrictions without exposing them to agents.
* Fixed an issue where custom contact lists could only be replaced, and not removed, after they were assigned to a team.
* Fixed an issue where the inheritance indicator and <strong>Reset to parent</strong> button was missing from the queue level <strong>Contact List Management</strong> pane.
* Fixed an issue where the SMS and Web chat availability preferences in the agent adapter were the reverse of how they were configured.
* Fixed an issue where queue transfer restrictions were not saved after being configured.
* Fixed an issue that occurred when a user attempted to name a new queue. The name field abruptly lost focus after the first character, forcing the user to enter the queue name again.
* Fixed an issue where creating an instance would time out and fail.
* Fixed an issue that prevented reports from being downloaded.
* Fixed an issue where the chat history for blended SMS sessions failed to save.
* Fixed an issue where the <strong>Transfer failed</strong> message didn't appear. This occurred when an agent failed to pick up a transferred call before the transferred call expiration time expired.
* Fixed an issue where IVR call recordings failed to save or were corrupted. This resulted in recordings that were only one second long, were saved in the wrong format, or weren't saved at all.
* Fixed an issue where completed chat sessions appeared in the chats waiting area of agent desktop.
* Fixed an issue for CRM users with voicemails that are attached directly to tickets. An incorrect "External Storage must be configured" warning appeared when configuring voicemail options for IVR queues.
* Fixed an issue where transfer restrictions that were configured and saved for a web queue did not appear correctly the next time the <strong>Transfer Restrictions</strong> pane for that queue was viewed.
* Fixed an issue where the unread message count in the chat pane was inconsistent when viewing it from multiple browser tabs.
* Fixed an issue in virtual assistant reporting where the <code>finish_reason</code> property was incorrectly assigned to the <code>undefined</code> value. Now the <code>finish_reason</code> property is assigned to descriptive values that describe the reason for the conclusion of the chat session.
* Fixed an issue where PDF transcripts of chat sessions contained malformed links.
* Fixed an issue in historical reports where the fields in the <strong>Failed Reason Description</strong> column were blank.
* Fixed an issue where CSAT scores were missing from some advanced reporting dashboards.
* Fixed an issue for HubSpot users that caused long delays in case creation for inbound calls.
* Fixed an issue where the photo and video files that the agent provided in pre-session Smart Actions didn't appear in the CRM.
* Fixed an issue where agents in <code>Unavailable</code> status couldn't see waiting web chats.
* Fixed an issue where HTML was not rendering properly in virtual agent messages in the agent adapter
* Fixed an issue where agents were not switching into <code>Wrap-up Exceeded</code> status after a breakthrough call.
* Fixed an agent desktop issue where administrators were unable to assign announcements to some teams or agents.
* Fixed an agent desktop issue where agents couldn't copy text to the clipboard from an agent desktop custom panel.
* Fixed an agent desktop issue where the term "Anonymous User" wasn't being translated into French.
* Fixed an issue where the <code>UJET_ID</code> and <code>ANI</code> variables weren't passed correctly for SIP calls.
* Fixed an issue where the chat adapter froze when agents switched between chats.
* Fixed an issue on the <strong>Agents</strong> page of the Google Cloud CCaaS portal where administrators couldn't switch between session types.
* Fixed an issue where a newly added Agent Assist platform displayed as <code>Invalid</code> even though it was valid.
* Fixed an issue for Salesforce users where the call button didn't work when an agent attempted to call a number that was attached to a record for a previous call.
* Fixed an issue where audio files with accented characters in their file names failed to play back when using a storage proxy.
* Fixed an agent desktop issue where the <code>UJET_ID</code> variable in the custom URL for a custom panel wasn't being passed correctly.
* Fixed an issue where calls originating from a native campaign generated two CRM tickets for the same interaction.
* Fixed latency issues with web SDK Telnyx calls.
* Fixed an issue where outbound Bring Your Own Carrier (BYOC) calls used a number other than the one agents selected in the agent adapter.
* Fixed a Telnyx chatbot worker failure issue where background jobs related to call processing and chatbot escalations were failing and consuming excessive system resources.
* Fixed an issue where calls to the bulk user upload endpoint returned a success status even when the uploads failed.
* Fixed an issue in the chat waiting field of the agent desktop when multiple chats were in wrap-up. Instead of displaying <strong>Wrap-up in progress</strong> for all sessions in wrap-up, some sessions displayed <strong>Auto answered</strong>.
* Fixed an issue in the queue group dashboard where the <strong>Callbacks waiting</strong> tile incorrectly included callbacks that were completed, abandoned, or failed.
* Fixed an issue that caused inbound calls to disconnect if they were routed to an agent with a disabled microphone.
* Fixed an issue for HubSpot users where logging the "call started" event (<code>create_activity</code>) in the ticket was delayed.
* Fixed an issue that prevented transferred calls from being routed to available agents.
* Fixed an issue in the agent adapter for French (Canada) where words weren't translated or were translated incorrectly.
* Fixed an issue in call queue reporting where the Failed Reason Description for voice-scheduled mobile calls was not appearing.
* Fixed an advanced reporting issue where CSAT ratings were not appearing correctly when creating custom dashboards.
* Fixed an advanced reporting issue where callbacks waiting metrics didn't match in the following dashboards: <strong>Queue Groups Dashboard Calls</strong> and <strong>Queued Calls Status Dashboard</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>This release addresses numerous issues, including chat focus, data redaction, contact list loading, email errors, manager statistics, call duration accuracy, external storage settings, outbound call numbers, chat data reports, password resets, SSO configurations, agent status restrictions, custom contact lists, queue settings, SMS/Web chat availability, transfer restrictions, queue naming, instance creation timeouts, report downloads, chat history saving, transfer failure messages, IVR recording issues, completed chats in waiting areas, voicemail warnings, transfer restriction display, unread message counts, virtual assistant reporting, PDF transcript links, historical report fields, CSAT scores, HubSpot case creation, CRM photo/video display, agent status visibility, HTML rendering, agent status transitions, announcement assignments, clipboard functionality, French translations, SIP call variables, chat adapter freezing, session type switching, Agent Assist platform display, Salesforce call button issues, audio file playback, custom panel variables, CRM ticket creation, Telnyx call latency, BYOC call numbers, Telnyx chatbot worker failures, bulk user upload status, wrap-up status display, queue group dashboard callbacks, inbound call disconnections, HubSpot call logging, transferred call routing, French translation in agent adapter, call queue reporting, and advanced reporting metrics.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Bug Fixes and Improvements</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-20:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Version 3.37 is released</strong></p>
<p>All release notes published on this date are part of version 3.37.</p>
<p>The timing of the update to your instance depends on the deployment schedule that you have chosen. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/deployment-schedules">Deployment schedules</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Version 3.37 is released. All release notes published on this date are part of version 3.37.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: New version released</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-20:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Restrict email transfers</strong></p>
<p>You can now configure your instance to prevent users with the agent role from transferring email sessions to other agents. Agents can still assign unassigned emails to themselves, and users with the manager role can still transfer email sessions from agent to agent.</p>
<p>Administrators: There's a new <strong>Transfer Restrictions</strong> pane at <strong>Settings &gt; Queue &gt; Email &gt; Edit / View &gt; [queue] &gt; Transfer Restrictions &gt; Configure</strong>.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/prevent-email-reassignment">Prevent email reassignment</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Restrict email transfers for agents.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Email Transfer Restrictions</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-20:feature:2</id>
    <published>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Skip the connecting message playback</strong></p>
<p>You can now configure your instance to skip playback of the connecting message when calls are connected to agents.</p>
<p>Administrators: The <strong>Settings &gt; Call &gt; Call Details</strong> pane contains a new <strong>Skip the Connecting Message playback</strong> checkbox.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/call-settings#configure-global-call-settings">Configure global call settings</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Skip connecting message playback for agent calls.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Connecting Message Playback Skipped</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-20:feature:3</id>
    <published>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Workforce Management terminology update</strong></p>
<p>We've updated the terminology in the Workforce Management interface to align with Google Cloud CCaaS terminology. For example, we've changed "supervisor" to "manager", "employee" to "agent", and "Supervisor Portal" to "Manager Portal".</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Workforce Management terminology update</summary>
    <title>Feature: Workforce Management terminology update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-20:feature:4</id>
    <published>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Generative knowledge assist is available in Agent Desktop</strong></p>
<p>Generative knowledge assist is now available in Agent Desktop as a widget that you can drag into a desktop panel.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/agent-desktop-create-desktop-layouts">Create desktop layouts</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Generative knowledge assist is now available in Agent Desktop.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Generative Knowledge Assist in Agent Desktop</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-20:feature:5</id>
    <published>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Generative knowledge assist is available in the agent adapter</strong></p>
<p>Generative knowledge assist is now available in the agent adapter.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Generative knowledge assist is available in the agent adapter.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Generative Knowledge Assist</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-20:feature:6</id>
    <published>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Web SDK version 3.37</strong></p>
<p>Starting with version 3.37, web SDK releases align with portal releases and share the same version number.</p>
<p>Web SDK version 3.37 includes the following update: we've improved the accessibily of the web SDK to be in compliance with the European Accessibility Act.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Web SDK version 3.37 improves accessibility for compliance with the European Accessibility Act.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Web SDK 3.37 Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-20:feature:7</id>
    <published>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>New advanced reporting dashboards</strong></p>
<p>The following new advanced reporting dashboards are available:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Missed interactions</strong>. Get data on missed interactions to help you optimize operations. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/dashboards-missed-interactions">Missed interactions dashboards</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Failed sessions</strong>. Get insight into why your sessions are failing. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/dashboards-failed-sessions">Failed sessions dashboards</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Screen share</strong>. Get data on your agents' Screen Share interactions with end-users. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/dashboards-screenshare">Screen shared dashboards</a>.</li>
<li><strong>CSAT</strong>. Get insights into the customer satisfaction (CSAT) ratings that end-users give to their sessions with agents. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/dashboards-csat">CSAT dashboards</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Dispositions</strong>. Get disposition information to gain insights into common end-user issues and concerns. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/dashboards-dispositions">Dispositions dashboards</a>.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>New advanced reporting dashboards are now available to help you optimize operations, gain insights into failing sessions, track agent screen sharing, understand customer satisfaction, and identify common end-user issues.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Reporting Dashboards</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-20:fixed:8</id>
    <published>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following issues were addressed in this release:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where a blank error message box appeared in the agent adapter when a call connected.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the notification icon for a new message or event in the chat adapter didn't clear after the agent viewed the message or event.</li>
<li>~~Fixed a Conversational Insights issue where conversation recordings were split into a file for the human agent segment and a file for the virtual agent segment. Now all call segments are aggregated into a single recording file, which is more useful for conversational analysis.~~</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a single call was being reported as two separate calls after the following occurred: (1) A call was escalated from a virtual agent to a queue, (2) An agent clicked <strong>Answer</strong> in the agent adapter, and (3) The end-user hung up before the countdown was complete.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where agents were unsure whether their action of declining a call was taking effect. Now, after an agent declines a call, the <strong>Decline</strong> button changes to <strong>Declining...</strong>, the <strong>Answer</strong> button is deactivated, and a message displays indicating that the call was declined.</li>
<li>Fixed the message that appeared in the agent adapter when an agent left a multi-party session. Instead of saying that the session will be tranferred to the remaining agents(s), the message now says that the session will be transferred to the remaining participant(s). This is because the remaining participants might not be agents.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where administators were unable to monitor or barge into calls.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the <strong>Decline</strong> button didn't display or didn't work correctly in the agent adapter when the following occurred: (1) An agent was in an active call, and (2) The agent received a second call on their direct number.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where clearing the <strong>Play Call Recording Message</strong> checkbox in <strong>Settings &gt; Call &gt; Call Details</strong> pane didn't work if the queue was configured for human agents and virtual agents or virtual agents only.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the <strong>Transfer failed</strong> error message failed to appear in the call adapter after the following occured: a transferred call wasn't answered before the unanswered call expiration time expired.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where an agent on a team that was assigned to a queue wasn't able to select their desired queue to make an outbound call. We also improved the text at <strong>Settings &gt; Call &gt; Call Details &gt; Queue Selection for Outbound Call</strong> to better describe the call adapter behavior.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the missed chat message didn't appear after the missed chat threshold expired.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where end-users were unable to download chat transcripts containing special characters, emoji, or redacted content.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with the web SDK where configuring custom system messages with empty quotes or NULL values didn't fully suppress the messages.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with the web SDK where some non-English characters in downloaded chat transcripts were appearing as question marks.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in Hubspot where recordings of transferred calls were failing to save.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in Salesforce where the <strong>Call</strong> button in the call adapter wasn't working for outbound calls to a phone number that was associated with a previous record.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the data in reports didn't match the data in the dashboards.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where virtual agent calls using Dialogflow CX failed, ending unexpectedly.</li>
<li>Fixed two cross-site scripting vulnerabilites in the agent adapter.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where deltacast selected the agent with the longest time in the Available status instead of the agent with the longest time since their last customer interaction.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where escalations from a virtual agent to a human agent failed, and audio from the last agent response before human agent escalation was truncated.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where transcriptions weren't being created for IVR calls.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where agents could become stuck in wrap-up status, particularly with concurrent calls or quick callbacks.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>This release addresses various issues, including problems with error messages, notification icons, call handling, agent status visibility, and data discrepancies. Enhancements were made to call recording aggregation, agent status updates, and multi-party session messaging. Specific fixes were implemented for chat transcript downloads, web SDK behavior, and integrations with Hubspot and Salesforce. Additionally, security vulnerabilities and issues with virtual agent escalations and call transcriptions have been resolved.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Bug Fixes and Improvements</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-13:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Check the version number of your instance</strong></p>
<p>You can now check the version number of your instance and compare it with the version numbers of the updates and patches that Google announces in these release notes. In this way you can know which capabilities are available in your instance. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/get-started#check_the_version_number_of_your_instance">Check the version number of your instance</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Check your instance version.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Instance Version Check</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-08-11:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Availability in three additional regions</strong></p>
<p>Google Cloud CCaaS is now available in the following three additional regions:</p>
<ul>
<li>northamerica-northeast2 (Toronto)</li>
<li>us-east4 (Virginia)</li>
<li>me-west1 (Tel Aviv)</li>
</ul>
<p>In each of these regions, Workforce Management is available and advanced reporting isn't available. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/localities#regions">Google Cloud regions</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Google Cloud CCaaS is now available in three additional regions: Toronto, Virginia, and Tel Aviv. Workforce management is available in these regions, but advanced reporting is not.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: New regions available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-07-24:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Mobile SDK patch 2.13.1 is released</strong></p>
<p>This patch fixes an issue where the Android SDK didn't support deep linking in the customizable link format.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Mobile SDK patch 2.13.1 released, fixing deep linking for Android.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: SDK Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-07-10:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Portal version 3.37 pre-release notes</strong></p>
<p>Here are the pre-release notes for portal version 3.37. When we release version 3.37, we expect the new capabilities to be as shown here.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Here are the pre-release notes for portal version 3.37. When we release version 3.37, we expect the new capabilities to be as shown here.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Portal version 3.37 pre-release notes</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-07-10:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Restrict email transfers</strong></p>
<p>You can now configure your instance to prevent users with the agent role from transferring email sessions to other agents. Agents can still assign unassigned emails to themselves, and users with the manager role can still transfer email sessions from agent to agent.</p>
<p>Administrators: There's a new <strong>Transfer Restrictions</strong> pane at <strong>Settings &gt; Queue &gt; Email &gt; Edit / View &gt; [queue] &gt; Transfer Restrictions &gt; Configure</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now restrict email transfers for agents. Managers can still transfer sessions, and agents can still self-assign unassigned emails. Admins can configure this in the Transfer Restrictions pane.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Restrict email transfers</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-07-10:feature:2</id>
    <published>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Skip the connecting message playback</strong></p>
<p>You can now configure your instance to skip playback of the connecting message when calls are connected to agents.</p>
<p>Administrators: The <strong>Settings &gt; Call &gt; Call Details</strong> pane contains a new <strong>Skip the Connecting Message playback</strong> checkbox.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now configure your instance to skip the playback of the connecting message when calls are connected to agents. This setting can be found in the Call Details pane.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Skip Connecting Message Playback</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-07-10:feature:3</id>
    <published>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Workforce Management terminology update</strong></p>
<p>We've updated the terminology in the Workforce Management interface to align with Google Cloud CCaaS terminology. For example, we've changed "supervisor" to "manager", "employee" to "agent", and "Supervisor Portal" to "Manager Portal".</p>]]></content>
    <summary>We've updated Workforce Management terminology to align with Google Cloud CCaaS standards. Key changes include renaming 'supervisor' to 'manager' and 'employee' to 'agent', along with updating 'Supervisor Portal' to 'Manager Portal'.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Workforce Management Terminology Updated</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-07-10:feature:4</id>
    <published>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Generative knowledge assist is available in Agent Desktop</strong></p>
<p>Generative knowledge assist is now available in Agent Desktop as a widget that you can drag into a desktop panel.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/agent-desktop-create-desktop-layouts">Create desktop panels</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Generative knowledge assist is now available in Agent Desktop as a widget that can be added to desktop panels.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Generative knowledge assist in Agent Desktop</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-07-10:feature:5</id>
    <published>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Generative knowledge assist is available in the agent adapter</strong></p>
<p>Generative knowledge assist is now available in the agent adapter.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Generative knowledge assist is now available in the agent adapter.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Generative knowledge assist in agent adapter</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-07-10:feature:6</id>
    <published>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Web SDK version 3.37</strong></p>
<p>Starting with version 3.37, web SDK releases align with portal releases and share the same version number.</p>
<p>Web SDK version 3.37 includes the following update: we've improved the accessibily of the web SDK to be in compliance with the European Accessibility Act.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Web SDK is updated to version 3.37, aligning with portal releases. This version includes accessibility improvements to comply with the European Accessibility Act.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Web SDK 3.37: Accessibility Improvements</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-07-10:fixed:7</id>
    <published>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following issues were addressed in this release:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where a blank error message box appeared in the agent adapter when a call connected.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the notification icon for a new message or event in the chat adapter didn't clear after the agent viewed the message or event.</li>
<li>Fixed a Conversational Insights issue where conversation recordings were split into a file for the human agent segment and a file for the virtual agent segment. Now all call segments are aggregated into a single recording file, which is more useful for conversational analysis.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a single call was being reported as two separate calls after the following occurred: (1) A call was escalated from a virtual agent to a queue, (2) An agent clicked <strong>Answer</strong> in the agent adapter, and (3) The end-user hung up before the countdown was complete.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where agents were unsure whether their action of declining a call was taking effect. Now, after an agent declines a call, the <strong>Decline</strong> button changes to <strong>Declining...</strong>, the <strong>Answer</strong> button is deactivated, and a message displays indicating that the call was declined.</li>
<li>Fixed the message that appeared in the agent adapter when an agent left a multi-party session. Instead of saying that the session will be tranferred to the remaining agents(s), the message now says that the session will be transferred to the remaining participant(s). This is because the remaining participants might not be agents.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where administators were unable to monitor or barge into calls.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the <strong>Decline</strong> button didn't display or didn't work correctly in the agent adapter when the following occurred: (1) An agent was in an active call, and (2) The agent received a second call on their direct number.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where clearing the <strong>Play Call Recording Message</strong> checkbox in <strong>Settings &gt; Call &gt; Call Details</strong> pane didn't work if the queue was configured for human agents and virtual agents or virtual agents only.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the <strong>Transfer failed</strong> error message failed to appear in the call adapter after the following occured: a transferred call wasn't answered before the unanswered call expiration time expired.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where an agent on a team that was assigned to a queue wasn't able to select their desired queue to make an outbound call. We also improved the text at <strong>Settings &gt; Call &gt; Call Details &gt; Queue Selection for Outbound Call</strong> to better describe the call adapter behavior.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the missed chat message didn't appear after the missed chat threshold expired.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where end-users were unable to download chat transcripts containing special characters, emoji, or redacted content.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with the web SDK where configuring custom system messages with empty quotes or NULL values didn't fully suppress the messages.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with the web SDK where some non-English characters in downloaded chat transcripts were appearing as question marks.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in Hubspot where recordings of transferred calls were failing to save.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in Salesforce where the <strong>Call</strong> button in the call adapter wasn't working for outbound calls to a phone number that was associated with a previous record.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the data in reports didn't match the data in the dashboards.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where virtual agent calls using Dialogflow CX failed, ending unexpectedly.</li>
<li>Fixed two cross-site scripting vulnerabilites in the agent adapter.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where deltacast selected the agent with the longest time in the Available status instead of the agent with the longest time since their last customer interaction.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where escalations from a virtual agent to a human agent failed, and audio from the last agent response before human agent escalation was truncated.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where transcriptions weren't being created for IVR calls.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>This release addresses various issues, including problems with error messages, notification icons, call recordings, call reporting, and the agent adapter's functionality. Enhancements were made to call handling, chat transcript downloads, and data consistency across reports and dashboards. Security vulnerabilities were also resolved.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Resolved Issues and Enhancements in Recent Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-07-08:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Mobile SDK 2.13 is released</strong></p>
<p>Mobile SDK 2.13 includes the following updates:</p>
<ul>
<li>End-users can download chat transcripts to their devices during a session or after a session ends. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/chat-transcripts#download_chat_transcripts_using_the_web_sdk_and_mobile_sdks">Download chat transcripts using the web SDK and mobile SDKs</a>.</li>
<li>
<p>The user experience with post-session virtual assistants is improved in the following ways:</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>You can configure an opt-in banner to appear for the post-session virtual assistant experience.</p>
</li>
<li>The user interface makes it easier for an end-user to know whether they are speaking to a human agent or a post-session virtual agent.</li>
<li>End-users can navigate the user interface using keyboard shortcuts in conformance with the W3C Web Content Accessibility Guidelines.</li>
<li>You can configure your instance to let end-users skip customer satisfaction surveys.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>The latest release of Mobile SDK 2.13 introduces new features for end-users, including the ability to download chat transcripts and improved navigation with keyboard shortcuts. Additionally, administrators can now configure opt-in banners for post-session virtual assistants, provide clearer identification of virtual agents, and allow users to skip customer satisfaction surveys.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Mobile SDK 2.13 Release</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-07-08:fixed:1</id>
    <published>2025-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following issues were addressed in this release:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Android SDK:</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Fixed an issue where system messages containing an empty space were being sent, even though the message strings were set to NULL.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>iOS SDK:</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Fixed an issue where the "Skip the human agent" button was displayed after an end-user was transferred to a virtual agent.</p>
</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a notification sound played for new chat messages despite the end-user disabling notifications.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>This release includes fixes for the Android SDK, addressing an issue with system messages containing empty spaces. For the iOS SDK, weve resolved the display of the "Skip the human agent" button after transfers to a virtual agent and fixed an issue where notification sounds played despite being disabled.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Fixed issues in Android and iOS SDKs</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-07-07:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Session metadata in Conversational Insights conversations is GA</strong></p>
<p>The Google Cloud CCaaS capability of including session metadata when creating conversations in Conversational Insights is now <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products?e=48754805&amp;hl=en#product-launch-stages">generally available (GA)</a>. Metadata values are available for each conversation. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/conversational-insights">Conversational Insights and Quality AI</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The session metadata feature in Conversational Insights is now generally available. This allows for the inclusion of session metadata when creating conversations, with values available for each.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Session Metadata in Conversational Insights Now GA</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-07-02:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Version 3.36 is released</strong></p>
<p>All release notes published on this date are part of version 3.36.</p>
<p>The timing of the update to your instance depends on the deployment schedule that you have chosen. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/deployment-schedules">Deployment schedules</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Version 3.36 has been released. The release includes all release notes published on this date. The update timing depends on your chosen deployment schedule.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Version 3.36 Released</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-07-02:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Configure storage of Screen Share recordings</strong></p>
<p>You can now configure how long to store Screen Share recordings in your external storage settings. You can also now store Screen Share recordings that originated from the Screen Share adapter.</p>
<p>Administrators: The <strong>CRM Comments Creation Details</strong> pane at <strong>Settings &gt; Operation Management</strong> has new <strong>Post Cobrowse recording link to CRM record</strong> settings. You need to contact Google support to enable Screen Share recordings.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/crm-external-storage">Set up external storage for CRMs</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now configure the retention period for Screen Share recordings and choose to store recordings from the Screen Share adapter. To enable this feature, administrators need to contact Google support and adjust settings in the CRM Comments Creation Details pane.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Configure Screen Share Recording Storage</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-07-02:feature:2</id>
    <published>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Restrict auto-assignment for email queues</strong></p>
<p>You can now configure email queues so that incoming emails are auto-assigned only during queue operating hours or to agents who are signed in.</p>
<p>Administrators: The <strong>Auto assignment</strong> dialog at <strong>Settings &gt; Queue &gt; Email Edit/View &gt; [queue name] &gt; Automatic assignment &gt; Configure</strong> has two new checkboxes.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/email-channel-config#email-auto-assignment">Email auto assignment</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now configure email queues to auto-assign incoming emails only during operating hours or to signed-in agents. This provides more control over the distribution of emails to your team.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Control email auto-assignment</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-07-02:feature:3</id>
    <published>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Salesforce: New closed record options for scheduled calls</strong></p>
<p>If you've integrated Google Cloud CCaaS with the Salesforce CRM, you can configure how your instance handles scheduled calls for closed records. Here are the configuration options that are available with Salesforce integrations:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Don't look up record status</strong>. Your instance doesn't look up record status and makes the scheduled call regardless of whether the record is open or closed.</li>
<li><strong>Look up record status and reopen closed records</strong>. Your instance looks up record status before making a scheduled call and reopens records that are closed.</li>
<li><strong>Look up record status and cancel scheduled calls for closed records</strong>. Your instance looks up record status before making a scheduled call and cancels scheduled calls for records that are closed.</li>
</ul>
<p>Administrators: The <strong>CRM Record Creation Details</strong> pane at <strong>Settings &gt; Operation Management</strong> has new settings at <strong>Closed record options when initiating an API-scheduled call</strong>.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/schedule-calls-salesforce">Schedule calls with Salesforce</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Salesforce administrators can now configure how their instance handles scheduled calls for closed records. The new options allow the instance to either disregard record status, reopen closed records, or cancel scheduled calls for closed records. These settings are available in the CRM Record Creation Details pane.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New options for handling closed records in Salesforce</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-07-02:fixed:4</id>
    <published>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following issues were addressed in this release:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where calls weren't being assigned to the correct agent in Google Cloud CCaaS reporting.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where calls weren't being assigned to the correct agent in the CRM.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the communication between a virtual task assistant and an end-user was not included in the Agent Assist live transcript in the agent adapter.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where agent outbound calls generated incorrect URLs in reporting. URLs contained <code>ticket</code> instead of <code>tickets</code>.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where newly created global contact list destinations were not available in the <strong>Overcapacity Deflection</strong> settings for IVR queues.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the <code>on_email_thread_created</code> event listener was mistakenly logging customer names and email addresses.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where uploading a new overcapacity deflection message didn't replace the existing message.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where agents were not being assigned chat sessions while routing was configured for deltacast.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where attachments were lost when: (1) A chat session was transfered to another agent, or (2) After a chat auto-dismissed, an end-user restarted the chat with the same agent in the same queue.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where chats didn't time out after being inactive for longer than the chat timeout setting for the queue.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where agents who were removed from a chat session using the <strong>Connected Chats</strong> page were not fully disconnected from the session. These agents remained in the conversation tile, couldn't remove themselves from the session, and couldn't receive new chats.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where chats initiated outside of working hours generated incorrect chat transcripts. Instead of indicating that the support center was closed, the transcipts indicated that customer support was experiencing high volume.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where an external agent and an end-user couldn't communicate after an internal agent did the following: (1) Answered the call, (2) Put the end-user on hold, (3) tranferred the call to a queue with auto redirect to an external number, and (4) failed to release the hold before leaving the call.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where end-users with a blocked phone number were able to contact support using chat.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the global disposition list appeared in the chat adapter during wrap-up instead of the disposition list for the agent's queue.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a barge-in event interrupted an agent's audio.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where call session recordings were either not being sent to external storage or they were sent in the wrong file format.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in advanced reporting dashboards where chats appeared in the chat waiting menu even after the chat sessions ended.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the agent desktop translations in French (Canada) and Japanese were not complete.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the system was generating duplicate After Call Work records for a single wrap-up.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where bulk upload containing new users assigned to teams failed.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the chat adapter failed to appear after Nexmo VOIP initialization failed.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where saving chat transcripts to a CRM failed.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>This release addresses numerous issues, including incorrect call routing, missing chat transcripts, and problems with attachment transfers. It also resolves an issue where agents were not being fully disconnected from chat sessions and ensures correct URLs are generated in reporting. Additionally, it fixes problems with overcapacity deflection settings, event listener logging, and chat timeout functionality. The release also corrects issues related to external call transfers, blocked phone numbers, disposition lists, barge-in events, call recording formats, duplicate After Call Work records, and user/team assignments. Finally, it resolves issues with agent desktop translations and the visibility of the chat adapter after VOIP initialization failure.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Resolved various issues affecting call routing, chat functionality, and reporting.</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-06-26:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Web SDK version 3</strong></p>
<p>We're pleased to announce that the web SDK v3 is now <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">generally available (GA)</a>. The web SDK v3 is built on the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/headless-web-guide">headless web SDK</a>, so all of the methods that are available on a headless SDK client are also available with the web SDK v3 widget.</p>
<p><strong>Deprecation notice</strong></p>
<p>Starting on <strong>December 31, 2025</strong>, the web SDK v2 will no longer function. Be sure to <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/web-sdk-v3-upgrade">update your website</a> to use the web SDK v3 before that date to avoid breaking your integration with the web SDK. We are no longer adding new features to the web SDK v2.</p>
<p><strong>Capabilities</strong></p>
<p>The web SDK v3 provides the following new capabilities:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>View previous chats and download chat transcripts</strong>. End-users can view previous chats and download chat transcripts from the web SDK widget. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/chat-transcripts">View previous chats and download chat transcripts</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Web forms</strong>. You can set up HTML web forms to collect data from end-users. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/use-data-collection-forms">Use data collection forms</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Include conditional operators with proactive chat triggers</strong>. When configuring proactive chat triggers, you can include OR operators with keywords and AND operators with multiple conditions. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/Chat_Settings_and_Features#UUID-ff948643-7f0c-2db5-ff46-a3e121b180d4">Proactive Web SDK Triggers</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Agents can attach files during chats</strong>. An agent can attach a wide variety of file types using the web SDK widget during a chat session. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/Chat_Settings_and_Features#rich-messaging">Configure rich messaging and file attachments</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Disable chat audio</strong>. An end-user can disable chat audio using the web SDK widget.</li>
<li><strong>System message categorization</strong>. System messages are categorized as standard, confirmation, or error types.</li>
<li><strong>Post-session transfers when the end-user ends a session</strong>. Post-session transfers can be triggered when an end-user ends a call or chat session. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/post-session-transfer">Post-session transfers</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Documentation</strong></p>
<p>Here's the web SDK v3 documentation:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/web-sdk-v3-getting-started">Web SDK v3 guide</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/web-sdk-v3-strings">Web SDK v3 strings guide</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/web-sdk-v3-upgrade">Upgrade from web SDK version 2 to web SDK version 3</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Upgrade</strong></p>
<p>For help upgrading to web SDK v3, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/web-sdk-v3-upgrade">Upgrade from web SDK version 2 to web SDK version 3</a>. If you've been using the Private Preview version of web SDK v3, be sure to update your implementations to access <code>widget.js</code> from your Google Cloud CCaaS instance.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The new web SDK v3 is now generally available, built upon the headless web SDK. It introduces new features such as viewing past chats, web forms, and agent file attachments. The previous version, web SDK v2, will be deprecated on December 31, 2025, so an upgrade is recommended.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Web SDK v3 Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-06-09:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Salesforce ICU Update</strong></p>
<p>This is for Google Contact Center as a Service (CCaaS) customers that use Salesforce integration with CCaaS.</p>
<p>On <strong>June 15th, 2025</strong>, Salesforce is rolling out an automatic upgrade to its International Components for Unicode (ICU) locale data. This affects how date, time, number, and currency formatting are handled across Apex, Visualforce, and Lightning components.</p>
<p>This change affects Salesforce integrations that are using Apex API versions earlier than 45.0. These integrations use the legacy Java locale behavior, which could cause formatting discrepancies, incorrect parsing, or runtime errors.</p>
<p><strong>Solution</strong></p>
<p>Google has reviewed the CCaaS managed package and has updated the impacted classes to use safe, ICU-compatible parsing and formatting methods. This includes cleaning up legacy code that uses older API versions, which might affect this transition.</p>
<p>The following table shows the affected classes:</p>
<p><strong>Affected classes</strong></p>
<p>| Name | API version |
| --- | --- |
| <code>UJETUtilsController</code> | 35.0 |
| <code>UJETUtilsControllerTests</code> | 35.0 |
| <code>UJETJWT</code> | 43.0 |
| <code>UJETJWTTests</code> | 43.0 |
| <code>UJETPageController</code> | 43.0 |</p>
<p><strong>Required action</strong></p>
<p>To ensure compatibility with the Salesforce ICU update and prevent any operational impact, you must complete the following action before <strong>June 15th, 2025</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Install the <a href="https://login.salesforce.com/?ec=302&amp;startURL=%2Fpackaging%2FinstallPackage.apexp%3Fp0%3D04tKk0000011MNw%26InstHostname%3Dlogin.salesforce.com">v1.40 update</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>This installation updates the affected classes. No further action is required.</p>
<p><strong>What happens if you don't upgrade?</strong></p>
<p>If any part of your integration or Apex code uses versions earlier than 45.0 after June 15th, Salesforce will not apply the ICU formatting to those sections. This could potentially lead to issues, including the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Incorrect date and time parsing</li>
<li>Unexpected errors in workflows or automations</li>
<li>Mismatch between Lightning and Classic behavior</li>
<li>Breakage in integrations expecting consistent locale handling</li>
</ul>
<p>Google considers the affected classes in CC_AGENT_APP v1.38 to be safe. While some of the affected classes have legacy methods that are affected by this update, they are not being actively used and will be deprecated in version 1.40. Regardless, Google still recommends installing the v1.40 update. Not upgrading can potentially impact other solutions that are installed on the environment, as described in this communication.</p>
<p><strong>Defer the update</strong></p>
<p>As described in <a href="https://help.salesforce.com/s/articleView?id=xcloud.icu_migration_enable.htm&amp;type=5">Enable the ICU Locale Formats</a>, you can defer the automatic rollout of this update.</p>
<p>To defer this update, follow these steps:</p>
<ol>
<li>From the Quick Find search box in <strong>Setup</strong>, enter <strong>User Interface</strong>.</li>
<li>On the User Interface page, deselect the <strong>Enable ICU locale formats as part of the scheduled rollout</strong> checkbox.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Important</strong>: This will only be effective if completed before <strong>June 15th 2025</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Salesforce is upgrading its ICU locale data on June 15th, 2025. This may affect Google CCaaS customers using Salesforce integration with Apex API versions earlier than 45.0, potentially causing formatting discrepancies or errors. Google has updated its managed package to ensure compatibility. To prevent issues, install the v1.40 update before June 15th, 2025. Failure to upgrade may lead to incorrect parsing, unexpected errors, and integration breakages.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Salesforce ICU Update Affecting CCaaS Customers</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-06-05:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Patch 3.35.15 is released</strong></p>
<p>This patch does the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixes an issue in agent desktop. When an agent had active chat sessions with two end-users simultaneously, the chat history was missing for one of the chats.</li>
<li>~~Fixes an issue where bulk user upload jobs on the <strong>Bulk User Management</strong> page got stuck and didn't complete.~~</li>
<li>Fixes an issue in agent desktop where the chat adapter was unavailable when a chat was received.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Patch 3.35.15 resolves critical issues including missing chat history in agent desktop for agents handling multiple simultaneous chats and the unavailability of the chat adapter when receiving a chat.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Patch 3.35.15 Released</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-06-23:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Version 3.36 pre-release notes</strong></p>
<p>Here are the pre-release notes for version 3.36. When we release version 3.36, we expect the new capabilities to be as shown here.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The latest pre-release notes for version 3.36 are now available, providing a preview of upcoming features and improvements.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Version 3.36 Pre-Release Notes</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-06-23:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Configure storage of Screen Share recordings</strong></p>
<p>You can now configure how long to store Screen Share recordings in your external storage settings. You can also now store Screen Share recordings that originated from the Screen Share adapter.</p>
<p>Administrators: The <strong>CRM Comments Creation Details</strong> pane at <strong>Settings &gt; Operation Management</strong> has new <strong>Post Cobrowse recording link to CRM record</strong> settings. You need to contact Google support to enable Screen Share recordings.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now configure the retention period for Screen Share recordings stored in your external storage. This includes recordings from the Screen Share adapter. Contact Google support to enable this feature.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Screen Share Recording Configuration</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-06-23:feature:2</id>
    <published>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Restrict auto-assignment for email queues</strong></p>
<p>You can now configure email queues so that incoming emails are auto-assigned only during queue operating hours or to agents who are signed in.</p>
<p>Administrators: The <strong>Auto assignment</strong> dialog at <strong>Settings &gt; Queue &gt; Email Edit/View &gt; [queue name] &gt; Automatic assignment &gt; Configure</strong> has two new checkboxes.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now restrict email auto-assignment to agents who are signed in and during queue operating hours. This provides more control over how incoming emails are distributed.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Restrict Email Auto-Assignment</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-06-23:feature:3</id>
    <published>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Salesforce: New closed record options for scheduled calls</strong></p>
<p>If you've integrated Google Cloud CCaaS with the Salesforce CRM, you can configure how your instance handles scheduled calls for closed records. Here are the configuration options that are available with Salesforce integrations:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Don't look up record status</strong>. Your instance doesn't look up record status and makes the scheduled call regardless of whether the record is open or closed.</li>
<li><strong>Look up record status and reopen closed records</strong>. Your instance looks up record status before making a scheduled call and reopens records that are closed.</li>
<li><strong>Look up record status and cancel scheduled calls for closed records</strong>. Your instance looks up record status before making a scheduled call and cancels scheduled calls for records that are closed.</li>
</ul>
<p>Administrators: The <strong>CRM Record Creation Details</strong> pane at <strong>Settings &gt; Operation Management</strong> has new settings at <strong>Closed record options when initiating an API-scheduled call</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>New options are available for managing scheduled calls with closed records in Salesforce. Administrators can choose to ignore record status, reopen closed records, or cancel scheduled calls for closed records via new settings in the CRM Record Creation Details pane.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Salesforce: New closed record options for scheduled calls</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-06-23:fixed:4</id>
    <published>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following issues were addressed in this release:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where calls weren't being assigned to the correct agent in Google Cloud CCaaS reporting.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where calls weren't being assigned to the correct agent in the CRM.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the communication between a virtual task assistant and an end-user was not included in the Agent Assist live transcript in the agent adapter.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where agent outbound calls generated incorrect URLs in reporting. URLs contained <code>ticket</code> instead of <code>tickets</code>.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where newly created global contact list destinations were not available in the <strong>Overcapacity Deflection</strong> settings for IVR queues.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the <code>on_email_thread_created</code> event listener was mistakenly logging customer names and email addresses.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where uploading a new overcapacity deflection message didn't replace the existing message.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where agents were not being assigned chat sessions while routing was configured for deltacast.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where attachments were lost when: (1) A chat session was transfered to another agent, or (2) After a chat auto-dismissed, an end-user restarted the chat with the same agent in the same queue.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where chats didn't time out after being inactive for longer than the chat timeout setting for the queue.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where agents who were removed from a chat session using the <strong>Connected Chats</strong> page were not fully disconnected from the session. These agents remained in the conversation tile, couldn't remove themselves from the session, and couldn't receive new chats.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where chats initiated outside of working hours generated incorrect chat transcripts. Instead of indicating that the support center was closed, the transcipts indicated that customer support was experiencing high volume.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where an external agent and an end-user couldn't communicate after an internal agent did the following: (1) Answered the call, (2) Put the end-user on hold, (3) tranferred the call to a queue with auto redirect to an external number, and (4) failed to release the hold before leaving the call.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where end-users with a blocked phone number were able to contact support using chat.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the global disposition list appeared in the chat adapter during wrap-up instead of the disposition list for the agent's queue.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a barge-in event interrupted an agent's audio.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where call session recordings were either not being sent to external storage or they were sent in the wrong file format.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in advanced reporting dashboards where chats appeared in the chat waiting menu even after the chat sessions ended.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the agent desktop translations in French (Canada) and Japanese were not complete.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the system was generating duplicate After Call Work records for a single wrap-up.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where bulk upload containing new users assigned to teams failed.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Several issues have been resolved, including problems with call routing and agent assignment in CCaaS reporting and CRM, incorrect URL generation for agent outbound calls, and issues with overcapacity deflection settings. Additionally, fixes were made for chat session handling, including lost attachments, incorrect chat timeouts, and agent disconnections. The update also addresses problems with call recordings, reporting dashboards, agent desktop translations, duplicate After Call Work records, and bulk user upload failures.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Resolved various issues in reporting, routing, and chat functionalities</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-05-28:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Headless web SDK 3.6.5 is released</strong></p>
<p>This release does the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixes an issue where duplicate messages from the virtual assistant appeared in the end-user's chat pane.</li>
<li>Fixes an issue where end-users were able to reactivate inactive chats outside of operating hours.</li>
<li>Fixes an issue with data collection forms, where the SDK timed out during the form server's first load attempt, causing a delay in the appearance of the form in the end-user's chat pane.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>A new version of the Headless web SDK (3.6.5) has been released, addressing issues with duplicate messages, reactivation of inactive chats, and data collection form loading times.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Headless web SDK 3.6.5 Released</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-05-27:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Version 3.35 is released</strong></p>
<p>All release notes published on this date are part of version 3.35.</p>
<p>The timing of the update to your instance depends on the deployment schedule that you have chosen. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/deployment-schedules">Deployment schedules</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Version 3.35 has been released, including all release notes published on this date. The update timing depends on your chosen deployment schedule.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Version 3.35 Released</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-05-27:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>QM integration now includes chat session events</strong></p>
<p>You can now export chat session events to an external quality management (QM) system. After you configure the endpoint of your QM system in Google Cloud CCaaS, your chat session events can be streamed to the endpoint in real time.</p>
<p>User experience change:</p>
<ul>
<li>The <strong>QM Integration</strong> dialog at <strong>Settings &gt; Developer Settings &gt; Session Data Export &gt; QM Integration</strong> has a new <strong>QM Chat Events - send chat sessions events</strong> checkbox.</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/qm-siprec-integration">QM, SIPREC, and WFM integration</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now export chat session events to an external quality management (QM) system in real time. This feature is available after configuring the QM system endpoint in Google Cloud CCaaS.</summary>
    <title>Feature: QM integration now includes chat session events</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-05-27:feature:2</id>
    <published>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Remove email subject lines from interaction data</strong></p>
<p>We now support removing email subject lines when you delete interaction data from your instance for specified end-users. The email subjects are removed when you delete data for an end-user in the <strong>Consumer Privacy</strong> dialog at <strong>Settings &gt; Consumer Management &gt; Consumer Privacy</strong>. To completely remove an end-user's data, you must also delete their emails from your mail server. You must also delete chat transcripts, call recordings, and other session-related files from your CRM or external storage, depending on your configuration.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/remove-end-user-data#remove-subject-lines-from-email-interactions">Remove subject lines from end-user email interactions</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now remove email subject lines from interaction data for specific end-users through the Consumer Privacy dialog in your instance settings. This helps in completely removing an end-user's data, but you also need to delete their emails from your mail server and other session-related files from your CRM or external storage.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Remove email subjects from interaction data</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-05-27:feature:3</id>
    <published>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>New sender email with auto-response emails</strong></p>
<p>You can now configure an outbound-only email address and use it as the sender address for auto-response emails. The outbound-only address is a "no-reply" email address that prevents the receiver from responding.</p>
<p>User experience changes:</p>
<ul>
<li>The <strong>Auto-response</strong> dialog at <strong>Settings &gt; Queue &gt; Email &gt; [your-email-queue] &gt; Auto-response</strong> has a new <strong>Sender email</strong> field.</li>
<li>The <strong>Add an email</strong> dialog at <strong>Settings &gt; Developer Settings &gt; Email Account Management &gt; Email account list &gt; Add email account</strong> has a new <strong>This is an outbound only email account</strong> checkbox.</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/email-channel-config#configure-outbound-only-email-account">Configure an outbound-only email account</a> and <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/email-channel-config#configure-auto-response-email">Configure an auto-response email</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now configure an outbound-only email address to use as the sender for auto-response emails. This new feature prevents recipients from replying to these automated messages.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New sender email for auto-responses</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-05-27:feature:4</id>
    <published>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Include images in outbound emails</strong></p>
<p>You can now include images in outbound emails. This includes emails from an agent in an email session and outbound auto-response emails.</p>
<p>User experience change:</p>
<ul>
<li>The <strong>Auto-response</strong> dialog at <strong>Settings &gt; Queue &gt; Email &gt; [your-email-queue] &gt; Auto-response</strong> has a new <strong>Insert Image</strong> button.</li>
<li>The email adapter has a new <strong>Insert Image</strong> button.</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/email-adapter">Agent email adapter</a> and <a href="https://cloud.google.com/contact-center/ccai-platform/docs/email-channel-config#configure-auto-response-email">Configure an auto-response email</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now include images in your outbound emails, both from agents and in automated responses. Look for the new 'Insert Image' button in the auto-response settings and the email adapter.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Include images in outbound emails</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-contact-center-as-a-service:2025-05-27:fixed:5</id>
    <published>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following issues were addressed in this release:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed an issue where calls were were being logged as <strong>Call with unknown contact</strong> in HubSpot instead of under the correct contact name.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the client secret couldn't be saved when a user attempted to set up authentication (using either basic authentication or OAuth) for a custom CRM with the <strong>Generic API</strong> CRM lookup method.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the setup dialog for <strong>Find an account by query endpoint</strong> could not be reached due to an authentication error when configuring OAuth for a custom CRM.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where calls were being passed to a custom CRM with the incorrect phone number format.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue for ServiceNow users where records were created for outbound calls despite the agent selecting <strong>Do not create a record</strong> in the call adapter.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a queue did not have access to the global contact list even though it was configured to have access to it.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the <strong>Directory</strong> tab didn't appear when an agent was transferring a call.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the <strong>Voice Campaign</strong> checkbox didn't appear for <strong>Select Call Types</strong> in the <strong>Create Reports</strong> pane, despite the user having the appropriate report access permissions.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where agent extension deflection recordings didn't upload after appearing to be successfully uploaded.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue that occurred when the <code>@{NEXT_REOPEN_HOUR}</code> dynamic variable was put in the <strong>Message</strong> field for <strong>After Hour Messaging</strong> in the <strong>Web &amp; Mobile Messages</strong> pane. The variable always resolved as the next time the chat queue opened on the <em>following</em> day. This happened even when the next time the chat queue opened was on the <em>current</em> day.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue that occurred when an end-user on the global contact list placed an inbound call to a queue with access to the global contact list turned off. The agent adapter displayed the destination name of the caller, despite access to the global contact list being turned off.</li>
<li>Extended the search conditions for the <strong>Directory</strong> tab in the agent adapter to include search by an extension number.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the "next open hours" message was incorrect when a chat ended after midnight.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the call transcript failed to continue after an agent returned from hold.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the default disposition list appeared in the agent adapter instead of the custom disposition list, which was configured to appear.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a user with a manager role received a "Not Authorized" error when attempting to use the <strong>Operation Management</strong> and <strong>Disposition Codes</strong> pages.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the <code>failReason</code> and <code>afterHours</code> fields in the session metadata file were incorrect for chats that failed because they were attempted after hours.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the <strong>Assign agents</strong> button wasn't working for custom after hours deflection and automatic redirection.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the client secret was not saved when configuring OAuth for a custom CRM.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where calling the current queue status endpoint of the Manager API intermittently returned a 404 error.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the wrong disposition code list appeared for an agent after transferring a chat to an agent in a different queue.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where chat shortcuts were not working in the agent adapter for mobile chats.</li>
<li>Fixed issues where agents were unable to successfully move beyond the wrap-up state to handle the next call.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Several issues have been resolved, including problems with call logging in HubSpot, authentication for custom CRMs, call routing, record creation in ServiceNow, directory access, report visibility, recording uploads, dynamic variable resolution, inbound call display, agent adapter search functionality, midnight chat handling, call transcriptions, disposition lists, manager role access, session metadata accuracy, assignment buttons, client secret saving, API endpoint errors, disposition code display, chat shortcuts, and agent state transitions.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Resolved various issues for improved functionality</title>
  </entry>
</feed>