<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Cloud Database Migration Service</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Cloud Database Migration Service</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-database-migration-service</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/cloud-database-migration-service/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-database-migration-service:2025-08-14:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Database Migration Service now supports Private Service Connect interfaces for network connectivity in homogeneous Cloud SQL for MySQL, Cloud SQL for PostgreSQL, and AlloyDB for PostgreSQL migrations. For more information, see the following pages:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/database-migration/docs/mysql/networking-methods">Networking methods in homogeneous Cloud SQL for MySQL migrations</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/database-migration/docs/postgres/networking-methods">Networking methods in homogeneous Cloud SQL for PostgreSQL migrations</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/database-migration/docs/postgresql-to-alloydb/networking-methods">Networking methods in homogeneous AlloyDB for PostgreSQL migrations</a></li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Database Migration Service now supports Private Service Connect interfaces for network connectivity.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Private Service Connect Support</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-database-migration-service:2025-06-30:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Database Migration Service support for heterogeneous SQL Server to PostgreSQL migrations is now generally available (<a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">GA</a>).</p>
<p>For more information, see:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/database-migration/docs/sqlserver-to-csql-pgsql/scenario-overview">Database Migration Service for SQL Server to Cloud SQL for PostgreSQL</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/database-migration/docs/sqlserver-to-alloydb/scenario-overview">Database Migration Service for SQL Server to AlloyDB for PostgreSQL</a></li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Database Migration Service now supports heterogeneous SQL Server to PostgreSQL migrations, including to Cloud SQL and AlloyDB for PostgreSQL. This feature is now generally available.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: Database Migration Service now supports SQL Server to PostgreSQL</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-database-migration-service:2025-06-16:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Heterogeneous Oracle and SQL Server migrations now provide an improved experience with conversion overview dashboards and streamlined conversion issue grouping. To learn more about Database Migration Service conversion workspaces with Gemini-powered conversion features, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/database-migration/docs/convert-sql-with-dms#conversion-workspaces">Convert SQL with Database Migration Service</a> .</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Database Migration Service now offers an enhanced experience for migrating Oracle and SQL Server databases, featuring new conversion overview dashboards and better issue grouping.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Improved Database Migration Experience</title>
  </entry>
</feed>