<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Dataplex</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Dataplex</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:dataplex</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/dataplex/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:dataplex:2025-11-17:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Previously, data profile scan results were published only to the Google Cloud console. You can now publish the results of a data profile scan as Dataplex Universal Catalog metadata. The latest results are saved to the entry that represents the source table. You can view the results in the Google Cloud console.</p>
<p>If you want to enable catalog publishing for an existing data profile scan, you must edit the scan and re-enable the publishing option.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/dataplex/docs/use-data-profiling">Use data profiling</a>.</p>
<p>This feature is <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">generally available (GA)</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now publish data profile scan results as Dataplex Universal Catalog metadata, with the latest results saved to the entry representing the source table. This provides a new way to access and view your data profiling information.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Data Profile Scan Results Now Available as Catalog Metadata</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:dataplex:2025-09-29:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Column-level lineage is generally available (<a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">GA</a>).
The feature provides a granular view of your data by tracking the flow between individual columns within tables. You can perform functions such as root cause analysis, impact analysis, and data source verification for specific columns. Column-level lineage is only supported for BigQuery jobs. For more information about column-level lineage, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/dataplex/docs/lineage-views#column-level-lineage">Column-level lineage</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Column-level lineage is now generally available for BigQuery jobs. This feature provides a granular view of your data by tracking the flow between individual columns within tables, enabling functions such as root cause analysis, impact analysis, and data source verification for specific columns.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Column-level lineage now available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:dataplex:2025-09-23:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now connect your Dataplex Universal Catalog instance to your favorite developer tools, such as the Gemini CLI and other IDEs. This integration enables AI-driven data discovery and asset management directly within your development environment. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/dataplex/docs/pre-built-tools-with-mcp-toolbox">Use Dataplex Universal Catalog with MCP, Gemini, and other agents</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Dataplex Universal Catalog can now be connected to your preferred developer tools like the Gemini CLI and IDEs, allowing for AI-driven data discovery and management within your development environment.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Dataplex Universal Catalog Now Connects to Developer Tools</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:dataplex:2025-09-03:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cloud.google.com/dataplex/docs/search-assets">Natural language search</a> in Dataplex Universal Catalog is available in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">preview</a>.</p>
<p>Natural language search extends keyword search to support natural language queries. It lets you find resources using everyday language, eliminating the need for complex syntax.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Dataplex Universal Catalog now supports natural language search in preview. This feature allows you to find resources using everyday language, moving beyond traditional keyword searches.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Natural language search available in Dataplex Universal Catalog</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:dataplex:2025-06-18:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Previously, data quality scan results were published only to the Google Cloud console. You can now publish the results of a data quality scan as Dataplex Universal Catalog metadata. The latest results are saved to the entry that represents the source table. You can view the results in the Google Cloud console.</p>
<p>If you want to enable catalog publishing for an existing data quality scan, you must edit the scan and re-enable the publishing option.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/dataplex/docs/use-auto-data-quality">Use auto data quality</a>.</p>
<p>This feature is generally available (<a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">GA</a>).</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Data quality scan results can now be published as Dataplex Universal Catalog metadata, with the latest results saved to the entry representing the source table. To enable this for existing scans, edit the scan and re-enable the publishing option. This feature is now generally available.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Data quality scan results now available in Dataplex Universal Catalog</title>
  </entry>
</feed>