<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Colab Enterprise</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Colab Enterprise</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:colab-enterprise</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/colab-enterprise/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:colab-enterprise:2025-10-20:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Visualization cells</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">Preview</a>: You can
use visualization cells to generate interactive and editable visualizations
from within a Colab Enterprise notebook. You can configure the
chart type, aggregation, colors, labels, and other aspects of the
visualization to help you explore data and discover insights. For more
information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/colab/docs/visualization-cells">Use visualization cells</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Create interactive and editable visualizations directly within your Colab Enterprise notebooks. Customize chart types, colors, and labels to explore data and uncover insights.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Interactive Visualizations in Colab Enterprise</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:colab-enterprise:2025-10-14:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>SQL cells</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">Preview</a>: You can
use SQL cells to write, edit, and run SQL queries directly from your
Colab Enterprise notebooks. For more information, see
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/colab/docs/sql-cells">Use SQL cells</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Write, edit, and run SQL queries directly within your Colab Enterprise notebooks using the new SQL cells feature.</summary>
    <title>Feature: SQL Cells in Colab Enterprise</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:colab-enterprise:2025-10-07:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Post-startup scripts</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">Preview</a>: You can
use a post-startup script to perform tasks after the startup process
of your Colab Enterprise runtime. For example, you can use
a post-startup script to install specific packages or make specific
changes to your runtime's VM. For more information, see
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/colab/docs/post-startup-script">Use a post-startup script</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now use post-startup scripts to customize your Colab Enterprise runtime after it starts, for tasks like installing packages or modifying the VM.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Post-startup scripts available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:colab-enterprise:2025-08-05:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">Generally available</a>: You can consume reservations with Colab Enterprise runtimes. Reservations of Compute Engine zonal resources help you gain a high level of assurance that your runtimes have the necessary resources to run. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/colab/docs/reservations">Use reservations with Colab Enterprise</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now use reservations with Colab Enterprise runtimes to ensure your runtimes have the resources they need.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Colab Enterprise now supports reservations</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:colab-enterprise:2025-08-04:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now use the new Data Science Agent to automate exploratory data analysis, perform machine learning tasks, and deliver insights from within a Colab Enterprise notebook. To get started, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/colab/docs/use-data-science-agent">Use the Data Science Agent</a>. This feature is in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">Preview</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Automate your data analysis and machine learning tasks with the new Data Science Agent in Colab Enterprise.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Data Science Agent Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:colab-enterprise:2025-06-30:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">Preview</a>: You can consume reservations with Colab Enterprise runtimes. Reservations of Compute Engine zonal resources help you gain a high level of assurance that your runtimes have the necessary resources to run. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/colab/docs/reservations">Use reservations with Colab Enterprise</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Colab Enterprise runtimes can now use reservations of Compute Engine zonal resources. This provides a higher level of assurance that your runtimes will have the necessary resources to run.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Colab Enterprise now supports reservations</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:colab-enterprise:2025-05-28:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Python 3.11 is now available in Colab Enterprise. Existing runtimes and runtime templates will remain using Python 3.10. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/colab/docs/runtimes#python">Python versions</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Python 3.11 is now available for use in Colab Enterprise. However, please note that existing runtimes and templates will continue to use Python 3.10.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Python 3.11 Now Available in Colab Enterprise</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:colab-enterprise:2025-05-28:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When you create a runtime template, you can now configure it to use the latest Python version available to Colab Enterprise, or you can specify the Python version. Using <code>Latest</code> is a new option that means when a new version of Python is introduced to Colab Enterprise, runtimes that you create will use the latest Python version.</p>
<p>Existing runtime templates and runtimes remain using their current Python version (Python 3.10). This includes existing auto-generated default runtime templates. To create default runtime templates that use <code>Latest</code>, you must do one of the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Delete the existing default runtime templates. Then, when a new default runtime template is created, the Python version will be set to Latest.</li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/colab/docs/runtimes#change-python-version">Change a runtime template's Python version</a> by using the REST API.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now choose to use the latest available Python version for your Colab Enterprise runtimes or specify a particular version. Runtimes using the "Latest" option will automatically update to the newest Python version when it becomes available. Existing runtimes will continue to use their current Python version.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Python version options for runtimes</title>
  </entry>
</feed>