<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Cloud Data Fusion</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Cloud Data Fusion</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-data-fusion</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/cloud-data-fusion/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-data-fusion:2025-08-27:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud Data Fusion version 6.11.1 is <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">generally available (GA)</a>. This release includes the following features:</p>
<ul>
<li>Added support for HTTP access tokens (Bearer authentication) in Bitbucket Server for <a href="https://cloud.google.com/data-fusion/docs/how-to/source-control-management">source control management</a> (<a href="https://cdap.atlassian.net/browse/CDAP-21049">CDAP-21049</a>).</li>
<li>A new API is available to retrieve the application count for each namespace (<a href="https://cdap.atlassian.net/browse/CDAP-21161">CDAP-21161</a>).</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud Data Fusion version 6.11.1 is now generally available. This release adds support for HTTP access tokens in Bitbucket Server for source control management and introduces a new API to retrieve application counts per namespace.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud Data Fusion 6.11.1</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-data-fusion:2025-08-27:changed:1</id>
    <published>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Changes in Cloud Data Fusion 6.11.1:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Java runtime environment is upgraded from Java 8 to Java 11 (<a href="https://cdap.atlassian.net/browse/CDAP-21184">CDAP-21184</a>).</li>
<li>To create ephemeral Dataproc clusters, Cloud Data Fusion uses the Dataproc 2.3 image by default (<a href="https://cdap.atlassian.net/browse/CDAP-21187">CDAP-21187</a>).</li>
<li>The pipeline JSON size limit for creating new pipelines and importing pipelines as JSON is increased to 5MB (previously 2MB) (<CDAP-21194>).</li>
<li>On the Pipeline details page, the inbound triggers sidebar features a paginated list of pipelines where you can select the pipelines you want to add to the trigger. Additionally, a refresh button is added to update the existing list of triggers and pipelines (<a href="https://cdap.atlassian.net/browse/CDAP-21195">CDAP-21195</a>).</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud Data Fusion 6.11.1 is now available. This release includes an upgrade to Java 11, updated Dataproc image defaults for ephemeral clusters, an increased pipeline JSON size limit to 5MB, and enhancements to the pipeline details page for inbound triggers.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Cloud Data Fusion 6.11.1 Release Notes</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-data-fusion:2025-08-27:fixed:2</id>
    <published>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Fixed in Cloud Data Fusion 6.11.1:</p>
<ul>
<li>To prevent storage issues on static Dataproc clusters, temporary pipeline data is automatically deleted after a successful run (<a href="https://cdap.atlassian.net/browse/CDAP-21076">CDAP-21076</a>).</li>
<li>Fixed an issue that prevented <a href="https://github.com/data-integrations/wrangler/blob/develop/wrangler-core/src/main/java/io/cdap/wrangler/expression/EL.java">Expression Language (EL)</a> from being used within user-defined directives (<a href="https://cdap.atlassian.net/browse/CDAP-21204">CDAP-21204</a>).</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a pipeline would fail when reading an encrypted file from Cloud Storage using Tink (<a href="https://cdap.atlassian.net/browse/PLUGIN-1717">PLUGIN-1717</a>).</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Temporary pipeline data is now automatically deleted after a successful run to prevent storage issues on static Dataproc clusters. Additionally, Expression Language can now be used within user-defined directives, and an issue with reading encrypted files from Cloud Storage using Tink has been resolved.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Temporary pipeline data is automatically deleted after a successful run</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-data-fusion:2025-08-27:deprecated:3</id>
    <published>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dataproc 2.0 is no longer supported in Cloud Data Fusion version 6.11.1 and later.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Dataproc 2.0 is no longer supported starting with Cloud Data Fusion version 6.11.1.</summary>
    <title>Deprecated: Dataproc 2.0 Deprecation</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-data-fusion:2025-07-25:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now attach tags to Cloud Data Fusion instances during instance creation. This ensures immediate metadata for better organization, cost tracking, and policy automation. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/data-fusion/docs/how-to/control-access-with-tags#add-tags">Attach tags during instance creation</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Tags can now be attached to Cloud Data Fusion instances at creation for better organization and cost tracking.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud Data Fusion instance tags</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-data-fusion:2025-07-23:fixed:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Cloud Data Fusion version 6.10.1.5 patch revision is generally available (<a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">GA</a>). 6.10.1.5 includes reliability fixes.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Reliability fixes for Cloud Data Fusion.</summary>
    <title>Fixed: Cloud Data Fusion v6.10.1.5 now available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-data-fusion:2025-07-20:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The SAP ODP plugin version 0.12 is available in Cloud Data Fusion version 6.10 and later. This release includes the following changes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Support for old SAP ODP RFCs is removed to align with SAP Note 3255746.</li>
<li>Messages have been updated when attempting to extract data from unsupported hierarchy data sources.</li>
</ul>
<p>We recommend upgrading all your pipelines to the latest SAP ODP plugin version, as earlier versions are no longer compliant with SAP Guidelines.</p>
<p><strong>Note:</strong> This release is backward compatible.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>SAP ODP plugin update available. Older versions no longer compliant.</summary>
    <title>Changed: SAP ODP Plugin Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-data-fusion:2025-07-16:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Oracle plugin version 1.12.3 is available in Cloud Data Fusion (via Hub) versions 6.11.0 and later, and 1.11.8 is available in Cloud Data Fusion (via Hub) version 6.10.</p>
<p>This release provides backward compatibility for recent schema changes, including the following:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/data-fusion/docs/release-notes#March_14_2023">Precisionless numbers</a>: In version 1.10.0, precisionless numbers were handled as strings.</li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/data-fusion/docs/release-notes#June_14_2023">Improved timestamp handling</a>: Version 1.11.0 introduced improvements to timestamp handling.</li>
</ul>
<p>To address backward compatibility for these changes, two new hidden fields are introduced in Oracle batch source configurations: <code>treatPrecisionlessNumAsDeci</code> and <code>treatAsOldTimestamp</code>. Both flags default to <code>false</code>. To enable these flags, edit the respective values in your exported connection JSON (if using connections) or pipeline JSON (if not using connections) before re-importing or re-deploying (<a href="https://cdap.atlassian.net/browse/PLUGIN-1893">PLUGIN-1893</a>).</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Oracle plugin has been updated to version 1.12.3 for Cloud Data Fusion versions 6.11.0 and later, and version 1.11.8 for version 6.10. This update includes backward compatibility for precisionless numbers and improved timestamp handling, with new hidden fields `treatPrecisionlessNumAsDeci` and `treatAsOldTimestamp` available for configuration.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Oracle plugin updated</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-data-fusion:2025-06-12:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Elasticsearch plugin version 1.11.0 is available in Cloud Data Fusion version 6.11.0. This release includes the following change:</p>
<ul>
<li>Upgraded Hadoop version for Elasticsearch plugin compatibility (<a href="https://cdap.atlassian.net/browse/PLUGIN-1881">PLUGIN-1881</a>).</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>The Elasticsearch plugin has been updated to version 1.11.0 in Cloud Data Fusion 6.11.0. This update includes an upgraded Hadoop version to ensure compatibility for the Elasticsearch plugin.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Elasticsearch plugin updated</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-data-fusion:2025-06-11:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The HTTP plugin version 1.4.4 is available in Cloud Data Fusion version 6.10.1. This release includes the following changes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Implemented the Client Credentials Grant flow for HTTP OAuth2, enabling authorized clients to securely access data using the <code>client_credentials</code> grant type. Client credentials can be passed through Basic Authentication header, in the request body, or as query parameters (<a href="https://cdap.atlassian.net/browse/PLUGIN-1872">PLUGIN-1872</a>).</li>
<li>Fixed an issue causing the HTTP Source plugin to throw a <code>NullPointerException</code> when the <code>BasePageIterator</code> received a null response (<a href="https://cdap.atlassian.net/browse/PLUGIN-1894">PLUGIN-1894</a>).</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>The HTTP plugin has been updated to version 1.4.4 in Cloud Data Fusion 6.10.1. This update introduces support for the Client Credentials Grant flow in HTTP OAuth2 and resolves a NullPointerException in the HTTP Source plugin.</summary>
    <title>Changed: HTTP plugin updated to version 1.4.4</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-data-fusion:2025-06-09:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud Data Fusion is available in the <code>northamerica-south1</code> (Mexico) region. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/data-fusion/pricing">Pricing</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud Data Fusion is now available in the `northamerica-south1` (Mexico) region. For more details on pricing, please refer to the documentation.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Cloud Data Fusion now in Mexico</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-data-fusion:2025-06-02:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://cloud.google.com/data-fusion/docs/how-to/configure-salesforce-batch-source">Salesforce plugin</a> version 1.6.10 is available in Cloud Data Fusion versions 6.10.1 and 6.11.0. This release includes the following changes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Upgraded Salesforce API version from 53.0 to 62.0 (<a href="https://cdap.atlassian.net/browse/PLUGIN-1891">PLUGIN-1891</a>).</li>
<li>Added a retry mechanism for all Salesforce API calls from the Salesforce plugin (<a href="https://cdap.atlassian.net/browse/PLUGIN-1892">PLUGIN-1892</a>).</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>The Salesforce plugin has been updated to version 1.6.10 in Cloud Data Fusion versions 6.10.1 and 6.11.0. This update includes an upgrade to Salesforce API version 62.0 and the addition of a retry mechanism for all Salesforce API calls.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Salesforce plugin updated</title>
  </entry>
</feed>