<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Google Cloud: AlloyDB for PostgreSQL</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: AlloyDB for PostgreSQL</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:alloydb-for-postgresql</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/alloydb-for-postgresql/" />
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:alloydb-for-postgresql:2025-07-14:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="text/markdown">You can now create an AlloyDB instance with a specific IP address range using the Google Cloud CLI, Terraform, or REST API. You can also override IP address range allocations configured during cluster creation. For more information, see [Create an instance with a specific IP address range](https://cloud.google.com/alloydb/docs/cluster-create#ip-instance). This feature is generally available [GA](https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages).</content>
    <summary>You can now create AlloyDB instances with specific IP address ranges using the Google Cloud CLI, Terraform, or REST API, and override existing IP range allocations.</summary>
    <title>Feature: AlloyDB instance IP address range support</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:alloydb-for-postgresql:2025-06-17:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="text/markdown">You can use the columnar engine to improve the performance of vector similarity
searches, specifically K-Nearest Neighbor (KNN) searches, when combined with
highly-selective predicate filtering. For more information, see
[Accelerate your filtered vector search](https://cloud.google.com/alloydb/docs/ai/perform-vector-search#accelerate-filtered-vector-search). This feature is in
[Preview](https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages).</content>
    <summary>A new feature allows for improved performance of vector similarity searches, specifically K-Nearest Neighbor (KNN) searches, when combined with highly-selective predicate filtering. This feature is currently in Preview.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Improved Vector Search Performance</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:alloydb-for-postgresql:2025-06-02:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="text/markdown">You can let [AlloyDB automatically create Private Service Connect endpoints](https://cloud.google.com/alloydb/docs/configure-private-service-connect#create_the_endpoint_automatically)
for authorized projects when you create Private Service Connect-enabled
instances, based on your defined service connection policy. This feature is generally available ([GA](https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages)).</content>
    <summary>AlloyDB now supports automatic creation of Private Service Connect endpoints for authorized projects, simplifying network configuration. This feature is now generally available.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Automatic Private Service Connect Endpoints for AlloyDB</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:alloydb-for-postgresql:2025-06-02:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="text/markdown">You can create AlloyDB clusters with [Private Services Connect](https://cloud.google.com/alloydb/docs/configure-private-service-connect#create_the_endpoint_automatically) through the Google Cloud console.</content>
    <summary>You can now create AlloyDB clusters using Private Services Connect directly from the Google Cloud console.</summary>
    <title>Feature: AlloyDB Private Services Connect Support</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:alloydb-for-postgresql:2025-05-29:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="text/markdown">You can now
[start, stop, and restart your primary and read pool AlloyDB instances](https://cloud.google.com/alloydb/docs/instance-start-stop-restart)
using the Google Cloud console and the Google Cloud CLI. This feature is
generally available
([GA](https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages)).</content>
    <summary>You can now start, stop, and restart your AlloyDB instances using the Google Cloud console and CLI. This feature is now generally available.</summary>
    <title>Feature: AlloyDB instance management is now GA</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:alloydb-for-postgresql:2025-05-27:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="text/markdown">The [AlloyDB Omni Kubernetes](/alloydb/omni/current/docs/deploy-kubernetes) operator version 1.4.1 is generally available (GA) and includes the following bug fixes:

* Fix for overriding replication related parameters. This fix lets you override the `wal_keep_size` value. For more information, see [Work with cross-data-center replication](/alloydb/omni/current/docs/cross-data-center-replication/work-with-cross-data-center-replication). This fix requires database version 15.7.1 or later.
* 63-character DBCluster names are supported, which lets you define clearer and more descriptive cluster names.
* Various bug fixes are implemented to enhance stability and the user experience.</content>
    <summary>The AlloyDB Omni Kubernetes operator 1.4.1 is now generally available, featuring support for 63-character DBCluster names and fixes for replication parameters and overall stability.</summary>
    <title>Feature: AlloyDB Omni Kubernetes Operator 1.4.1 Released</title>
  </entry>
</feed>