<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Google Cloud Managed Service for Apache Kafka</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Google Cloud Managed Service for Apache Kafka</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-managed-service-for-apache-kafka</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/google-cloud-managed-service-for-apache-kafka/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-managed-service-for-apache-kafka:2025-12-10:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Using <code>gcloud</code> or the REST API, you can now view the following
information about a Managed Service for Apache Kafka cluster:</p>
<ul>
<li>Broker node IDs and indexes</li>
<li>The zones where brokers are located</li>
<li>The Kafka version that the cluster is running</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, see
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/managed-service-for-apache-kafka/docs/view-cluster">View a Kafka cluster</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now view broker node IDs, locations, and Kafka versions for your Managed Service for Apache Kafka clusters using `gcloud` or the REST API. This provides greater visibility into your cluster's configuration.</summary>
    <title>Feature: View Kafka cluster details</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-managed-service-for-apache-kafka:2025-12-08:change:0</id>
    <published>2025-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Kafka Connect cluster workers can now reach any endpoint that is accessible from
the worker (primary) subnetwork. Previously, to extend worker connectivity to
other subnets within the same VPC network, you had to specify
these subnets in the cluster configuration. The <code>additionalSubnets</code> field is now
ignored, and this configuration setting has been removed from the
Google Cloud console. For more information, see
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/managed-service-for-apache-kafka/docs/connect-cluster/create-connect-cluster#worker-subnet">Worker (primary) subnet</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Kafka Connect workers can now access any endpoint from their primary subnetwork, simplifying network configuration. Previously, you needed to explicitly list additional subnets, but this is no longer required and the configuration option has been removed.</summary>
    <title>Change: Kafka Connect network access expanded</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-managed-service-for-apache-kafka:2025-12-08:deprecated:1</id>
    <published>2025-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <code>additionalSubnets</code> field in the
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/managed-service-for-apache-kafka/docs/reference/rest/v1/projects.locations.connectClusters#connectnetworkconfig"><code>ConnectNetworkConfig</code></a>
REST API resource is deprecated. Connect cluster workers can reach any endpoint
that is accessible from <code>primarySubnet</code> subnetwork.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The `additionalSubnets` field in the `ConnectNetworkConfig` resource is deprecated. Connect cluster workers can reach any endpoint accessible from the `primarySubnet` subnetwork.</summary>
    <title>Deprecated: `additionalSubnets` field deprecated</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-managed-service-for-apache-kafka:2025-10-01:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Support for Kafka Connect is now <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">generally available</a> (GA). Kafka Connect lets you stream data at scale between Managed Service for Apache Kafka clusters and other systems, such as external Kafka deployments, BigQuery, Cloud Storage, or Pub/Sub. For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/managed-service-for-apache-kafka/docs/kafka-connect-overview">Kafka Connect overview</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Stream data at scale between Managed Service for Apache Kafka and other systems.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Kafka Connect Now Generally Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-managed-service-for-apache-kafka:2025-09-24:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Integration with <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc-service-controls/docs/supported-products#table_managed_kafka">VPC Service Controls</a> is <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">generally available</a> (GA).</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Integration with VPC Service Controls is now generally available. This feature enhances security by allowing you to control data access to your managed Kafka service.</summary>
    <title>Feature: VPC Service Controls integration now generally available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-managed-service-for-apache-kafka:2025-09-17:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Managed Service for Apache Kafka now supports <a href="https://cloud.google.com/managed-service-for-apache-kafka/docs/custom-constraints">Organization Policy Service custom constraints</a>. Custom constraints allow you to restrict specific operations on Managed Service for Apache Kafka resources.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now use custom constraints with Managed Service for Apache Kafka to restrict specific operations on your Kafka resources.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Managed Service for Apache Kafka now supports custom constraints</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-managed-service-for-apache-kafka:2025-09-09:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>General availability: You can now use mutual TLS (mTLS) for certificate-based authentication with your Managed Service for Apache Kafka brokers. This feature is available for clusters created after June 24, 2025. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/managed-service-for-apache-kafka/docs/authn-types-kafka">Authentication types for Kafka brokers</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Mutual TLS (mTLS) authentication is now generally available for Managed Service for Apache Kafka, enhancing security for your Kafka clusters. This feature supports certificate-based authentication and is available for clusters created after June 24, 2025. For detailed information, refer to the official documentation on authentication types.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Mutual TLS (mTLS) for Apache Kafka Now Generally Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-managed-service-for-apache-kafka:2025-09-04:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Integration with <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc-service-controls/docs/supported-products#table_managed_kafka">VPC Service Controls</a> is in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">preview</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>We're excited to announce that the integration with VPC Service Controls for Kafka is now available in preview. This feature allows you to enhance your data security by controlling network access to your Kafka services.</summary>
    <title>Feature: VPC Service Controls integration for Kafka is now in preview</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-managed-service-for-apache-kafka:2025-09-02:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Managed Service for Apache Kafka now supports <a href="https://cloud.google.com/security/compliance/hipaa">HIPAA Compliance on Google Cloud</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Managed Service for Apache Kafka now supports HIPAA compliance, allowing you to run sensitive workloads in the cloud.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Managed Service for Apache Kafka now HIPAA compliant</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-managed-service-for-apache-kafka:2025-07-15:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Google Cloud Managed Service for Apache Kafka service creates new brokers automatically based on the memory and vCPU configuration of the cluster. When you update a cluster's size, the service now performs a safety check to verify that individual brokers have sufficient capacity for their portion of the traffic. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/managed-service-for-apache-kafka/docs/update-cluster#update-memory-vCPUs">Update the memory and vCPUs</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Auto-creation of Kafka brokers based on cluster configuration.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Kafka Broker Autoscaling</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-managed-service-for-apache-kafka:2025-07-09:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>General availability: Metrics for all Google Cloud Managed Service for Apache Kafka resources are now available, with some exceptions. Exceptions include the <code>request_count</code> and <code>topic_error_count</code> metrics for Kafka clusters and Kafka Connect connectors. For a list of supported metrics, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/monitoring/api/metrics_gcp#gcp-managedkafka">Metrics for Cloud Managed Service for Apache Kafka</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Metrics for all Google Cloud Managed Service for Apache Kafka resources are now available. For a list of supported metrics, see the documentation.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Metrics for Managed Service for Apache Kafka Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-managed-service-for-apache-kafka:2025-05-29:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Public preview: Google Managed Service for Apache Kafka now offers schema registry support. For more information about the feature, see the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/managed-service-for-apache-kafka/docs/schema-registry/schema-registry-overview">schema registry overview</a> or <a href="https://cloud.google.com/managed-service-for-apache-kafka/docs/quickstart-avro">get started with an Avro producer in Java</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Google Managed Service for Apache Kafka now supports schema registry, a centralized repository for managing data schemas. This feature helps ensure data compatibility and consistency across your data streams.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Managed Kafka adds schema registry support</title>
  </entry>
</feed>