<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Cloud SQL for MySQL</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Cloud SQL for MySQL</subtitle>
  <updated>2026-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/cloud-sql-for-mysql/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2026-01-15:feature:0</id>
    <published>2026-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2026-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud SQL for MySQL now supports fast clone operations within the same zone (<a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">GA</a>).</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/clone-instance">Clone an instance</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL for MySQL now offers fast clone operations within the same zone. This feature allows for quicker instance duplication, enhancing operational efficiency. Learn more about cloning your MySQL instances.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Fast MySQL Clone Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-12-17:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can build data agents that interact with the data in your
database using conversational language. Use these data agents as tools to
empower your applications. For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/data-agent-overview">Data agents overview</a>. This feature is available in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">Preview</a>, and access to it requires a <a href="https://forms.gle/pJByTWfenZAWbaXo7">sign-up</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Empower your applications by building data agents that interact with your database using conversational language. This feature is currently in preview and requires sign-up to access.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Build conversational data agents</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-12-16:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud SQL enhanced backups are now generally available (<a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">GA</a>).</p>
<p>With enhanced backups, backups are managed and stored in a centralized
backup management project that leverages the
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/backup-disaster-recovery">Backup and DR service</a>, and
provides enforced retention, granular scheduling, and longer retention.</p>
<p>Enhanced backups now also support
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/backup-recovery/restore">point-in-time-recovery (PITR) after instance deletion</a>.</p>
<p>For more information about the available options and their limitations, see
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/backup-recovery/backup-options">Backup options</a>.
For more information about enhanced backups pricing, see
<a href="https://cloud.google.com/backup-disaster-recovery/pricing">Backup and DR pricing</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL enhanced backups are now generally available, offering centralized management, enforced retention, granular scheduling, and longer retention periods through the Backup and DR service. This feature also supports point-in-time recovery even after instance deletion.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud SQL Enhanced Backups Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-11-21:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To help prevent out-of-memory (OOM) events, you can enable managed buffer pool
for Cloud SQL for MySQL 8.0 and later instances. When you enable managed buffer
pool, Cloud SQL reduces the value of the
<code>innodb_buffer_pool_size</code> configuration and frees up memory when memory usage
is high, and the instance is in danger of an OOM event.
After memory usage stabilizes at a lower value, MySQL increases the
value of <code>innodb_buffer_pool_size</code> incrementally to its original value.</p>
<p>To enable managed buffer pool, your Cloud SQL instance must use a
maintenance version of <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/maintenance-changelog/"><code>[$MYSQL_VERSION].R20251004.01_07</code></a>
or later. You can't enable managed buffer pool for instances that use a
shared core or for instances that are running MySQL 5.6 or MySQL 5.7.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/optimize-high-memory-usage#enable-managed-buffer-pool">Enable managed buffer pool</a>.
Support for managed buffer pool is in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">Preview</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Prevent OOM events with managed buffer pool for Cloud SQL for MySQL 8.0+ instances. This feature dynamically adjusts the innodb_buffer_pool_size to manage memory usage and avoid Out-of-Memory errors.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Managed buffer pool for Cloud SQL for MySQL</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-11-18:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud SQL for MySQL 8.4.6 is upgraded to MySQL 8.4.7.
For more information, see the <a href="https://dev.mysql.com/doc/relnotes/mysql/8.4/en/news-8-4-7.html">MySQL 8.4.7 Release Notes</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL for MySQL has been upgraded to version 8.4.7.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud SQL for MySQL 8.4.7 upgrade</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-11-17:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud SQL now offers a free trial instance for both existing and new Google
Cloud customers. A free trial instance lets you test advanced Cloud SQL
capabilities and features for up to 30 days without any financial commitment.</p>
<p>For information about a free trial instance, and its inclusions and conditions,
see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/free-trial-instance">Free trial instance overview</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Test Cloud SQL features for free for up to 30 days. Available for new and existing Google Cloud customers.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud SQL Free Trial</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-11-14:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud SQL for MySQL now supports <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/read-pool-autoscaling">read pool autoscaling</a>
<a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">(GA)</a>, which helps you
more easily manage your application's workload needs.</p>
<p>This feature automates read pool scale in and scale out operations based on one
or both of the following conditions:</p>
<ul>
<li>Allowed CPU usage of the read pool</li>
<li>Allowed number of client connections to the read pool</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Automate read pool scaling operations based on CPU usage or client connections.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud SQL for MySQL now supports read pool autoscaling</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-11-13:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud SQL for MySQL now lets you have more control over the number of results
that are returned when you perform an ANN vector search with filters.
You can use iterative filtering when the selective filters of the
<code>WHERE</code> clause in your ANN search query produce fewer results
than the number of results specified in your <code>LIMIT</code> clause.</p>
<p>To enable iterative filtering for your ANN search query, set the
<code>cloudsql_vector_iterative_filtering</code> flag to <code>ON</code>.
You can set the flag at a session or global level.</p>
<p>To enable and use iterative filtering for your ANN search query, you must have
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/maintenance-changelog/"><code>[MYSQL_$VERSION].R20251004.01_07</code></a>
or later installed on your MySQL instance.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/search-filter-vector-embeddings#ann">Search approximate nearest neighbors (ANN)</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now control the number of results returned during ANN vector searches with filters in Cloud SQL for MySQL. Iterative filtering can be used when filters yield fewer results than specified in the LIMIT clause. Enable this feature by setting the `cloudsql_vector_iterative_filtering` flag to ON.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Control ANN search results</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-11-12:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud SQL for MySQL now supports minor version
<a href="https://dev.mysql.com/doc/relnotes/mysql/8.0/en/news-8-0-44.html">8.0.44</a>.
To upgrade your existing
instance to the new version, see
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/upgrade-minor-db-version#manual-upgrade">Upgrade the database minor version</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL for MySQL instances now support the latest MySQL minor version 8.0.44. You can upgrade your existing instances to take advantage of this new version.</summary>
    <title>Feature: MySQL 8.0.44 support in Cloud SQL</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-11-10:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud SQL now provides brute-force detection and protection for your Cloud SQL
instances. This helps protect your instances from brute-force access attempts
by identifying the source and mitigating the risk caused by these attempts.
For more information, see
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/use-brute-force-protection">Use brute-force protection</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL now offers brute-force detection and protection to safeguard your instances from unauthorized access attempts. This feature identifies and mitigates risks associated with such attacks.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Brute-force Protection for Cloud SQL Instances</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-11-04:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud SQL now supports the
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/upgrade-minor-db-version#auto-upgrade">automatic minor version upgrade</a>
for Cloud SQL for MySQL 8.0.35 or later instances.
If your Cloud SQL for MySQL instance is running MySQL 8.0.35 or later, but
you didn't select a specific minor version when you created the instance (<code>databaseVersion=MYSQL_8_0</code>),
then your MySQL instance is upgraded automatically to the <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/sql/docs/db-versions#database-version-support"><strong>default minor version</strong></a>
of Cloud SQL for MySQL 8.0 during its <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/maintenance">regular scheduled maintenance update</a>.</p>
<p>All eligible Cloud SQL for MySQL instances receive the first automatic
minor version upgrade during the rollout of <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/maintenance-changelog/mysql-8-0#mysql_8_0_%5B18,-26,-27,-28,-30,-31,-32,-33,-34,-35,-36,-37,-39,-40,-41,-42,-43%5D.r20251004.01_07"><code>MYSQL_8_0_[N].R20251004.01_07</code></a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL for MySQL instances running version 8.0.35 or later can now benefit from automatic minor version upgrades. Eligible instances will receive their first upgrade during the rollout of a specific maintenance update.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Automatic minor version upgrade for Cloud SQL for MySQL</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-10-28:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud SQL has enhanced the optimized writes feature, which includes
an improved crash recovery algorithm to reduce crash recovery time and utilizes
unused disk I/O throughput adaptively to accelerate buffer pool warm-up.
The optimized writes feature provides a set of write performance improvements
that adjust MySQL configurations dynamically based on workload demand and
underlying infrastructure.</p>
<p>By default these improvements are enabled for all new
Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus edition instances that you create or that you upgrade
to from Cloud SQL Enterprise edition.</p>
<p>For more information about optimized writes, see
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/flags#tips-optimized-write">Configure database flags</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL's optimized writes feature now offers faster crash recovery and adaptive buffer pool warm-up. These performance enhancements are enabled by default for new Enterprise Plus instances.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Optimized Writes in Cloud SQL</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-10-17:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud SQL Enterprise edition now supports a new machine series called the N4 machine series. This machine series provides balanced price-to-performance and uses the Hyperdisk Balanced storage. You can create custom machine types for the N4 machine series with up to 80 vCPUs and up to 640 GB memory. The N4 machine series is <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">generally available</a> (GA).</p>
<p>For more information about the N4 machine series and its availability, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/machine-series-overview">Machine series overview</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The N4 machine series is now available for Cloud SQL Enterprise Edition, offering balanced price-to-performance with Hyperdisk Balanced storage and customizable machine types.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New N4 machine series for Cloud SQL Enterprise Edition</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-10-17:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/machine-series-overview#c4a">C4A machine series</a> is now <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">generally available</a> (GA).</p>
<p>The C4A machine series is supported for Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus edition instances, and provides optimized price-performance and delivers predictable high performance for high demand Cloud SQL workloads. It uses the Hyperdisk Balanced storage.</p>
<p>For more information about the C4A machine series and its availability, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/machine-series-overview">Machine series overview</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The C4A machine series is now generally available for Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus edition instances. This series offers optimized price-performance and predictable high performance for demanding workloads, utilizing Hyperdisk Balanced storage.</summary>
    <title>Feature: C4A machine series now generally available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-09-29:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/write-sql-gemini#fix-query">use Gemini's capabilities to fix errors in a query within Cloud SQL Studio</a> (<a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">Preview</a>).</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Gemini can now help you fix errors in your SQL queries within Cloud SQL Studio. This feature is currently in Preview.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Fix SQL query errors with Gemini</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-09-25:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud SQL for MySQL now supports minor version 8.0.43. To upgrade your existing instance to the new version, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/upgrade-minor-db-version">Upgrade the database minor version</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL for MySQL has been updated to support minor version 8.0.43. You can now upgrade your existing instances to this latest version. For instructions, refer to the documentation on upgrading database minor versions.</summary>
    <title>Feature: MySQL 8.0.43 Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-09-24:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud SQL for MySQL 8.4.5 is upgraded to MySQL 8.4.6. For more information, see the <a href="https://dev.mysql.com/doc/relnotes/mysql/8.4/en/news-8-4-6.html">MySQL 8.4.6 Release Notes</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL for MySQL has been upgraded to version 8.4.6. This update includes the latest improvements and fixes from the MySQL 8.4.6 release.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud SQL for MySQL 8.4.6 Upgrade</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-09-23:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now provision, manage and query your databases using the dedicated Gemini CLI extension for Cloud SQL for MySQL. The extension provides full lifecycle control of your database—from provisioning instances, to exploring schemas and troubleshooting issues—from your command-line interface.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/pre-built-tools-with-mcp-toolbox">Use Cloud SQL for MySQL with MCP, Gemini CLI, and other agents</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Manage your Cloud SQL for MySQL databases directly from your command line using the new Gemini CLI extension. Provision instances, explore schemas, and troubleshoot issues with ease.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Gemini CLI for Cloud SQL for MySQL</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-09-23:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now retain point-in-time recovery (PITR) logs for an instance after its deletion for a specified retention period. These logs can be used to restore the deleted instance to a specific point in time. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/backup-recovery/restore#deleted-instance">Restore a deleted instance using PITR</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now retain point-in-time recovery (PITR) logs for an instance even after it has been deleted. This allows you to restore the deleted instance to a specific point in time within a defined retention period.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Point-in-Time Recovery Logs Retained After Deletion</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-09-08:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud SQL read pools are now generally available and provide operational simplicity and scaling for your read workloads.</p>
<p>Read pools provide a single endpoint in front of up to 20 read pool nodes and automatically load balance traffic.</p>
<p>You can scale your read pool in several ways:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Scale in or out</strong>: scale load balancing capacity horizontally by modifying the number of read pool nodes in the read pool. Each read pool supports up to 20 read pool nodes.</li>
<li><strong>Scale up or down</strong>: scale load balancing capacity vertically by modifying the machine type associated with a read pool node. Once defined, configuration is uniformly applied across each read pool node in the read pool.</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, see
<a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/about-read-pools">About read pools</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL read pools are now generally available, offering a simplified way to scale read workloads. They provide a single endpoint that load balances traffic across up to 20 nodes, which can be scaled horizontally or vertically.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud SQL read pools now available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-09-08:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can have Cloud SQL create a <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/about-private-service-connect#psc-endpoint">Private Service Connect</a> endpoint automatically. You can use this endpoint to access Cloud SQL instances through a VPC network. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/configure-private-service-connect#create-endpoint-automatically">Create a Private Service Connect endpoint automatically</a>.</p>
<p>This feature is now generally available (<a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">GA</a>).</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new feature allows for the automatic creation of Private Service Connect endpoints for Cloud SQL instances, enabling access through VPC networks. This feature is now generally available.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Private Service Connect endpoint for Cloud SQL</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-09-04:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The release note on <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/release-notes#August_13_2025">August 13, 2025</a> regarding Private Service Connect (PSC) outbound connectivity has been updated.</p>
<p>PSC outbound connectivity is required for <a href="https://cloud.google.com/database-migration/docs/homogeneous-migrations">homogeneous migrations</a> to PSC-enabled Cloud SQL instances using <a href="https://cloud.google.com/database-migration/docs">Database Migration Service</a>. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/about-private-service-connect#psc-outbound">PSC outbound connections</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The release notes for Private Service Connect (PSC) outbound connectivity have been updated as of August 13, 2025. This update is relevant for homogeneous migrations to PSC-enabled Cloud SQL instances utilizing the Database Migration Service.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Private Service Connect Outbound Connectivity Updated</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-09-03:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud SQL Managed Connection Pooling is now generally available (<a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">GA</a>). Managed Connection Pooling lets you scale your workloads by optimizing resource utilization for Cloud SQL instances using pooling.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/managed-connection-pooling">Managed Connection Pooling overview</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL Managed Connection Pooling is now GA. This feature helps optimize resource utilization for Cloud SQL instances through pooling, enabling better workload scalability.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud SQL Managed Connection Pooling Now Generally Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-09-03:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now enable your instance to take a final backup at instance deletion and define its retention period by setting the final backup <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/instance-settings">instance setting</a>.</p>
<p>You can also create a <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/org-policy/custom-org-policy">custom organization policy</a> to define final backup instance settings.
For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/backup-recovery/backups#final-backup">Final backup</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now enable your instance to take a final backup at instance deletion and define its retention period by setting the final backup instance setting.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Instance backup on deletion</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-08-21:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can save and manage SQL queries in Cloud SQL Studio. This feature is in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">Preview</a>. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/saved-queries">Saved queries overview</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Save and manage SQL queries in Cloud SQL Studio.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud SQL Studio Feature</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-08-15:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Now you can use <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/about-private-service-connect#psc-backend">Private Service Connect backends</a>, as an alternative to Private Service Connect endpoints, to access Cloud SQL instances.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Private Service Connect backends are now available as an alternative to endpoints for Cloud SQL instance access.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Private Service Connect Option for Cloud SQL</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-08-15:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Now you can create an IPv6 endpoint for Private Service Connect (PSC) connections. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/configure-private-service-connect#create-psc-endpoint">Connect to an instance using Private Service Connect</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Create an IPv6 endpoint for Private Service Connect connections.</summary>
    <title>Feature: IPv6 Endpoint for PSC</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-08-15:deprecated:2</id>
    <published>2025-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can no longer set a deny maintenance period for instances that are running a maintenance version older than 12 months. To update your instance, <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/self-service-maintenance">perform self-service maintenance</a> or wait until the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/set-maintenance-window#find-maintenance-api">next maintenance window</a> to update your instance automatically. For more information about maintenance, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/maintenance">Maintenance updates on Cloud SQL instances</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Deny maintenance periods are no longer available for instances with older maintenance versions.</summary>
    <title>Deprecated: Maintenance Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-08-13:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud SQL now supports Private Service Connect (PSC) outbound connectivity. With PSC outbound connectivity, you can attach a PSC interface to your existing Cloud SQL PSC-enabled instances to allow your instances to make outbound connections to your network. This is required for <a href="https://cloud.google.com/database-migration/docs/homogeneous-migrations">homogeneous migrations</a> to PSC-enabled Cloud SQL instances using <a href="https://cloud.google.com/database-migration/docs">Database Migration Service</a>. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/about-private-service-connect#psc-outbound">PSC outbound connections</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL now supports Private Service Connect (PSC) outbound connectivity, enabling instances to connect to your network. This feature is essential for homogeneous migrations to PSC-enabled Cloud SQL instances using Database Migration Service.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Private Service Connect for Cloud SQL</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-08-07:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud SQL for Enterprise Plus edition supports quality enhancements for <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/observe-troubleshoot-with-ai">AI-assisted troubleshooting</a>. With AI-assisted troubleshooting, you can resolve complex database performance issues like <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/troubleshoot-slow-queries">slow queries</a> and <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/troubleshoot-high-database-load">high load</a> for your instances in a guided manner. To use AI-assisted troubleshooting, you need <a href="https://cloud.google.com/gemini/docs/cloud-assist/overview">Gemini Cloud Assist</a> and <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/using-query-insights#enable-insights">query insights</a> for Enterprise Plus edition.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>AI-assisted troubleshooting for Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Cloud SQL Updates</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-08-04:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud SQL for MySQL now supports <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/model-endpoint-overview">model endpoint management</a> to help you build your generative AI applications. With model endpoint management, you can register and call remote AI model providers or access the Vertex AI integration. This feature is in <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">Preview</a> and available in Cloud SQL for MySQL version 8.0.36 and later, which includes Cloud SQL for MySQL version 8.4.</p>
<p>To use model endpoint management, update your instance to <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/maintenance-changelog"><code>[MySQL version].R20250531.01_14</code></a> or later, and make sure that you've enabled the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/integrate-cloud-sql-with-vertex-ai">integration with Vertex AI</a> on your instance. You can <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/self-service-maintenance">perform self-service maintenance</a> or wait until the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/set-maintenance-window#find-maintenance-api">next maintenance window</a> to update the maintenance version of your instance automatically.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL for MySQL now supports model endpoint management, allowing you to build generative AI applications by registering and calling remote AI model providers or accessing Vertex AI integration. This feature is available for MySQL version 8.0.36 and later.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Feature: Model Endpoint Management in Cloud SQL for MySQL</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-07-31:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud SQL now offers two options of backup services to manage your instance's backups:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Enhanced backups</strong> (<a href="https://cloud.google.com/products?#product-launch-stages">Preview</a>): backups are managed and stored in a centralized backup management project that leverages the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/backup-disaster-recovery">Backup and DR service</a>, and provides enforced retention, granular scheduling, and longer retention.</li>
<li><strong>Standard backups</strong> (existing option): backups are created, managed, and stored in the same project as your Cloud SQL instances.</li>
</ul>
<p>You can choose between these options based on your instance's requirements and needs. Although instances can't use both backup options at the same time, Cloud SQL gives you the ability to switch between these backup options as necessary.</p>
<p>For more information about the available options and their limitations, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/backup-recovery/backups#backup-options">Backup options</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL introduces enhanced backups with centralized management and longer retention, alongside standard backups. You can switch between options as needed.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud SQL Backup Options</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-07-02:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The write endpoint feature for Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus edition instances is now <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">generally available</a> (GA). This endpoint is a global domain name service (DNS) name and resolves to the IP address of the current primary Cloud SQL instance that's enabled with private services access.</p>
<p>By using a write endpoint, you can avoid having to make application connection changes after performing a switchover or replica failover operation to test or mitigate a region failure.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/connect-to-instance-using-write-endpoint">Connect to an instance using a write endpoint</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Cloud SQL write endpoint for Enterprise Plus edition instances is now generally available. This feature provides a stable global domain name, resolving to the primary instance</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud SQL write endpoint now available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-06-17:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You no longer have to upgrade your instance to MySQL 8.0.37 before you upgrade to Cloud SQL for MySQL 8.4. You can upgrade to Cloud SQL for MySQL 8.4 from any minor version of Cloud SQL for MySQL 8.0. For more information about upgrading the major version of a Cloud SQL instance, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/upgrade-major-db-version-inplace">Upgrade the database major version-place</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now upgrade to Cloud SQL for MySQL 8.4 from any minor version of MySQL 8.0, removing the previous requirement to upgrade to 8.0.37 first. For more details on major version upgrades, refer to the documentation.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Cloud SQL for MySQL 8.4 upgrade flexibility</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-07-01:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The write endpoint feature for Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus edition instances is now <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">generally available</a> (GA). This endpoint is a global domain name service (DNS) name and resolves to the IP address of the current primary Cloud SQL instance that's enabled with private services access.</p>
<p>By using a write endpoint, you can avoid having to make application connection changes after performing a switchover or replica failover operation to test or mitigate a regional failure.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/connect-to-instance-using-write-endpoint">Connect to an instance using a write endpoint</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus instances now support a generally available write endpoint. This global DNS name resolves to the primary instance's IP address, simplifying application connections after failover events and eliminating the need for manual connection changes.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus write endpoint now generally available</title>
  </entry>
</feed>