<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Cloud SQL for MySQL</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Cloud SQL for MySQL</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/cloud-sql-for-mysql/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-07-02:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The write endpoint feature for Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus edition instances is now <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">generally available</a> (GA). This endpoint is a global domain name service (DNS) name and resolves to the IP address of the current primary Cloud SQL instance that's enabled with private services access.</p>
<p>By using a write endpoint, you can avoid having to make application connection changes after performing a switchover or replica failover operation to test or mitigate a region failure.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/connect-to-instance-using-write-endpoint">Connect to an instance using a write endpoint</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Cloud SQL write endpoint for Enterprise Plus edition instances is now generally available. This feature provides a stable global domain name, resolving to the primary instance</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud SQL write endpoint now available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-06-17:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You no longer have to upgrade your instance to MySQL 8.0.37 before you upgrade to Cloud SQL for MySQL 8.4. You can upgrade to Cloud SQL for MySQL 8.4 from any minor version of Cloud SQL for MySQL 8.0. For more information about upgrading the major version of a Cloud SQL instance, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/upgrade-major-db-version-inplace">Upgrade the database major version-place</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now upgrade to Cloud SQL for MySQL 8.4 from any minor version of MySQL 8.0, removing the previous requirement to upgrade to 8.0.37 first. For more details on major version upgrades, refer to the documentation.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Cloud SQL for MySQL 8.4 upgrade flexibility</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-mysql:2025-07-01:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The write endpoint feature for Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus edition instances is now <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">generally available</a> (GA). This endpoint is a global domain name service (DNS) name and resolves to the IP address of the current primary Cloud SQL instance that's enabled with private services access.</p>
<p>By using a write endpoint, you can avoid having to make application connection changes after performing a switchover or replica failover operation to test or mitigate a regional failure.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/mysql/connect-to-instance-using-write-endpoint">Connect to an instance using a write endpoint</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus instances now support a generally available write endpoint. This global DNS name resolves to the primary instance's IP address, simplifying application connections after failover events and eliminating the need for manual connection changes.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus write endpoint now generally available</title>
  </entry>
</feed>