<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Google Agentspace</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Google Agentspace</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-agentspace</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/google-agentspace/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-agentspace:2025-10-02:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Google Agentspace: Configure prompt chips</strong></p>
<p>You can create, delete, edit, and enable or disable Google-provided and custom prompts that provide better guidance to your users.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/agentspace/docs/configure-prompt-chips">Configure prompt chips</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Configure prompt chips to guide users with custom and Google-provided prompts.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Prompt Chips Configuration</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-agentspace:2025-10-02:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Google Agentspace: Generate images using Nano Banana (GA)</strong></p>
<p>Image generation and editing with Nano Banana (Gemini 2.5 Flash Image) is generally available (GA) in Google Agentspace across Global, EU, and US multi-regions.</p>
<p>For more information on generating images, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/agentspace/docs/assistant-analyze#generate_an_image">Generate an image</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Image generation and editing powered by Nano Banana (Gemini 2.5 Flash Image) is now generally available in Google Agentspace. This feature is accessible across Global, EU, and US multi-regions, allowing users to create and modify images within the platform.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Nano Banana Image Generation Now Available in Agentspace</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-agentspace:2025-09-26:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Google Agentspace: Manage image and video generation on the web app</strong></p>
<p>By default, image and video generation are enabled in the Agentspace web app. To turn off these features, admins must navigate to the <strong>Configurations &gt; Feature Management</strong> tab, and turn off the <strong>Enable video generation</strong> and <strong>Enable image generation</strong> options.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Admins can manage image and video generation settings within the Agentspace web app.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Image and Video Generation</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-agentspace:2025-09-24:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Google Agentspace: Knowledge base filter for catalog entities in ServiceNow connectors (GA)</strong></p>
<p>In your ServiceNow connectors, you can filter your knowledge base entities by catalog IDs. This lets you selectively ingest only those catalog entities whose <code>catalogSysId</code> matches the filter.
If no values are specified, then the connector ingests all catalog entities. This feature is Generally available (GA).</p>
<p>For information about ServiceNow connectors, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/agentspace/docs/connect-servicenow">Connect ServiceNow</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now filter knowledge base entities in ServiceNow connectors by catalog ID to selectively ingest data. If no filter is applied, all catalog entities will be ingested. This feature is Generally Available.</summary>
    <title>Feature: ServiceNow Connectors Now Support Filtering Knowledge Base Entities by Catalog ID</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-agentspace:2025-09-24:changed:1</id>
    <published>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Google Agentspace: Interface updates</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>File uploads can be canceled at any time.</li>
<li>The Star and Share buttons now appear after a user has initiated a session by submitting a prompt.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>File uploads can now be canceled at any time. Additionally, the Star and Share buttons are now visible after a user has started a session by submitting a prompt.</summary>
    <title>Changed: File uploads can be canceled</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-agentspace:2025-09-23:breaking:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Google Agentspace: Change in ACLs for incidents in ServiceNow</strong></p>
<p>The access-control list (ACL) behavior for ServiceNow incidents has significantly changed, from too permissive to least-privilege behavior. This change drastically reduces the possibility of data leaks, but might be too restrictive for your needs.</p>
<p>For more information about ServiceNow, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/agentspace/docs/connect-servicenow">Connect ServiceNow</a> and <a href="https://cloud.google.com/agentspace/docs/assistant-actions-servicenow">Add ServiceNow actions</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>ACLs for ServiceNow incidents have been updated to a least-privilege model, enhancing data security and reducing leak risks.</summary>
    <title>Breaking: ServiceNow Incident ACLs Updated</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-agentspace:2025-09-15:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Google Agentspace and Google NotebookLM Enterprise: Model Armor</strong></p>
<p>Model Armor helps proactively screen prompts and responses within Agentspace apps and NotebookLM Enterprise instances. For more information on how administrators can enable this feature, see:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/agentspace/docs/enable-model-armor">Enable Model Armor in Google Agentspace</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/agentspace/notebooklm-enterprise/docs/enable-model-armor">Enable Model Armor in NotebookLM Enterprise</a></li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>Model Armor proactively screens prompts and responses in Agentspace apps and NotebookLM Enterprise. This feature helps enhance security and control over your AI applications.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Model Armor: Proactive Screening for Agentspace and NotebookLM Enterprise</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-agentspace:2025-09-15:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Google Agentspace: Real-time sync (Public preview)</strong></p>
<p>Real-time sync uses webhooks to receive notifications when data is created, updated, and deleted in a third-party data source. Notifications typically arrive within minutes of the event. The following data stores support real-time sync:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/agentspace/agentspace-enterprise/docs/connect-jira-cloud#enable_real-time_sync">Jira Cloud</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/agentspace/agentspace-enterprise/docs/connect-confluence-cloud#enable_real-time_sync">Confluence Cloud</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/agentspace/agentspace-enterprise/docs/connect-onedrive#real-time-sync">Microsoft OneDrive</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/agentspace/agentspace-enterprise/docs/connect-sharepoint-online#real-time-sync">Microsoft SharePoint Online</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/agentspace/agentspace-enterprise/docs/connect-servicenow#real-time-sync">ServiceNow</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Support for real-time sync for these data stores is in Public preview.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Real-time sync is now available in public preview. This feature allows you to receive notifications when data is created, updated, or deleted in supported third-party data sources within minutes of the event.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Real-time sync now in public preview</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-agentspace:2025-09-11:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Google Agentspace: Interface updates</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The LLM model selector has moved from the search bar to directly below the product logo in the top-left corner.</li>
<li>The web grounding tool and source has been renamed <em>Google Search</em> and <em>Enterprise web search,</em> depending on the type of web grounding configured.</li>
<li>The <em>Sources</em> button in the search bar has been renamed <em>Data.</em></li>
<li>The <em>Data</em> menu (formerly <em>Sources</em>) now shows which sources are selected.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>The LLM model selector has been relocated to the top-left corner, below the product logo. Web grounding tools and sources have been renamed for clarity, and the 'Sources' button is now labeled 'Data', which also indicates selected sources.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Interface Updates in Google Agentspace</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-agentspace:2025-09-05:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Google NotebookLM Enterprise: Notebook creation and management using the API (GA)</strong></p>
<p>Use standalone APIs to programmatically create and manage your notebooks. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/agentspace/notebooklm-enterprise/docs/api-notebooks">Create and manage notebooks using the API</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Programmatically create and manage notebooks with NotebookLM Enterprise API.</summary>
    <title>Feature: NotebookLM Enterprise API</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-agentspace:2025-08-28:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Google NotebookLM Enterprise: Generate podcasts using the Podcast API (GA with allowlist)</strong></p>
<p>Use a standalone API to programmatically generate NotebookLM-style podcasts. No data store required; provide the source content directly to the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/agentspace/docs/reference/rest/v1/projects.locations.podcasts.operations">Podcast API</a>.</p>
<p>This feature is available to select Google Cloud customers (GA with allowlist). For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/agentspace/notebooklm-enterprise/docs/podcast-api">Generate podcasts (API method)</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new API allows you to programmatically generate podcasts using NotebookLM-style content. No data store is needed, as you can provide source content directly to the Podcast API. This feature is available to select Google Cloud customers.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Generate podcasts programmatically</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-agentspace:2025-08-21:breaking:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Full sync in SharePoint connector to avoid duplicate documents</strong></p>
<p>Because of a change that tries to optimize the sync performance, performing an incremental sync in a <a href="https://cloud.google.com/agentspace/docs/connect-sharepoint-online">SharePoint connector data store</a> can cause duplicate documents for <code>file</code> entity types. This is applicable to all SharePoint connectors created before August 21, 2025, that contain <code>file</code> entity types.</p>
<p>As a one-time solution, you can avoid duplication by either running a full sync manually or waiting for the next scheduled full sync. After performing the full sync, you can perform incremental syncs without generating any duplicate documents.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Avoid duplicate documents in SharePoint connector with a full sync.</summary>
    <title>Breaking: SharePoint Connector Duplicates</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-agentspace:2025-08-18:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Google Agentspace: Export analytics</strong></p>
<p>Export metrics to a BigQuery table in your Google Cloud project using the <code>analytics:exportMetrics</code> method.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/agentspace/docs/view-analytics#export_metrics">View and export analytics data</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Export metrics to a BigQuery table using the `analytics:exportMetrics` method.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Google Agentspace: Export analytics</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-agentspace:2025-08-12:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Google Agentspace: Custom starter prompts for no-code agents</strong></p>
<p>You can add starter prompts to no-code agents. Starter prompts guide users on how to interact with the agent. See <a href="https://cloud.google.com/agentspace/docs/agent-designer">Create a no-code agent with Agent Designer</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now add starter prompts to no-code agents. Starter prompts guide users on how to interact with the agent.</summary>
    <title>Feature: No-code agent starter prompts</title>
  </entry>
</feed>