<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Google Cloud Architecture Center</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Google Cloud Architecture Center</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-architecture-center</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/google-cloud-architecture-center/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-architecture-center:2025-09-17:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(New guide) <a href="https://cloud.google.com/architecture/ccn-distributed-apps-design/ccn-nva-ra">VPC Network Peering Cross-Cloud Network with NVAs and regional affinity</a>: Describes how to deploy network virtual appliances (NVAs) in a single-region Cross-Cloud Network architecture.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new guide is available on deploying network virtual appliances (NVAs) in a single-region Cross-Cloud Network architecture.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New guide on Cross-Cloud Network with NVAs</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-architecture-center:2025-09-16:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(New guide) <a href="https://cloud.google.com/architecture/multiagent-ai-system">Multi-agent AI system in Google Cloud</a>: A reference architecture to help you design robust multi-agent AI systems in Google Cloud.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>This is a reference architecture to help you design robust multi-agent AI systems.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Multi-agent AI systems</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-architecture-center:2025-09-11:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(New guide) <a href="https://cloud.google.com/architecture/rag-genai-agentspace-vertexai">RAG infrastructure for generative AI using Google Agentspace and Vertex AI</a>: Design infrastructure for a generative AI application with retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) using Google Agentspace and Vertex AI.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A new guide is available on designing retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) infrastructure for generative AI applications using Google Agentspace and Vertex AI.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New guide on RAG infrastructure for generative AI</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-architecture-center:2025-08-21:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(New guide) <a href="https://cloud.google.com/architecture/oracle-peoplesoft-with-oci-exadata">Oracle PeopleSoft on Compute Engine with Oracle Exadata</a>: Shows how to build the infrastructure to run Oracle PeopleSoft applications with OCI Exadata databases in Google Cloud.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>A guide to running Oracle PeopleSoft applications with OCI Exadata databases on Google Cloud.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Oracle PeopleSoft on Compute Engine</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-architecture-center:2025-08-08:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(New guide) <a href="https://cloud.google.com/architecture/security/best-practices-continuous-access-to-google-cloud">Best practices for continuous access to Google Cloud</a>: Describes best practices for using emergency access and IdP failover to ensure continuous access to Google Cloud.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Best practices for continuous access to Google Cloud using emergency access and IdP failover.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Best Practices for Continuous Google Cloud Access</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-architecture-center:2025-08-07:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cloud.google.com/architecture/framework/perspectives/ai-ml/reliability">AI and ML perspective: Reliability</a>: Major update to expand the reliability principles and recommendations in the AI and ML perspective.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>This is a short summary for a title.</summary>
    <title>Changed: AI and ML Reliability Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-architecture-center:2025-07-28:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(New guide) <a href="https://cloud.google.com/architecture/framework/perspectives/fsi">Well-Architected Framework: Financial services industry (FSI) perspective</a>: Principles and recommendations that are specific to FSI, aligned to each pillar of the Architecture Framework.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>New guide for Financial Services Industry (FSI) perspective on the Well-Architected Framework.</summary>
    <title>Feature: FSI Well-Architected Framework Guide</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-architecture-center:2025-07-22:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(New guide) <a href="https://cloud.google.com/architecture/secure-apps-resources-using-context-aware-access">Secure apps and resources by using context-aware access</a>: Describes how you can use context-aware access to secure different types of apps and resources.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>This new guide explains how to implement context-aware access to secure your applications and resources, offering a robust approach to access control.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Context-Aware Access Guide</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-architecture-center:2025-07-22:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(New guide) <a href="https://cloud.google.com/architecture/secure-apps-resources-using-context-aware-access/best-practices">Best practices for securing apps and resources by using context-aware access</a>: Describes best practices for using context-aware access to secure apps and resources.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>This guide details best practices for implementing context-aware access to enhance the security of your applications and resources.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Best Practices for Context-Aware Access</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-architecture-center:2025-07-01:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(New guide) <a href="https://cloud.google.com/architecture/gen-ai-graphrag-spanner">GraphRAG infrastructure for generative AI using Vertex AI and Spanner Graph</a>: Shows how to design infrastructure for GraphRAG-capable generative AI applications in Google Cloud by using Vertex AI and Spanner Graph.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>This guide demonstrates how to build generative AI applications with GraphRAG capabilities using Vertex AI and Spanner Graph on Google Cloud. It outlines the design for such an infrastructure.</summary>
    <title>Feature: GraphRAG Infrastructure with Vertex AI and Spanner Graph</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-architecture-center:2025-06-02:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(New guide) <a href="https://cloud.google.com/architecture/optimize-ai-ml-workloads-managed-lustre">Optimize AI and ML workloads with Google Cloud Managed Lustre</a>: Shows how to use Managed Lustre to optimize the performance of AI and ML workloads.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>This guide demonstrates how to leverage Google Cloud Managed Lustre to enhance the performance of AI and ML workloads.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Optimize AI/ML Workloads with Managed Lustre</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-architecture-center:2025-05-30:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cloud.google.com/architecture/patterns-for-connecting-other-csps-with-gcp">Patterns for connecting other cloud service providers with Google Cloud</a>: Added Network Connectivity Center and Hybrid NAT where relevant. Updated VPN references to only refer to HA VPN.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>This document provides guidance on establishing connections between other cloud service providers and Google Cloud. It has been updated to include information on Network Connectivity Center and Hybrid NAT, and now exclusively references HA VPN for VPN connections.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Connecting to Google Cloud</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:google-cloud-architecture-center:2025-05-28:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cloud.google.com/architecture/framework/perspectives/ai-ml/cost-optimization">AI and ML perspective: Cost optimization</a>: Major update to expand the cost optimization recommendations in the AI and ML perspective.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>This update expands the cost optimization recommendations within the AI and ML perspective, offering more guidance on managing expenses in machine learning and artificial intelligence workloads.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Cost Optimization for AI and ML</title>
  </entry>
</feed>