<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Google Cloud: Network Connectivity Center</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Network Connectivity Center</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:network-connectivity-center</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/network-connectivity-center/" />
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:network-connectivity-center:2025-06-26:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="text/markdown">Static routes for Network Connectivity Center are available in [public preview](https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages).

You can use static routes to define the next hop along the path that network traffic takes to reach a given destination. For more information about using static routes with Network Connectivity Center, see the
[Static routes overview](https://cloud.google.com/network-connectivity/docs/network-connectivity-center/concepts/static-routes-overview).</content>
    <summary>Static routes for Network Connectivity Center are now in public preview. This feature allows you to define the next hop for network traffic to reach specific destinations. For more details, refer to the static routes overview.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Static routes for Network Connectivity Center now in public preview</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:network-connectivity-center:2025-06-09:issue:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="text/markdown">Routes that NCC Gateway advertises don't show up in the list of a VPC network's effective routes.</content>
    <summary>Routes advertised by NCC Gateway are not appearing in the effective routes list of a VPC network.</summary>
    <title>Issue: NCC Gateway routes not visible in VPC network</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:network-connectivity-center:2025-06-04:announcement:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="text/markdown">[NCC Gateway](https://cloud.google.com/network-connectivity/docs/network-connectivity-center/concepts/ncc-gateway-overview) is available in [public preview](https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages).

NCC Gateway is a regional product that enables security functions such as third-party Security Service Edge (SSE) for Cross-Cloud Network traffic. You can use [Secure Access Connect](https://cloud.google.com/secure-access-connect/docs/overview) with NCC Gateway to securely connect remote workforces to private applications in Google Cloud, on-premises, or other cloud providers and to public applications, like Palo Alto Networks Prisma Access and Symantec Cloud Secure Web Gateway.</content>
    <summary>NCC Gateway is now in public preview, enabling security functions like third-party SSE for Cross-Cloud Network traffic. It can be used with Secure Access Connect to securely connect remote workforces to private and public applications.</summary>
    <title>Announcement: NCC Gateway now in public preview</title>
  </entry>
</feed>