<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Cloud SQL for SQL Server</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Cloud SQL for SQL Server</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-sql-server</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/cloud-sql-for-sql-server/" />
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-sql-server:2025-07-08:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="text/markdown">Cloud SQL for SQL Server now offers Active Directory support for write endpoints. For more information, see [Write endpoints across forests](https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/sqlserver/configure-private-ip#cross-forest-trusts).</content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL for SQL Server now supports Active Directory for write endpoints, allowing for cross-forest trusts.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Active Directory Support for Cloud SQL for SQL Server</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-sql-server:2025-05-28:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="text/markdown">Cloud SQL for SQL Server now offers the maximum server memory recommender.

Database instances running with an allocation of memory that's either too low or too high might experience performance issues.

The `max server memory (mb)` flag limits the amount of memory that Cloud SQL can allocate for its internal pools. You can manually set a value for this flag, or omit the flag and let Cloud SQL manage memory limits for you automatically.

For more information, see [Optimize maximum server memory usage](https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/sqlserver/recommender-maximum-server-memory).</content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL for SQL Server now includes a feature that recommends the optimal server memory allocation. This helps prevent performance issues caused by insufficient or excessive memory, allowing you to either manually set the 'max server memory (mb)' flag or let Cloud SQL manage it automatically.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New memory recommender for Cloud SQL for SQL Server</title>
  </entry>
</feed>