<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Cloud CDN</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Cloud CDN</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-cdn</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/cloud-cdn/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-cdn:2025-10-07:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud CDN provides predefined dashboards that are enabled by default for a quick
insight into system health and performance. These dashboards display key metrics
that enable you to monitor traffic distribution and cache effectiveness without
manual configuration. This feature is <strong>Generally Available</strong>.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/cdn/docs/logging#predefined-cdn-dashboards">Predefined dashboards</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Gain quick insights into your system's health and performance with Cloud CDN's new predefined dashboards. Monitor traffic distribution and cache effectiveness effortlessly with key metrics displayed by default, requiring no manual setup. This feature is Generally Available.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud CDN Predefined Dashboards Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-cdn:2025-06-23:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud CDN lets you add custom code to the request processing path of global external Application Load Balancers by using Service Extensions edge extensions. These extensions help you implement customizations in the request path pre-cache, which can influence how content is cached and the backend service is selected on the Application Load Balancer. This feature is in <strong>Preview</strong>.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/cdn/docs/integration-with-service-extensions">Use Service Extensions for edge computing</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now add custom code to the request processing path of global external Application Load Balancers using Service Extensions edge extensions. These extensions enable pre-cache customizations to influence content caching and backend selection. This feature is currently in Preview.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud CDN introduces Service Extensions for custom request processing</title>
  </entry>
</feed>