<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: NetApp Volumes</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: NetApp Volumes</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:netapp-volumes</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/netapp-volumes/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:netapp-volumes:2025-11-06:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google Cloud NetApp Volumes supports the block storage feature with iSCSI
protocol in allow-listed General Availability (GA) for the Flex service level of
the <strong>Unified</strong> type. For more information, see
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/netapp/volumes/docs/discover/features#block_storage">Block storage</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Google Cloud NetApp Volumes has introduced support for the iSCSI protocol, enabling block storage capabilities for the Flex service level of the Unified type. This feature is now generally available for allow-listed customers.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Google Cloud NetApp Volumes Now Supports iSCSI Block Storage</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:netapp-volumes:2025-10-01:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The manual QoS feature is now generally available for Google Cloud NetApp Volumes, supporting the Standard, Premium, and Extreme service levels. For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/netapp/volumes/docs/performance/optimize-performance#manual_qos">Manual QoS</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Google Cloud NetApp Volumes now supports manual QoS for Standard, Premium, and Extreme service levels.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Manual QoS now generally available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:netapp-volumes:2025-09-26:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Selective file restore feature is now generally available for Google Cloud NetApp Volumes, supporting the Standard, Premium, and Extreme service levels. For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/netapp/volumes/docs/protect-data/about-backups#selective_file_restore">Selective file restore</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Google Cloud NetApp Volumes now offers selective file restore for Standard, Premium, and Extreme service levels. This feature allows for more granular data recovery.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Selective File Restore Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:netapp-volumes:2025-09-24:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google Cloud NetApp Volumes now supports the FlexCache feature in allow-listed General Availability (GA) for the Premium and Extreme service levels. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/netapp/volumes/docs/discover/features#flexcache">FlexCache</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Google Cloud NetApp Volumes now supports the FlexCache feature for Premium and Extreme service levels. This feature enhances data caching capabilities.</summary>
    <title>Feature: FlexCache Feature Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:netapp-volumes:2025-09-05:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The auto-tiering feature for the Flex service level is now generally available for custom-performance Flex zonal pools. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/netapp/volumes/docs/configure-and-use/volumes/manage-auto-tiering">Manage auto-tiering</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The auto-tiering feature for the Flex service level is now generally available for custom-performance Flex zonal pools.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Auto-tiering for Flex is now available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:netapp-volumes:2025-08-25:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google Cloud NetApp Volumes now supports the external replication feature in allow-listed General Availability (GA) for Standard, Premium, and Extreme service levels. This feature uses bi-directional SnapMirror to replicate data between ONTAP-based systems and NetApp Volumes. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/netapp/volumes/docs/protect-data/replicate-ontap/overview#about_external_replication">About external replication</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Google Cloud NetApp Volumes has released external replication, supporting data replication between ONTAP-based systems and NetApp Volumes using bi-directional SnapMirror.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Google Cloud NetApp Volumes now supports external replication</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:netapp-volumes:2025-08-19:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Large capacity volumes now support a maximum capacity of 3 PiB. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/netapp/volumes/docs/configure-and-use/volumes/overview#large-capacity-volumes">Large capacity volumes</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Large capacity volumes now support a maximum capacity of 3 PiB.</summary>
    <title>Changed: New large capacity volumes</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:netapp-volumes:2025-08-07:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the Flex service level, the storage pool and volume now support a maximum capacity of 300 TiB. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/netapp/volumes/docs/discover/service-levels">Service levels</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The storage pool and volume for the Flex service level now support a maximum capacity of 300 TiB.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Increased capacity for Flex service level</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:netapp-volumes:2025-07-31:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google Cloud NetApp Volumes now supports organization policy for Customer Managed Encryption Keys (CMEK). For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/netapp/volumes/docs/configure-and-use/cmek/cmek-overview#cmek_organization_policy">CMEK organization policy</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Google Cloud NetApp Volumes now supports organization policy for Customer Managed Encryption Keys (CMEK).</summary>
    <title>Feature: New CMEK Organization Policy Support</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:netapp-volumes:2025-07-29:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google Cloud NetApp Volumes is now integrated with NetApp BlueXP Connector. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/netapp/volumes/docs/discover/features#netapp-volumes-integration-with-bluexp">NetApp Volumes integration with BlueXP</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Google Cloud NetApp Volumes is now integrated with NetApp BlueXP Connector.</summary>
    <title>Feature: NetApp BlueXP Connector Integration</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:netapp-volumes:2025-07-25:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google Cloud NetApp Volumes now supports cross-project cross-region replication for Standard, Premium, and Extreme service levels. This feature is generally available for allow-listed users. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/netapp/volumes/docs/protect-data/about-volume-replication">About volume replication</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cross-project, cross-region replication for Google Cloud NetApp Volumes is now available.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Google Cloud NetApp Volumes Replication</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:netapp-volumes:2025-07-25:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google Cloud NetApp Volumes now supports volume backups for large capacity volumes. This feature is now generally available. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/netapp/volumes/docs/protect-data/about-backups">About backups</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Volume backups for large capacity volumes are now available for Google Cloud NetApp Volumes.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New Feature: Volume Backups for Large Capacity Volumes</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:netapp-volumes:2025-07-22:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google Cloud NetApp Volumes now supports multi-VPC peering for all service levels. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/netapp/volumes/docs/get-started/quickstarts/connect-additional-networks">Connect additional networks</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Google Cloud NetApp Volumes now supports multi-VPC peering for all service levels.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Multi-VPC Peering Support</title>
  </entry>
</feed>