<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Cloud NGFW</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Cloud NGFW</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-ngfw</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/cloud-ngfw/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-ngfw:2025-11-17:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can create a Remote Direct Memory Access (RDMA) over converged ethernet (RoCE) Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) network and configure firewall rules that apply to the network. For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/firewall/docs/firewall-for-roce">Cloud NGFW for RoCE VPC networks</a>. This feature is available in <strong>General Availability</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now create a Remote Direct Memory Access (RDMA) over Converged Ethernet (RoCE) Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) network and configure firewall rules for it. This feature is now in General Availability.</summary>
    <title>Feature: RDMA over Converged Ethernet (RoCE) Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) now in General Availability</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-ngfw:2025-11-13:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can create a firewall endpoint that supports jumbo frames up to 8,500 bytes in size. For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/firewall/docs/about-firewall-endpoints#supported-packet-size">Supported packet size</a>. This feature is available in <strong>General Availability</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now create firewall endpoints that support jumbo frames up to 8,500 bytes. This feature is in General Availability.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Firewall endpoints now support jumbo frames</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-ngfw:2025-09-23:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can use the URL filtering service to filter your workload traffic by using domain and Server Name Indication (SNI) information available in the egress HTTP(S) messages. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/firewall/docs/about-url-filtering">URL filtering service overview</a>. This feature is available in <strong>Preview</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Filter your workload traffic using domain and SNI information from HTTP(S) messages. This feature is available in Preview.</summary>
    <title>Feature: URL filtering for workload traffic</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-ngfw:2025-08-04:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can create a secure tag at the organization level and bind its value to all virtual machine (VM) instances across that organization. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/firewall/docs/tags-firewalls-overview">Secure tags for firewalls</a>. This feature is available in <strong>General Availability</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Securely tag all VM instances across your organization.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Organization-level secure tags</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-ngfw:2025-07-25:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can create a Remote Direct Memory Access (RDMA) over converged ethernet (RoCE) Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) network and configure firewall rules that apply to the network. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/firewall/docs/firewall-for-roce">Cloud NGFW for RoCE VPC networks</a>. This feature is available in <strong>Preview</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>New feature: RDMA over converged ethernet (RoCE) Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) network and firewall rules configuration.</summary>
    <title>Feature: RDMA over Converged Ethernet (RoCE) VPC Network Feature</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-ngfw:2025-06-23:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can create a secure tag at the organization level and bind its value to all virtual machine (VM) instances across that organization, instead of applying tags to instances within a specific network. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/firewall/docs/tags-firewalls-overview">Secure tags for firewalls</a>. This feature is available in <strong>Preview</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now create secure tags at the organization level, applying them to all virtual machine instances organization-wide. This simplifies tag management and enhances security across your infrastructure. The feature is currently in Preview.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Organization-Level Secure Tags Now Available</title>
  </entry>
</feed>