<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Virtual Private Cloud</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Virtual Private Cloud</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/virtual-private-cloud/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-10-29:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can specify a <code>/96</code> IPv6 address range when reserving static regional IPv6
addresses. For more information, see the following:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/reserve-static-internal-ip-address">Reserve a static internal IP address</a></li>
<li><a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/reserve-static-external-ip-address">Reserve a static external IP address</a></li>
</ul>
<p>This feature is available in <strong>General Availability</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now reserve static external IP addresses within a /96 IPv6 address range.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New feature for IP address reservation</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-10-24:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can view IP address utilization when you
<a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/create-modify-vpc-networks#listing_existing_subnets">list</a>
or
<a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/create-modify-vpc-networks#describing_an_existing_subnet">describe</a>
subnets. IP address utilization displays the number of free
and allocated IP addresses in a subnet. This feature is available in
<strong>General Availability</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now view IP address utilization, which shows the number of free and allocated IP addresses, when you list or describe subnets. This feature is available in General Availability.</summary>
    <title>Feature: IP Address Utilization Viewable for Subnets</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-10-20:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>VPC Flow Logs supports logging for Cloud Run resources that are configured with
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/run/docs/configuring/vpc-direct-vpc">Direct VPC egress</a>. This feature is
available in <strong>General Availability</strong>.</p>
<p>For more information, see
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/about-traffic-flows#serverless-flows">Serverless flows</a> and
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/about-flow-logs-records#serverless-details">ServerlessDetails field format</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now use VPC Flow Logs with Cloud Run resources when using Direct VPC egress. This feature, now in General Availability, provides valuable insights into your network traffic. For more details, refer to the documentation on serverless flows and the ServerlessDetails field format.</summary>
    <title>Feature: VPC Flow Logs Now Available for Cloud Run with Direct VPC Egress</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-10-15:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Private Service Connect health is available in <strong>Preview</strong>.</p>
<p>Private Service Connect health lets service producers define health states to support automatic cross-region failover for consumers that use Private Service Connect backends. For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/about-private-service-connect-health">About Private Service Connect health for automatic cross-region failover</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Google Cloud's Private Service Connect health feature is now available in Preview. This feature allows service producers to define health states, enabling automatic cross-region failover for consumers using Private Service Connect backends.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Private Service Connect health now in Preview</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-09-26:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following features of VPC Flow Logs are available in <strong>General Availability</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Logging for <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/rdma-network-profiles#overview">RDMA over Falcon transport</a></li>
<li>Enhanced round-trip time precision for TCP and Falcon traffic</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/about-flow-logs-records#record_format">About VPC Flow Logs records</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>VPC Flow Logs are now in General Availability, including logging for RDMA over Falcon transport and enhanced round-trip time precision for TCP and Falcon traffic.</summary>
    <title>Feature: VPC Flow Logs Now Generally Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-09-25:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following features of VPC Flow Logs are available in <strong>General Availability</strong> through the Network Management API:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/using-flow-logs#enable-organization">Enabling VPC Flow Logs for an organization</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/using-flow-logs#enable-network">Enabling VPC Flow Logs for a VPC network</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/using-flow-logs#network-management">Enabling VPC Flow Logs for a subnet</a></li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/flow-logs#configurations">Supported configurations</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>VPC Flow Logs features are now generally available through the Network Management API, including options for enabling them at the organization, VPC network, or subnet level.</summary>
    <title>Feature: VPC Flow Logs Now Generally Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-09-23:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Service producers can publish services that are hosted on <a href="https://cloud.google.com/load-balancing/docs/l7-internal">cross-region internal Application Load Balancers</a>. This feature is available in <strong>General Availability</strong>. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/configure-private-service-connect-producer">Publish services by using Private Service Connect</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now publish services hosted on cross-region internal Application Load Balancers using Private Service Connect. This feature is in General Availability.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Private Service Connect with Internal Load Balancing</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-09-12:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can create a VPC network that supports RDMA over <a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/topics/systems/introducing-falcon-a-reliable-low-latency-hardware-transport">Falcon transport</a>, which lets you run AI and high performance computing (HPC) workloads on VM instances that have the <code>IRDMA</code> network interface type in Google Cloud, such as H4D instances. This feature is available in <strong>Preview</strong>. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/rdma-network-profiles">RDMA network profiles</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Run AI and HPC workloads with RDMA on Google Cloud VM instances with IRDMA network interfaces. This feature is available in Preview.</summary>
    <title>Feature: RDMA on Google Cloud</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-08-26:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>IPv6-only subnets and instances are available in <strong>General Availability</strong>. For more information, see the following:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/create-modify-vpc-networks#add-subnet-ipv6-only">Add an IPv6-only subnet</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/instances/create-ipv6-instance#create-vm-ipv6-only">Create an IPv6-only instance</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/connect-ipv6-to-ipv4">Configure IPv6-only subnets and instances with DNS64 and NAT64</a></li>
</ul>
<p>You can also use an IPv6-only NAT subnet to <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/configure-private-service-connect-producer#publish-service">publish a service with Private Service Connect</a>.</p>
<p>For information about which services support IPv6-only configurations, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/ipv6-support">IPv6 support in Google Cloud</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>IPv6-only subnets and instances are now available as a generally available feature. This allows for enhanced connectivity and the ability to publish services with Private Service Connect.</summary>
    <title>Feature: IPv6-only networking now generally available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-08-26:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>VPC Flow Logs supports logging for <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/rdma-network-profiles#overview">RDMA flows over Converged Ethernet</a>, such as GPU-to-GPU flows from A3 Ultra, A4, and A4X VMs. This feature is available in <strong>General Availability</strong>. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/about-flow-logs-records">About VPC Flow Logs records</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>VPC Flow Logs now supports logging for RDMA flows over Converged Ethernet, including GPU-to-GPU communications on A3 Ultra, A4, and A4X VMs.</summary>
    <title>Feature: VPC Flow Logs now supports RDMA flows</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-08-08:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>VPC Flow Logs includes metadata annotations for Google services such as Google APIs and VPC-hosted services. The following annotations are available in <strong>General Availability</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>service_name</code></li>
<li><code>connectivity</code></li>
<li><code>private_domain</code></li>
</ul>
<p>These annotations are supported for flows between VMs in VPC networks and Google services and for flows between on-premises endpoints and Google services (through Cloud Interconnect and Cloud VPN). For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/about-flow-logs-records#google-service-details">GoogleServiceDetails field format</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>VPC Flow Logs now supports metadata annotations for Google services, including service name, connectivity, and private domain. These annotations are available for general availability and apply to flows between VMs and Google services, as well as on-premises endpoints and Google services.</summary>
    <title>Feature: VPC Flow Logs Adds Google Service Metadata</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-08-04:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When you reserve an internal range with an automatically allocated IPv4 CIDR block, you can specify the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/internal-ranges#allocation-strategies">allocation strategy</a> that is used to select a free block. This feature is available in <strong>General Availability</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>New allocation strategies for internal IPv4 CIDR blocks.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Allocation Strategies Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-07-09:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dynamic Private Service Connect interfaces are available in <strong>Preview</strong>. You can update VM instances to add or remove dynamic Private Service Connect interfaces without restarting or recreating the instance.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/about-private-service-connect-interfaces#types">Private Service Connect interface types</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>VM instances can now be updated to add or remove dynamic Private Service Connect interfaces without needing to restart or recreate the instance.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Dynamic Private Service Connect interfaces now in preview</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-07-09:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>VPC Network Peering supports peering connections in consensus mode. This feature is available in <strong>Preview</strong>. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/using-vpc-peering#update-strategy">Update strategy</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>VPC Network Peering now supports connections in consensus mode. This feature is currently in Preview. For more details, refer to the update strategy documentation.</summary>
    <title>Feature: VPC Network Peering supports consensus mode</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-07-08:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following features of policy-based routes are available in <strong>General Availability</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Applying policy-based routes to IPv6 traffic</li>
<li>Using a next hop that is in a peered VPC network</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/use-policy-based-routes#create">Create policy-based routes</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Policy-based routes now support IPv6 traffic and peered VPC networks as next hops, offering enhanced routing flexibility.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Policy-based routes now generally available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-06-27:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Private Service Connect service connectivity automation periodically retries endpoint create or delete operations that fail due to errors. This feature is available in <strong>General Availability</strong>. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/about-service-connectivity-automation#endpoint-automation">Automatic retries for endpoint failures</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>This feature provides automatic retries for endpoint creation or deletion operations that fail, increasing reliability and reducing manual intervention.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Enhanced reliability for Private Service Connect</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-06-18:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following features of VPC Flow Logs are available in <strong>Preview</strong> through the Network Management API:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/using-flow-logs#enable-organization">Enabling VPC Flow Logs for an organization</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/using-flow-logs#enable-network">Enabling VPC Flow Logs for a VPC network</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/using-flow-logs#network-management">Enabling VPC Flow Logs for a subnet</a></li>
</ul>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/flow-logs#configurations">Supported configurations</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now manage VPC Flow Logs using the Network Management API. This includes enabling logs for your organization, VPC networks, and subnets. For more details on supported configurations, see the documentation.</summary>
    <title>Feature: VPC Flow Logs now available through Network Management API</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-06-16:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>VPC Flow Logs annotates RDMA traffic that is reported from A3 Mega VMs. This feature is available in <strong>General Availability</strong>. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/about-flow-logs-records">About VPC Flow Logs records</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>VPC Flow Logs now annotates RDMA traffic from A3 Mega VMs, a feature now in General Availability.</summary>
    <title>Feature: RDMA traffic annotation for VPC Flow Logs</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-06-13:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dynamic Network Interfaces (NICs) are available in <strong>Preview</strong>.</p>
<p>Dynamic NICs let you update an instance to add or remove network interfaces without having to restart or recreate the instance.</p>
<p>You can also use Dynamic NICs when you need more network interfaces. The maximum number of vNICs for most machine types in Google Cloud is 10; however, you can configure up to 16 total interfaces by using Dynamic NICs.</p>
<p>For more information, see the following:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/multiple-interfaces-concepts#dynamic-nics">Dynamic NICs</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/create-use-multiple-interfaces">Create a VM instance with Dynamic NICs</a></li>
<li><a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/add-dynamic-nics">Add Dynamic NICs to an existing instance</a></li>
</ul>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now add or remove network interfaces from your instances without needing to restart or recreate them, and increase the maximum number of vNICs to 16.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Dynamic Network Interfaces Available in Preview</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-06-05:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can <a href="https://cloud.google.com/secure-web-proxy/docs/deploy-service-attachment">publish a Secure Web Proxy instance</a> as a Private Service Connect service. Making Secure Web Proxy available as a published service lets you centralize egress traffic management across multiple VPC networks. This feature is available in <strong>General Availability</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Secure Web Proxy can now be published as a Private Service Connect service, enabling centralized egress traffic management across multiple VPC networks. This feature is now generally available.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Secure Web Proxy now available via Private Service Connect</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:virtual-private-cloud:2025-05-28:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can assign IPv6 bring your own IP (BYOIP) addresses to a subnet's external address range. These subnet ranges can only be used by VM instances, either as ephemeral or reserved addresses. To reserve addresses from these ranges, create a static regional external IPv6 address with the VM endpoint type. This feature is available in <strong>General Availability</strong>.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/vpc/docs/create-ipv6-sub-prefixes">Create and use IPv6 sub-prefixes</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now assign IPv6 bring your own IP (BYOIP) addresses to a subnet's external address range. These addresses can be used by VM instances as either ephemeral or reserved addresses. To reserve addresses, create a static regional external IPv6 address with the VM endpoint type. This feature is available in General Availability.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Assign IPv6 BYOIP Addresses to Subnets</title>
  </entry>
</feed>