<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Cloud SQL for PostgreSQL</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Cloud SQL for PostgreSQL</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-postgresql</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/cloud-sql-for-postgresql/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-postgresql:2025-07-31:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cloud SQL now offers two options of backup services to manage your instance's backups:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Enhanced backups</strong> (<a href="https://cloud.google.com/products?#product-launch-stages">Preview</a>): backups are managed and stored in a centralized backup management project that leverages the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/backup-disaster-recovery">Backup and DR service</a>, and provides enforced retention, granular scheduling, and longer retention.</li>
<li><strong>Standard backups</strong> (existing option): backups are created, managed, and stored in the same project as your Cloud SQL instances.</li>
</ul>
<p>You can choose between these options based on your instance's requirements and needs. Although instances can't use both backup options at the same time, Cloud SQL gives you the ability to switch between these backup options as necessary.</p>
<p>For more information about the available options and their limitations, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/postgres/backup-recovery/backups#backup-options">Backup options</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL introduces two backup options: Enhanced backups with centralized management and advanced features, and Standard backups managed within the instance's project. You can switch between them based on your needs.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud SQL Backup Options</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-postgresql:2025-07-02:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The write endpoint feature for Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus edition instances is now <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">generally available</a> (GA). This endpoint is a global domain name service (DNS) name and resolves to the IP address of the current primary Cloud SQL instance that's enabled with private services access.</p>
<p>By using a write endpoint, you can avoid having to make application connection changes after performing a switchover or replica failover operation to test or mitigate a region failure.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/postgres/connect-to-instance-using-write-endpoint">Connect to an instance using a write endpoint</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus instances now generally available with a write endpoint, simplifying connection management after failovers.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus Write Endpoint Now GA</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-postgresql:2025-07-01:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The write endpoint feature for Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus edition instances is now <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">generally available</a> (GA). This endpoint is a global domain name service (DNS) name and resolves to the IP address of the current primary Cloud SQL instance that's enabled with private services access.</p>
<p>By using a write endpoint, you can avoid having to make application connection changes after performing a switchover or replica failover operation to test or mitigate a regional failure.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/postgres/connect-to-instance-using-write-endpoint">Connect to an instance using a write endpoint</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus instances now support a generally available write endpoint. This global DNS name resolves to the current primary instance's IP address, allowing applications to maintain connections without needing updates after failover events.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus write endpoint now available</title>
  </entry>
</feed>