<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Google Cloud: Cloud SQL for PostgreSQL</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Cloud SQL for PostgreSQL</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-postgresql</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/cloud-sql-for-postgresql/" />
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-postgresql:2025-07-02:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="text/markdown">The write endpoint feature for Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus edition instances is now [generally available](https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages) (GA). This endpoint is a global domain name service (DNS) name and resolves to the IP address of the current primary Cloud SQL instance that's enabled with private services access.

By using a write endpoint, you can avoid having to make application connection changes after performing a switchover or replica failover operation to test or mitigate a region failure.

For more information, see [Connect to an instance using a write endpoint](https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/postgres/connect-to-instance-using-write-endpoint).</content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus instances now generally available with a write endpoint, simplifying connection management after failovers.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus Write Endpoint Now GA</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-sql-for-postgresql:2025-07-01:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="text/markdown">The write endpoint feature for Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus edition instances is now [generally available](https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages) (GA). This endpoint is a global domain name service (DNS) name and resolves to the IP address of the current primary Cloud SQL instance that's enabled with private services access.

By using a write endpoint, you can avoid having to make application connection changes after performing a switchover or replica failover operation to test or mitigate a regional failure.

For more information, see [Connect to an instance using a write endpoint](https://cloud.google.com/sql/docs/postgres/connect-to-instance-using-write-endpoint).</content>
    <summary>Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus instances now support a generally available write endpoint. This global DNS name resolves to the current primary instance's IP address, allowing applications to maintain connections without needing updates after failover events.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Cloud SQL Enterprise Plus write endpoint now available</title>
  </entry>
</feed>