<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Cloud Build</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Cloud Build</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-build</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/cloud-build/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-build:2025-12-08:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In build config files, the <code>mavenArtifacts</code> field now supports the
<code>deployFolder</code> field. You can use the <code>deployFolder</code> field to upload all Maven
files in a folder to a specific Artifact Registry repository. For more
information, see
<a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/build/docs/build-config-file-schema#upload-all-maven-files">Upload all Maven files in a folder to an Artifact Registry repository</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The `mavenArtifacts` field in build config files now supports the `deployFolder` field, allowing uploads to a specific Artifact Registry repository.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Maven deployFolder support</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-build:2025-10-09:changed:0</id>
    <published>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Service Account User role has been removed from the Cloud Build Permissions page in the Google Cloud Console. Instead, when you enable certain roles on your Cloud Build service account, you can configure your Cloud Build Service account to impersonate the service account of the managed services related to those roles. This configuration lets you deploy builds using managed services while maintaining minimal permissions. For more information, see <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/build/docs/deploying-builds/cb-sa-imp">Configure Cloud Build service account impersonation for managed services</a>.</p>
<p>In addition, the Cloud Build Permissions page in the Google Cloud Console will only show the <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/build/docs/cloud-build-service-account#about_legacy">legacy Cloud Build service account</a> if your organization's policy allows it.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>The Service Account User role has been removed from the Cloud Build Permissions page. You can now configure your Cloud Build service account to impersonate other service accounts for enhanced security and flexibility.</summary>
    <title>Changed: Cloud Build Permissions Update</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-build:2025-09-29:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Developer Connect build triggers are now <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products/#product-launch-stages">generally available</a>.</p>
<p>You can now create build triggers that build from <a href="https://docs.cloud.google.com/build/docs/triggers#devcon-triggers">repositories connected to Developer Connect</a> using the Google Cloud Console, <code>gcloud</code>, the Cloud Build API, and Terraform.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Build triggers for Developer Connect are now generally available. You can create these triggers using the Google Cloud Console, gcloud, the Cloud Build API, and Terraform.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Developer Connect build triggers are now available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-build:2025-09-02:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dark theme is now available for Cloud Build. To enable the dark theme, in the Google Cloud console, click <strong>Settings and utilities</strong> &gt; <strong>Preferences</strong>. In the navigation menu, click <strong>Appearance</strong>, and then select your color theme and click <strong>Save</strong>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Cloud Build now supports a dark theme. You can enable it through the console's Appearance settings.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Dark Theme Available for Cloud Build</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-build:2025-08-15:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>C3 and N2D machine families are now generally available in private pools. For a complete list of supported machines, see the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/build/docs/private-pools/private-pool-config-file-schema#machinetype"><code>machineType</code></a> entry in the private pool configuration file schema.</p>
<p>In addition, the <strong>Create private pool</strong> and <strong>Edit private pool</strong> pages now show a monthly estimate based on the pool's machine type configuration. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/build/docs/private-pools/create-manage-private-pools#view-price">View private pool price estimates</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>New machine types available in private pools.</summary>
    <title>Feature: C3 and N2D Machine Types Now Available</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:cloud-build:2025-05-27:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now create build triggers that build from <a href="https://cloud.google.com/build/docs/triggers#devcon-triggers">repositories connected to Developer Connect</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now create build triggers that build from repositories connected to Developer Connect. This integration allows for more streamlined CI/CD workflows by enabling builds directly from your connected repositories.</summary>
    <title>Feature: Build Triggers Now Support Developer Connect Repositories</title>
  </entry>
</feed>