<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Google Cloud: Organization Policy</title>
  <subtitle>Changelog for Google Cloud product: Organization Policy</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:organization-policy</id>
  <link rel="self" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/multani/gcp-changelog/refs/heads/main/content/organization-policy/"/>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:organization-policy:2025-08-18:feature:0</id>
    <published>2025-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can use custom constraints with Organization Policy to provide more granular control over specific fields for some Backup for GKE resources. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/kubernetes-engine/docs/add-on/backup-for-gke/how-to/create-custom-constraints">Manage Backup for GKE resources using custom constraints</a>. This feature is <a href="https://cloud.google.com/products#product-launch-stages">generally available</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>New custom constraints for Backup for GKE.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New custom constraints for Backup for GKE</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:organization-policy:2025-08-18:feature:1</id>
    <published>2025-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can now use organization policy conditions to match a tag key. This lets you enable or
disable enforcement against all resources with that tag key, regardless of what
tag value is attached. For more information, see <a href="https://cloud.google.com/resource-manager/docs/organization-policy/tags-organization-policy">Setting an organization policy with tags</a>.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>You can now use organization policy conditions to match a tag key.</summary>
    <title>Feature: New feature: Match tag key in organization policy</title>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <author>
      <name>Google Cloud</name>
    </author>
    <id>urn:github:multani:gcp-changelog:organization-policy:2025-07-25:issue:0</id>
    <published>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Organization policies in dry-run mode are reporting inconsistent results for the following <a href="https://cloud.google.com/resource-manager/docs/organization-policy/overview#managed_constraints">managed constraints</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>constraints/compute.managed.restrictProtocolForwardingCreationForTypes</code></li>
<li><code>constraints/iam.managed.allowedPolicyMembers</code></li>
<li><code>constraints/essentialcontacts.managed.allowedContactDomains</code></li>
<li><code>constraints/compute.managed.blockPreviewFeatures</code></li>
</ul>
<p>If a resource inherited an organization policy in dry-run mode that uses any of these managed constraints, that dry-run policy was evaluated without using the parameters specified in the live policy. Normally, an organization policy in dry-run mode that's inherited on a resource is overridden by the live organization policy set directly on that same resource. Not evaluating the live organization policy parameters in the inherited organization policy in dry-run mode led to inconsistent results.</p>
<p>Our engineering team is working to resolve this issue.</p>]]></content>
    <summary>Inconsistent results for managed constraints in dry-run mode.</summary>
    <title>Issue: Issue with dry-run organization policies</title>
  </entry>
</feed>